<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tales of Murder</title>
    <description>A murder mystery short story &amp;amp; novel site.</description>
    <link>localhost:3000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 16:41:11 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 16:41:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Side Up</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;first-farmers-bank&quot;&gt;First Farmers Bank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long, sleek limousine rolled slowly to a halt in front of the First Farmers Bank of New Albany, Indiana. The liveried negro chauffeur started to turn off the ignition when a sharp, thin voice from the rear seat froze his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leave her running, George.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Y-yes, suh!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get out and go into the bank—slowly f I’ll be right in back of you. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, suh. I—I understand.” George’s face was a little pale as he got out of the car and walked slowly, as directed, through the door of the bank. Though there was a cool breeze, sweat beaded his forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind him the expensive car disgorged incongruously a stocky kid, not over sixteen, his cheap checked suit tightly buttoned and his cap peaked down to shade his face. Both his hands dug deep in the pockets of his coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were few passersby on Main Street that afternoon in 1948, and they paid no attention to the chauffeur or the youth who followed him. Within the bank, the tellers were beginning to lounge. It was near closing time. The bank guard leaned his elbow contemplatively on the grilled window behind which Henry Green was counting his money. Mr. Smythe, gray-haired president of the bank, placed a paperweight carefully on the report he had been reading, and got up from behind his desk. He had an appointment to play golf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton, the guard, turned as he heard the bank door open. George, the chauffeur, entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, George,” grinned Horton. “You almost didn’t make it; bank’s getting ready to close.” Everyone knew George. He chauffeured for Mr. Jones, owner of the big steel mill over in Louisville, just across the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But George didn’t answer with his usual ready smile. His face was rigid, imploring; he moved forward stiffly as though propelled irresistibly from behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong?” demanded the guard in surprise. Then: “Hey!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stocky kid had swung suddenly into view. The cap was low over his eyes. A gun thrust forward in his hand. “Up with your hands, you blankety-blank so-and-so!” he said in a high, bleak voice. “If you make a move, I’ll drill you, so help me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton’s fingers dropped away from his holster; his arms lifted slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the rest of you,” snarled the kid. “Stand still and shut up. Where’s Smythe, the president of this bank?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Smythe stood at his desk. He held himself carefully. “I’m Mr. Smythe,” he said; “if you think you can hold up this bank you’re—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up! Turn around and open that safe in back of you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look here, you can’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Open that safe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smythe braced himself. “I won’t,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid fired. Sharp sound filled the bank. Smythe jerked forward, staggered and fell headlong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton gasped, dropped his right arm swiftly in a desperate attempt for his gun. The kid swerved; sound. again blasted the walls. The guard’s fingers uncurled, and the half-drawn gun dropped with a clatter to the floor. He followed it, shuddered and lay still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even as the reverberation of gunfire echoed from the marble, a new sound blasted with insistent clamor. The urgent shout of the alarm bell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid shoved his gun at the frightened teller. “You lousy son,” he screamed. “You asked for it” A single shot pierced the stridency of the alarm. Henry Green, his foot still on the buzzer, crumpled out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid backed toward the door, the smoking pistol covering his retreat. “You!” he stabbed at George. “Get the hell out there into the car. And no funny work. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I understand.” Ashen-faced, the breath sobbing in his lungs, the chauffeur stumbled out into the light&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gunman waited until he heard him open the car door. Then he spun around, raced for the limousine, flung himself into the back seat “Drive like hell! I’ll tell you where to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind him was a shambles: three dead men, panic and the senseless clangor of the alarm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;we-gotta-get-the-facts-sister&quot;&gt;We Gotta Get The Facts, Sister&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson, ace reporter of the Louisville Courier Journal, bent over the dying man. It was hard to hear his words. His chest swathed in bandages to hide the_ gaping wound and keep the ebbing life within a little longer, rose and fell in labored spasms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hospital nurse said: “You two will have to be brief; talking isn’t good for him,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lt. Dave Hunt of the New Albany police said gruffly: “We gotta get the facts, sister. Go ahead, Al. See if you can make out what he’s saying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al bent even closer. His voice was gentle, sympathetic. “This is tough on you, George, but it’s important. Do you think you’ll be able to tell me the story?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wounded man opened his eyes, tried to gather his strength. “I’ve got to, Mr. Aronson,” he whispered. “The killer—he’s only a kid—but he’s killed four men and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Three, George.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sad smile flitted over the Negro’s drawn face. “Four, Mr. Aronson,” he corrected. “I know I’m through. But—I was waiting over in Louisville to pick up my boss when this kid puts a gun to me, an’ makes me drive him over the bridge to New Albany. When we came to the bank—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shudder coursed through the dying man. He shut his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save your strength,” said Aronson. “We know that part; what happened after?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That kid was mad—mean mad when we got back in the car. I’ve heard cursing before, but never like that. He was filthy-mouthed. Cursed the men he’d killed, cursed the alarm system, cursed me. And in between curses he kept directing me—turn down First Street, then into Cranberry, left on Lake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson nodded. “Knew the town, eh, George?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, suh. He sure did. I was scared silly, but I tried ta fool him. Kept making mistakes, twisted wrong, tried to get him in front of the police station. I expected to smash the car and yell for help, but—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He knew better,” Aronson interjected softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George stared up at the reporter, his face sweating with the memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Knew every twist an’ turn like he’d lived here all his life. Pushed his gun in my back, swore he’d blow me ta hell. Landed me in an alley on the riverfront where no one was. Got out, turned, pointed that gun at me, said with a nasty grin: ‘Only one way ta keep your mouth shut,’ and pulled the trigger. Next thing I know, I’m here and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was going to die. George knew it as well as Al Aronson, Lt. Hunt, the nurse, the doctors, and everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor fellow, thought Aronson. No use trying to tell him he’s going to be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aloud he said: “What did he look like, George?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A heavy, tough kid— ‘bout seventeen, I’d say—and ‘bout five eight or nine. Wore a checked, tight suit o’ that loud green, and a cap. Couldn’t see much of his face; had his cap down too far; but he was full o’ pimples. Had a tough kid’s voice; the filthiest I ever did hear.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson straightened wearily. “That’s fine, George. Now, unless Lt. Hunt wants to ask you some more, just relax.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt set his jaw. “Just a couple o’ questions, George. In the first place—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chauffeur seemed to slump underneath the bedclothes. His eyes were fixed on Hunt, but they were blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save your question, Hunt,” said Aronson. “George will never answer it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;hunches&quot;&gt;Hunches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lt. Hunt chewed angrily on his cigar. “Stop trying to ride me, Aronson,” he exploded. “I’m telling you for the last time that killer was no local kid. I know every last hoodlum in town, and this punk doesn’t fit in. He’s an outsider.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned forward earnestly. “But,” he protested, “you heard George say that kid knew the back alleys here better than he did.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what? He could of come here a day before and studied the place. Why, for instance, would a local boy have to go over to Louisville to grab a car and bring it all the way here? Does that make sense?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It does sound screwy.” Aronson admitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, then. And don’t you go writing articles in your paper to the contrary, if you want the run of this place, either.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson was riding his hunches, and the hunch of George, the dead chauffeur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George had been sure the killer was a local boy. Yet Hunt was a damned good cop, and if he said that there wasn’t a hoodlum in New Albany who fit the description he was probably right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson disconsolately got into his car. He’d have to get back to the paper and write a story. Except it won’t be a story, he thought disgustedly. It’ll be a rehash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KILLER STILL ON THE LOOSE. NO CLUES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaperman in him revolted at the thought of dishing out yesterday’s warmed-over news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then an idea hit him! He heeled the car around in a screaming U-turn and went racing back to New Albany. He had an angle—not a very convincing one yet—but at least it explained how Lt. Hunt and the chauffeur could both be right. Maybe the kid had once lived in town, but had moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulling up at the first gas station, Aronson went into a huddle with a telephone book, and came out with the names and addresses of the six moving companies in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started making the rounds, interviewing the driver of every moving van. They listened to his description; then shook their heads. “Sorry, Buddy. If I ever saw him, I don’t remember.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson began to feel his job was futile. There was so little to go on. But he wouldn’t give up. Then—he struck pay dirt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mover named Davis said, “A mean kid, dark haired, pimples? A real low-down mean kid? Yeah, I remember him, all right; I’ll never forget the dirty little rat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When did you move him?” Al asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Must have been about a year ago. But I remember him good. Frankie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benson was his moniker. I moved him and his old man. The kid said he’d help me with a crate—a big crate—kind of a piano crate, but no piano in it When we had it up, he let go his end. Near busted my back. He started cussing me. Filthiest mouth I ever heard. I grabbed the punk and almost slugged him. Then I remembered he was just a kid, so I let him go. And when I turned around, he threw a hammer at me. Lucky his aim wasn’t too good. It missed my head, but near tore off my ear; here, I’ll show you the scar. They had to put three stitches in it, I woulda torn him apart if I got my hands on him, but he ran away, and I never saw him again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;but-what-could-i-do&quot;&gt;But What Could I Do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three hours later Al Aronson made his way down a dirty, ramshackle street in Louisville, to the address Davis had given him. He surveyed the paint-peeled, two room structure in the small, littered yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have gotten Hunt to come along, he thought. Wish I at least had a gun with me. Well, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crossed the street, now growing dark, and peered into the unlit front room. No one there. He made his way to the back of the house. Through a rear window he saw a stoop-shouldered, gray-haired man puttering around a stove. Apparently Frankie wasn’t at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson knocked on the door and introduced himself to Mr. Benson. He started telling the story, just the way it happened, carefully watching the old man’s face. Before the reporter was halfway through, the man suddenly burst out, “Don’t tell me no more; I don’t want to hear it It’s him, all right. I knew something like this would happen. Four men killed! Oh, my God! It’s my fault, I guess. He was bad all the way through, but what could I do?” The man’s voice was taking on a hysterical note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaperman helped the shaking old man to a chair; tried to quiet him. “All right, Mr. Benson, why don’t you tell me the whole thing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the floodgates opened. Benson poured out his story in a rush of words, as though something stored within him for years had now reached the bursting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t a particularly new story—not much different from dozens Aronson had written about— except its fateful climax. It was the story of a kid reared in the slums— a mother who died when the child was very young, and who hadn’t cared what happened to him before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A father who worked out of town, and saw him only a couple of hours on weekends. Frankie Benson had lived in the streets, almost like a wild animal, prowling back alleys for food, hanging around pool halls, bullying the smaller animals of the jungle he lived in and running from the larger ones; rejected and scorned by the decent elements of society, and nursing an ever-growing hatred. He had stolen, gone to reform school, and come out all the worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At first I thought he was just wild, like kids get sometimes,” the old man said hoarsely. “But then, when he was only thirteen, he started stealing. That’s when I knew he was bad. And I knew then that he’d end up rotten, that something like this would happen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Condemned at thirteen. Al thought bitterly. The kid never had a chance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His mind flashed back on his own boyhood. Thirteen—that was the year he was confirmed. He recalled that day in the synagogue— the joy and the warmth of it, surrounded by loving parents, relatives, friends, teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A kid needs people to love him, he said to himself. People rooting for him. Frankie never had anybody on his side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He used to hit me,” Benson went on in a voice that was now half sobbing. “His own father. I was afraid even to talk to him. I’d ask him to do something, he’d knock me down. Once when he was out in the box I yelled for him to come in to eat. He nearly choked me to death— said he’d kill me if I ever bothered him when he was busy with the box.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned over and said softly, “What box, Mr. Benson?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was a piano crate, I don’t know where he got it; he brought it home one day, years ago. He fixed it up and would stay in it. Sometimes almost a whole day. Like he was hiding from the world. It used to be sort of a game, I think—like most kids would use a tent. But then he’d shut himself in and hide. I don’t know from what.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s the box now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I shipped it out, like he told me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned forward. “When did he tell you? When did you ship it? Where did you ship it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man thought for a moment. “Day before yesterday. That musta been the day those men were killed. He gave me some money, and said I should ship the crate to Knoxville. No address, just Railway Express, in Knoxville. He said I’d better do it the next day, or he’d take care of me. So that’s what I did. I sent it to Knoxville.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you seen Frankie since?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you have a receipt for the box?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. I’ll get it.” . Benson reached into a drawer in the kitchen table, brought out a couple of scraps of paper. He gave the receipt to Aronson, and then stood studying a dirty piece of notepaper in his hand. “I found this on the table that night, after he told me about sending the box. I—I didn’t know what he meant then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson took the note from his fingers, and read the child-like scrawl. Stop me, please, before I do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man looked entreatingly at the reporter. “Before he does it again! Oh, stop him! Stop him!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson’s lips tightened. He took the receipt and headed for the door. “I’ll try.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;ill-kill-you-ill-kill-you&quot;&gt;I’ll Kill You! I’ll Kill You!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the quiet of the darkened warehouse, Lt. Hunt flashed his light along the rows of high-piled crates, trunks and boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I must be crazy,” he said to Al Aronson, “letting you drag me out of bed to chase an old piano crate down to Knoxville. It would be different if he had gotten away with the bank robbery—maybe he’d have the dough in the crate. But he didn’t get a dime. We could have had the Knoxville police pick him up whenever he calls for the box. I don’t know what you expect to find inside of it, or what the big hurry is?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not so loud,” whispered Aronson. “The warehouseman said it would be somewhere in this corner.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you whispering for?” the Lieutenant demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t want to warn the kid we’re coming.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What makes you think the kid is here in the warehouse? How could he get in? It’s locked and guarded.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s in the piano crate; he was shipped in it from Louisville.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re crazy’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll see. Flash your light around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle of yellow light moved slowly down the row until it came to one larger than the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The piano crate!” Al said. He checked the markings on the box. “This is it, all right.” Then he pointed to a series of round holes bored in the side of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just as I thought,” he whispered. “Air holes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt swore under his breath; drew his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al called out, “Okay, Frankie, we’ve got you covered. Come on out of the box.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson motioned for Hunt to take cover. He himself stepped behind a large trunk, said loudly, “Okay, Hunt, let’s roll this lousy crate over on its side.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two shots splintered holes in the box. A hysterical voice called, “Stay away from me, you lousy bums. I’ll kill you! I’ll kill you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be sensible, Kid,” the reporter called. “You can’t hit us because you can’t see us. But we can fill that box of yours full of lead; we can put more holes in it than a sieve. Come on out and give yourself up-”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obscene curse was the only answer, and a third shot crashed wood and spanged into a metal drum. “Show him we mean business, Lieutenant,” Al said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective fired a shot through the upper corner of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Next one goes right through the middle,” Aronson called out “What do you say, Frankie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a moment of silence, then a muffled sob, and the side of the case swung slowly back on its hinges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankie Benson came oat with his hands raised, crying. “Why did I do it?” he sobbed over mid over again. “Tell me why I did it. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lieutenant Hunt examined the piano crate; said, “Hey, AJ, he really had this thing rigged up—a Pullman bunk, three pistols, water bottles. cans of food—and straps -to hold everything in place. You ought to get a photographer down here. It will make a swell picture. You’ve got a great story—the story of the year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Al Aronson was staring at the sniveling kid in front of him, still sobbing, “Why did I do it? Why? Why? Why?” The sneering, ruthless killer who had coldly murdered four men without the slightest compunction was now just a scared, pimply-faced 16-year-old boy, all mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Al knew that the story he would write, the story that would command banner headlines on the front page, would not really be the main story. The important story was the one that would answer Frankie Benson’s plaintive entreaty—”Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, Al thought sadly, was an answer he didn’t know—a story that would never be written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/this-side-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/this-side-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Planned by the Stars</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-day-is-ill-omened&quot;&gt;The Day Is Ill-Omened&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sanctum of Madame Sovio was drab and tawdry. The room was small and done in faded blue draperies upon which were tinsel stars and moons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one window that overlooked Sixth Avenue bore the name of the astrologer in porcelain letters and the information that her hours of business were from two o’clock to five daily. A broad table that stood in the center of the room held a plaster skull and a quantity of astrological charts. Other charts were nailed up on either side of a door that led into an anteroom. The low ceiling had once been painted to give the impression of drifting clouds. Twin gas jets, blackening it, had long past destroyed the effect. The faint though pungent odor of gin hung on the stirless air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of the astrology parlor sat at the center table. Madame Sovio wore a flowing Egyptian kimono patterned extravagantly with the mystic signs of the zodiac. She was old, gaunt and unprepossessing. Her untidy hair was wreathed with a greasy veil; her shrewd eyes focused on the financial page of a morning newspaper. From time to time she stimulated herself with small quantities of fluid poured from a square bottle convenient to her elbow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio finished a perusal of the page she read and was turning languidly to the front sheet of the paper when she looked up. The door of the outer room had opened and closed. With the practice born of long experience she placed both bottle and newspaper in a lower drawer of the table, thrust a few cloves into her toothless mouth, and stood up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “waiting room” of the establishment was even smaller than the inner room. It contained nothing save a number of rickety chairs and a red-faced youth who was pinching out a cigarette ere consigning the stub to a coat pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caller was tall, bulky and unattractive. He wore a rusty brown suit and stained yellow brogans with bumpy toes. A celluloid collar held a stringy purple cravat; from under the sagging peak of a shoddy cap a low, protruding forehead, dark, crafty eyes and a loose, rapacious mouth were visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was evident to Madame Sovio that the youth was flotsam cast up by the turgid rivers of subterranea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He met her gaze and shuffled forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You the one that slides out the dope on what’s gonna happen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman inclined her head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Come in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visitor stepped into the room hung with the faded blue draperies. Madame Sovio closed the door after him. She indicated he should take the chair opposite her across the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you wish a horoscope or a reading?” she inquired as he sat down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A spinner on the docks give me the gab that you had steered him straight on the bang-tails. I’m due to gay-cat tonight on something important. I want a frame telling me how my luck is gonna break.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio twined her claw fingers together. She understood the youth to mean that some client who had sought her advice as to making bets on the races had recommended him to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The stars,” she began, following a usual procedure, “plan and compel! Their influence falls directly on each mortal. What is planned cannot be changed. A man’s planetary destiny is as inflexible as Fate. It is Fate. I charge one dollar for a reading.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red-faced youth produced a crumpled dollar and pushed it across the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give me the dope on how I’m gonna make out. Am I gonna be lucky or not ? Get the hop working and give me a buzz. Should I or shouldn’t I?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seamy lips of the astrologer came together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is your name?” she asked in a business-like voice. “What is the date of your birth? Upon what hour of that day or night were you born? I must know these things before I read the messages of the heavenly bodies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The youth continued to stare at her for a long minute. He muttered the name of Joe Carney, informed her of the date of his natal day and, without hesitation, said he had been born at the precise hour of midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio became engrossed in a deep study of her charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While she bent her gray-crowned head over the table Joe Carney settled back in his chair. He glanced about idly and wrinkled his nose at the familiar odor of gin that could not be disguised by the perfume of the cloves. He sat patiently until a slight exclamation moved his eyes to the woman across the table. He was surprised to see she was staring at a chart with every indication of horror. r&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not one hour of the twenty-four is propitious! The day is ill-omened! All the planetary influences are dark and evil. Mars, Saturn, Uranus and Mercury are adverse. Jupiter is in a hostile position and is ringed with red. This is the star that guides your footsteps through this constellation. Its scarlet rim foretells but one thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney met her gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio moved her hand slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Murder!” she said quietly. “At midnight you came upon this earth and at midnight the stars plan you shall be removed from it. Uranus intrudes and blurs the horoscope. I can read no further. That is all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney laughed harshly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The hell it is! I pay a dollar for that song and dance? Give me the money back. You’re a robber!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio pushed the dirty bill he had laid on the table across to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it! It will bring you no good. You are in the shadow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red-faced youth pocketed his money, shrugged with contempt and slouched out, banging the door after him. For an interval the woman sat motionless, fingers picking at the thumb-marked chart before her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The red ring,” she said half-aloud. “Blood on the stars—murder on earth—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emerging onto Sixth Avenue, from the narrow entrance of the building housing the two rooms of the star-reader, Joe Carney laughed under his breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A hell of a spiel!” he said to himself. “I should get glomed for a bone to get that bunk dished out. “The old dame is nuts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crossed to the west side of Sixth Avenue and walked north. A firm believer in the Black Arts, he wished he had not listened to the dock-walloper who had told him of the astrologer. He could have interviewed a palmist or crystal-gazer and not wasted his time. He knew nothing, and now it was too late to seek another seer. Within twenty minutes he had an appointment with Stanley Ray, the leader of the Duster Band; final plans for the night’s adventures were to be unfolded to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sight of the shopping district Carney entered a side street. He put a number of avenues behind him, passed under the scaffolding of an overhead railroad and presently was on the threshold of the small area of the city, controlled by Stanley Ray’s band of thugs and gangsters. Tenement houses stood shoulder to shoulder in flanks of brick. Down the slope of the side street an avenue where freight cars rolled was visible; further distant was the waterfront and the Hudson River. Frowsy women leaned from countless windows; children played in the gutters; the summer air was dank with the stench of salt water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the avenue where the freight trains ran Joe Carney stepped. He put two blocks behind him and presently came upon a waterfront hotel—a building that had been old when the city was young. Joe Carney passed through the hostelry’s yawning front door and moved into a small lobby. A few loafers, smoking nauseous pipes, played checkers silently or slumbered loudly, shaggy heads tilted forward on flannelled chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the group, brooding over his cigarette, sat a tall, heavily built young man with a dark, sinister face in which was largely written both determination and courage. This man stood up as Carney entered, nodded his head slightly and opened a white-washed door a few feet back from where he had been sitting. When Carney had followed him into a small room that was used as a refuge for drug-peddlers and their victims, he closed the door and turned the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney promptly sat down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I’m here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray inclined his head slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I see.” He pulled up a chair and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dropped into it. “Listen carefully. I’m passing you the word that you turn the job on Tenth Avenue tonight. I’ve never told you where you’re to go or what you’ve to do. All that you know is you’ve been picked out by me to swing a deal and keep your peep closed. The frame is set so that all you have to do is to walk in, help yourself and walk out. A half-wit could turn this without a mistake. That’s how soft it is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney fished in his pocket for the half-consumed cigarette. He lighted it and inhaled deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I make you. Let’s have it all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray went to the door and listened. He returned to his chair and leaned forward. He lowered his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Limping Lou has turned straight— by request. He works for the gas company. Tuesday he went to a flat on Tenth Avenue to read the cellar meter. In the front basement of the place are two rooms rented by a woman called Mrs. Garber. Lou had finished reading the meter and was passing out when he heard a clinking noise. It came from inside Mrs. Garber’s front room. Lou tried to look through the keyhole, but it was plugged. So he went out into the alley and found the side window of the same room. This window was protected by bars, but was open at the top. Lou found a barrel, stood up on it and looked through the top of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney drew a breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What did he see?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray leaned still closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He saw Mrs. Garber sitting before a trunk—counting money! Lou said she was tying up bales of the green stuff in old aprons. He watched her until she put the aprons in the trunk, filled it to the top with old clothes and then shut it up! That’s what he saw!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney dropped his cigarette to the floor and ground it out with his heel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What else?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I stuck a plant up there,” Stanley Ray resumed. “I found out this Mrs. Garber is out every afternoon. She makes her money playing the stock market. It’s no use trying to get into the room during the day because the janitor of the building and a bunch of ginnies are laying pipe in the cellar. I sent the Turk up yesterday. He took a fall out of the bars. He filed them to the bone. A couple of pulls will yank them out. The window’s always open and you can go in over the top of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What time do I go in? Will the miser be there when I get to the trunk ? How much long change do I get out of this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leader of the Duster Band favored Carney with a direct, cold stare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You get what I give you! Have you anything to say about it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the bland stare of the gangster king Joe Carney’s eyes wavered and fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing,” he said hastily. “Put me right on it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray smiled faintly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I found out this Mrs. Garber gets telephone calls from Levy’s Drug Store. At a quarter of twelve I’ll telephone the drug store and tell them to send for Mrs. Garber. They’ll shoot their kike kid over to the basement. You’ll be in the alley at quarter of twelve. When she goes out you go in. I’ll stall her on the wire as long as possible. It should take you just about ten minutes to grab the dough and exit. Do you get me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney reflectively rubbed his beard-rusty chin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” he said laconically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-right-dope&quot;&gt;The Right Dope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night was hot and unstirring. A full moon rode high in a cloudless sky. The dank smell of the river grew more pronounced. The streets were lined with coatless loungers sprawling at ease in doorway or on stoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney, shuffling up Tenth Avenue, searched each store window for a clock to tell the hour by. It could not be very late. The avenue was well filled’ —a number of shops were open and doing business. Again he regretted some prophet had not been employed to prognosticate the fortunes attending the enterprise. In every task he had set out to accomplish he had been warned in advance as to the condition of his luck. If he had been told it was not favorable lie had postponed the event. And never once had he been apprehended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked on, hands rammed in the pockets of his coat. He eyed the numbers of the buildings as he passed them, still searching for a clock, growing aware his destination must be only a few blocks distant. He saw the moon creep up over the sullen rooftops and perceived the canopy of brightly shining stars. He thought of the astrologer of the early afternoon and the jumble of her words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A murder!” he chuckled, touching the automatic revolver hung under his left arm. “Swell chancel”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two more blocks traversed, he came abreast the building in whose basement the wealthy Mrs. Garber resided. And at the same minute his eyes fell upon the face of a clock in a store of the tenement and he started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hands of the clock pointed to five minutes of the midnight hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guiltily realizing he had been delinquent and heedless of time, Carney descended a number of steps that led down into the basement. He found himself in a cement-lined passageway. He followed it to its termination and found himself in the clothesline-hung backyard in the rear of the building. An alley ran into the backyard, presided over by a lean cat. Carney removed the animal from his path with a toe of his boot and crouched against the face of the alley’s brick wall, ceasing to curse the vivid moonlight only when a barred window of translucent glass leaped out to meet him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tingle of anticipation ran through Joe Carney. Hex found the same barrel Limping Lou had made his observations from and wheeled it close to the window. He mounted it cautiously and applied an ear to the aperture in the window’s top. All was quiet within. Obviously, he decided, Mrs. Garber was in the drug store or on her way to it. He was ten minutes late and would have to work rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The window bars yielded instantly to his grasp. He tore them roughly away, one by one. When the last bar had been wrenched loose, Carney pressed the top half of the window lower and poked a head into the inky blackness of the room. Low but distinctly he heard the monotonous ticking of a clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied that no menace crouched in the gloom, Carney threw a leg over the sash and lowered himself into the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until his eyes could grow accustomed to the murk he stood motionless. A faint odor of gin assailed his nostrils. Faint stirrings tuned his nerves to a high pitch. With a sense of direction fixed firmly in mind, he crept forward. The treasure chest, Stanley Ray had told him, rested to the right, against the room’s north wall. As the thought flashed through his mind, his knees came in contact with some low-set object. His outstretched hands clasped the top of something he knew immediately was the trunk, and he exhaled a breath of relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover of the trunk swung upward at his touch. He felt to make sure that the connecting arms were firmly fastened and delved into a mass of soft garments, placed layer upon layer. These he dug out and flung to the floor, burrowing, mole-like, to reach the apron-wrapped treasure. The scent of gin seemed to envelop him. He wondered why this odor should stir odd recollections—recollections he could not piece together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had pulled the last article of clothing from the trunk when the door of the room vibrated with a sudden staccato rapping. Ere its first echoes throbbed into silence, a nasal voice sup–planted the loud knocks with an insistent statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Garber! Somebody wants you on the telephone down at Levy’s!” Joe Carney’s hands closed convulsively. The clock he had looked upon had been fast or the telephone had marred Stanley Ray’s message!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, Mrs. Garber must be within a few feet of him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The messenger from the drug store began his rapping again. Stiff as stone Joe Carney sought to think. Then, as the knocks ceased for the moment, he heard, from some quarter close at hand, the creak of a bed, a soft footfall—a sibilant swish that told of a garment being donned. Followed at once the rasp of an opening door. A vagrant air current, stirred to new action, touched Carney’s forehead—cold against the sweat that had gathered upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breathless questions rushed through the mind of the intruder. Should he allow the woman to answer the messenger? Or should he strike before she reached the door?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another series of footfalls wheeled him silently about. Someone was approaching—had stepped through the door. He thought he could detect a muffled shape of shadow moving closer to him. The suspense of waiting was agony. A breath caressed his hot face and a hand touched his arm. Someone gasped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same moment he sprang forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a low growl he felt his fingers dig deep into a soft, stringy throat. Eyes glared into his own; for all of the fact she was a woman, the figure he clutched fought desperately, Carney released his left hand to bring it down with crushing force on the jaw of the struggling figure. Before he had crashed it savagely into the upturned face the woman managed to wrench a scream from between her lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursing, Carney struck again. He gripped the throat again with the hand he had used with hammer force and shook the woman as a terrier shakes a rat. As if from a distance he heard fresh raps falling upon the door—the voice of the messenger:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Garber! Mrs. Garber!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carney relaxed the gripping pressure of his death-working fingers. He found he was talking but knew not what he said. He had killed a woman, but it was her own fault. Hot blood pounded within him—rage and a gloating satisfaction. He felt that at that moment he wished she possessed the nine lives of the cat he had kicked from his path. He would strangle each from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then he realized the apron-wrapped loot would never be his if he stood longer, clutching the limp figure. He opened his hands. The body slumped to the floor. The moon, swinging around, entered the alley and crept into the room, lighting it up like a pale arc lamp. Carney looked down at the huddle of his victim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman had fallen on her back. Her face was upturned to him— wreathed with a horrible, fixed grin. He stared, fascinated, eying, too, greasy gray hair that seemed strangely familiar. For a full watch-tick he stared, rigid. The odor of gin—the gray hair—the gaunt face, painted with the ghastly moon glare. All at once knowledge flooded him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Garber wore the face of the Madame Sovio who had read the stars for him that afternoon in the Sixth Avenue room!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Murder!” Carney whispered. “She had the right dope!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something, as he straightened up, stopped the flow of the incoming moonlight. He raised his eyes and turned them to the window. His gaze flashed and fell upon a helmeted head looking in over the lowered top of the translucent window. His right hand darted under his jacket and gripped his automatic. In some blind, dizzy fashion he managed to drag it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before he could pull the trigger the yellow glare of an electric torch smote him directly between the eyes. A voice, curt and imperious, bade him throw up his hands. Carney, blinking like an owl drenched in sunshine, fell back. His weapon crept up to firing position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the heavy silence was shattered by the sound of six shots, so rapidly fired that they merged as one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The automatic fell from Carney’s hand. He wondered vaguely if he had been shot—why his legs seemed to be melting away. Cursing again, his brain reeled and scintillated with sparks. He groaned and fell heavily across something softly yielding … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock that had ticked monotonously whirred and struck the hour of twelve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/planned-by-the-stars/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/planned-by-the-stars/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parting Gift</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;its-me-honey&quot;&gt;It’s Me, Honey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret walked slowly up the path to his front door, clicked his key in the lock and stepped into the warmth of his own hallway. For a moment he stood there in the semi-darkness, breathing hard, tilting his head, smelling the old familiar smells and wondering at himself for the thing he was about to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His wife, Eva, called down from upstairs, “Joe, is that you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret shivered and tightened his hand around the bulky object in his overcoat pocket. He said, as steadily as he could, “It’s me, honey,” and tasted for a brief moment a spasm of panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took a cigarette from his breast pocket and tucked it between dry lips, dragging in the taste of the unlit tobacco. Then he took off his coat and hat and threw them over the packed bags lying near the hat-rack by the door, and with the package in his hand, walked stealthily out into the kitchen and opened the door leading down into his workshop in the cellar. He stood at the head of the wooden steps, feeling the hot rush of blood into his face and the dizziness in his head. He went down the stairs and turned on the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the dry cigarette still waggling between his lips, Pomfret sat down at his bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carefully, he unwrapped the package, revealing an expensive bronze table lighter fashioned after a globe of the world, with the ignition plunger where the north pole should be, and the countries etched in neatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead, the echo of his wife’s footsteps jarred through the floor, hurrying him along. He pulled the cigarette away from his lips, tearing off a strip of skin, and reached over to the rack for a screwdriver. He unscrewed the filler cap, picked out the cotton wool, threw it in a wastebasket. From the rack where his reloading tools lay he took down a canister of pistol powder. Next he removed the wick from the lighter and fitted into its place a short, fast-burning fuse, and began pouring the powder into the base of the lighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew powders, he knew gas pressures. He knew what would happen when someone picked up the lighter, holding it close to the end of the cigarette, and pressed the plunger for a light. They’d get a light, all right, a light that would show them the way into eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without air space, the hundred-odd grains of powder compressed into that bronze base would be as deadly as a hand-grenade. Pomfret had seen it work once before. Just four grains of powder jammed down by an improperly hand-loaded bullet to the bottom of a cartridge case, without air space for the expanding pressure of the gas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He still had the wreckage of a once perfectly good heavy-frame revolver in one of the drawers in his filing cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he had screwed the cap back in place he picked up the lighter, carrying it as cautiously as he would have carried a bottle of nitro-glycerine, and walked up the stairs. He felt as weak as if he had spent the afternoon running around the block. He closed the cellar door behind him and leaned his back against it, hard, until his shoulder blades ached from the contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went over to the tap for a drink of water. Then he walked slowly back into the living room and placed the lighter gently on the cocktail table, where no one could miss seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew how it would react on Harvey. He knew it would be the first thing Harvey, a chain-smoker, would pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He closed his eyes and thought about Harvey’s handsome face. Then he went out into the hallway and began putting on his hat and coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;harveys-cigarette-case&quot;&gt;Harvey’s Cigarette Case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eva came down the stairs, and Pomfret paused by the door, watching her, taking her in, gauging the full fluid motion of her body and the slow swing of her long tawny hair and the full rich beauty of her face, feeling again the desire for her and the need of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped then, and turned toward the living room and took a hesitant step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said, “What’s wrong, Joe?” and the sound of her voice clipped his resolution in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret laughed, the cracked sound of it echoing hollow and false in his brain. “Nothing at all,” he said lamely. “Tired, I guess. Had a hard day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came to him and rested her hand on his arm. The touch of her pulled the trigger on his mind and the hatred in him welled up then and flowed fresh and potent until he thought he would kill her then and there, without benefit of gadgets or tricks or long-range plans, if she didn’t take her hand off him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, hoarsely, “Has Harvey called for his cigarette case yet, Eva?” and his keen, suspicious eyes probed hers for some sign of fear or admission of her guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took her hand away and color touched her cheeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For heaven’s sake, Joe, do we have to go through all that again? I told you he left it in the living room the last time he was here, and I took it upstairs to the bedroom so I wouldn’t forget to ask you to give it back to him when you saw him at the office. Isn’t that reasonable enough for you? Do you expect me to go down on my knees and beg for belief from my own husband?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her voice was as tight as a plucked violin string, vibrating against the resistance in his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He thought again of the lighter on the living room table. He let out his breath. The taste in his mouth was as sour and he wanted to be sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead he reached for her and kissed her harshly, feeling the softness of her against him, the elusive, heady perfume, the taste of her lipstick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling, too, the resistance that had been there for months now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” he said quietly. “Okay, hon. Let’s skip it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He opened the door and reached down for his bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll be back,” he said, as if it mattered. “It may take time. Maybe a week or more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You be careful of those Toledo blondes,” she said, smiling up at him. “I don’t know if I should trust you that far away from home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me! he thought bitterly. You don’t know if you can trust me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried a laugh on, just to see if it would fit, and when it didn’t, he turned and walked quickly from the house to the oar. There was a harsh bitter nip of Fall in the air. The breaths he took crackled in his lungs and reminded him of football games and the sharp clean tang of mustard on hot-dogs and the closeness and warmth Eva had been to him then, before Harvey joined the firm and began his series of weekly visits, finally moving into the house next door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret almost tore the transmission out of the car getting it into second gear. As he passed Harvey’s house he saw the shadow of Harvey’s bulk against the windowshades, and he knew that before he reached the corner the big eager man would be sneaking slyly through the gate in the hedge to where Eva waited for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He put the car into high gear and went down the street and turned the corner, out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;theyll-never-suspect-a-thing&quot;&gt;They’ll Never Suspect A Thing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey grinned. He had a good-natured, boyish grin that worked well with some types of women. He stood in the middle of Joe Pomfret’s living room, staring at Joe Pomfret’s wife. There was sweat on his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “Look, from now on, it’s so much velvet, Ev. Everything’s going to be okay. It’ll all be over soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked over to the table and spun a pack of cigarettes so that one flipped out. This he tapped on the table and put in his mouth. He picked up the bronze lighter and held it in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Neat little gadget,” he said, making his voice loud, as if to drown out his own thoughts and the ones in Eva’s mind. “Where’d you get it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She sat tensely on the edge of the studio couch, staring at her hands. The whip in his voice brought her head up and she glanced at the lighter, then shrugged impatiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know. Joe, I guess. He’s always bringing something home.” She wet her lips. “When, Harv? How long will it be?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey put the lighter back on the table and poured himself a stiff drink. He put it down his throat in one long smooth motion, and glanced at his watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When he hits the Turnpike hill,” he said, keeping his voice even, “he’ll have to brake hard for the sharp turn there. When he does, the brake cable goes. I took care of the emergency, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He poured another drink, rattling the bottle against the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a hundred foot drop through that fence. He won’t feel a thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shivered. He took the cigarette from his mouth and went over to her. She came willingly and easily into his arms. He kissed her in a way that Joe Pomfret had never known and would never learn, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment she lay still in his arms, her breath hot on his face, her eyes closed. The room was very still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey put the cigarette back in his mouth and pushed her gently away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be fine, angel. They’ll never suspect a thing.” Her mouth touched his again, jostling the cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled. Her hand searched out across the table, touching the rough etched metal of the lighter, closing around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She slid her other arm around his neck, pulling his head down to hers, touching the lighter to the end of his cigarette. Her lips brushed his ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Light, darling?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/parting-gift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/parting-gift/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Odds Are On Death</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;lucks-a-fickle-jade&quot;&gt;Luck’s A Fickle Jade&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran threw snake-eyes. An audible gasp went up from the well-dressed crowd around the crap-table. They had seen Corcoran make six straight passes; watched him run a ten-spot up to six hundred and forty bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, since there was no limit in Spot Shelton’s ultra-select gambling establishment, Corcoran had shot the works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loudly the girl alongside him said: “You were foolish, honey. You should have dragged down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her name was Margie Zaine. She wore her blue-black hair sleekly coiffed; she had a Madonna face. Her figure was a poem of curves sheathed in a crimson satin evening gown. Men had a hard time keeping their eyes away from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was a capper for Spot Shelton’s place. Sucker-bait. But Corcoran was no sucker. He was a private dick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grinned down into her dark eyes. She was playing her part to perfection. Nobody on Spot Shelton’s staff would possibly suspect her of disloyalty to Shelton tonight … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nor could anybody guess what Corcoran was really up to. Thus far he’d played his part of a reckless sap to the hilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it had been a tough job trying to make the dice obey orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck’s a fickle jade; when a man wants to lose, he almost invariably wins. It had taken him more than ten minutes to go broke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-teller-at-my-bank&quot;&gt;A Teller At My Bank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tuxedoed croupier said: “Still your dice if you want them, Mister.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie Zaine pressed herself closer to Corcoran. She was trembling a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the far end of the table a tall, nervous young man flashed a veiled glance at the private dick; flicked his eyebrows. Corcoran took his cue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said to the croupier: “I’d like to keep on shooting, but I’m cleaned.” He passed the cubes to the player on his right. Then he said: “Could I get a check cashed?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up at the end of the table, the tall young man was listening to a willowy blonde in daring décolletage. He seemed annoyed. The blonde looked sore. The croupier beckoned an attendant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendant came up to Corcoran and said: “How large a check, sir?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, about five hundred.” Corcoran drew a checkbook from his dinner jacket pocket. He didn’t produce the flat .25 automatic which also reposed in that pocket. The attendant frowned dubiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m afraid I’ll have to let Mr. Shelton pass on that, sir. It’s more than I’m authorized to cash. I’ll take you to his office.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie Zaine said: “Never mind. I’ll show the way.” She looked archly at Corcoran. “I know Spot Shelton. I’ll introduce you. Come along, honey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a chuckle, of course, Margie knew Shelton. She worked for him! But she wouldn’t be working for him after tonight. Corcoran slipped an arm around her waist. She led him out of the casino-room and down a long, carpeted corridor. She knocked on a closed door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A voice said: “Come in.” It was Spot Shelton’s voice, sleek and purring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They entered. Margie said: “Hello, Spot. This is my friend, Mr. Jones. He wants a check cashed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton’s eyes were heavy-lidded and crafty to match the thin gash of his avaricious mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Glad to accommodate you,” he said affably. “How much will you need?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran raised his ante. “A thousand will do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a light turned off, Shelton’s smile faded abruptly. “A thousand?” he said sharply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” Corcoran said, “I’ve got plenty in the bank. Want proof?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What kind of proof?” Shelton purred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Send for Harry Greer. He’s out at the dice-table. I just saw him. He’s a teller at my bank. He knows the balance I carry. Call him in. Ask him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton spoke into a house-phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;you-might-call-it-a-stick-up&quot;&gt;You Might Call It A Stick-Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment the door opened. A tall, nervous young man came in, the one who had flicked his eyebrow at Corcoran a while ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “Why, hello, Margie. Good evening, Mr. Jones,” he added politely to Corcoran. Then he looked at Shelton. “You want me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “He wants to know how much money I’ve got on deposit in your bank, Harry. Tell him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer cleared his throat; it was his only sign of uneasiness. “Why, more than thirty thousand dollars, roughly speaking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah,” Shelton smiled apologetically to Corcoran. “In that case I’ll be delighted to cash your check, Mr. Jones.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to the wall behind his elaborate desk, shoved aside an etching, and toyed with the dial of a counter-sunk safe. A big yellow solitaire diamond glittered on the ring finger of his right hand as he opened the safe’s circular door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran pulled out his .25 automatic and said: “Thanks, Shelton. Now step back and sit down before I blast you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gambler whirled, his sallow cheeks pale. “What is this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You might call it a stick-up,” Corcoran said. “But I’d sooner say it’s a bit of justice outside the law. I’m not a hood. Just a private shamus working for Harry Greer and Miss Zaine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, you dirty — !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Tie him to the chair, Harry. And Margie, you grab the dough out of the box. Just thirty grand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thirty grand — ?” Shelton snarled an oath at the girl. “You double-crossing vixen!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer slugged him in the teeth. The gambler sagged into his chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer produced a skein of picture-wire, and bound Shelton’s wrists and ankles, saying: “Maybe Margie used to be a double-crosser. But not any more. She’s all through capping for you, Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie was pulling packets of currency out of the safe, stuffing them into her beaded purse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer went on: “She got me to play your crooked games, Shelton. But you didn’t count on her falling for me, did you? Well, that’s what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Falling for you? That’s a laugh, you dirty — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer said: “I’m marrying Margie, see? That’s why I hired this detective to help me get back the thirty thousand dollars you took away from me with your loaded dice. Now I can put back what I took from the bank — before the auditors catch up with me. And from now on, Margie and I are going straight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gambler squirmed helplessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Margie he snarled: “Don’t be a sap, kid! Greer’s playing you for a sucker. He won’t marry you. Look what he did to Jackie Allan. Made her fall for him, too, then handed her the air. He’ll treat you the same way! Put that dough back, baby — and I’ll forget the whole thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added: “You can keep out five hundred if you want to. That’s all Greer ever lost to me, the lousy liar. He never dropped any thirty grand!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t believe you, Spot,” Margie said quietly. She snapped her purse shut. It bulged with the currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton raged: “You put that dough back in the safe or I’ll get you if it’s the last thing I ever do!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer hit him on the jaw again. The gambler sagged against his bonds, unconscious. Greer went over to him to make sure the wires were tightly knotted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “Okay. He won’t get loose for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;could-i-kiss-the-bride&quot;&gt;Could I Kiss The Bride?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door opened. A feminine voice said: “That’s what you think.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the willowy blonde who had approached Greer at the crap-table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer said: “Jackie Allan — !” in a scared whisper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of her heavy make-up she was gorgeous. Her hair was spun gold. She said: “I told you I’d get even with you for handing me the gate, Harry. I warned you I’d get something on you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer sputtered: “You — you — !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy, Harry,” she said frigidly. “And put that money back where it belongs. Spot Shelton was plenty decent to me after you walked out on me. This is my chance to make it up to him. You put that money back, or I’ll scream the place down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran went into action. He jumped at the blonde and slapped a muffling hand over her mouth. He looked at Greer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about this, Harry?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A pack of lies!” the bank-teller said harshly, indignantly. “It’s true I was nuts about her for a while. She was the one who first got me into playing Shelton’s crooked games. When I found out she was one of his come-ons, I ditched her. Then I fell in love with Margie, here. Margie came clean with me; promised to help me get my money back from Shelton … ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Hand me that picture-wire,” Corcoran snapped. He took the skein, tripped Jackie Allan to the floor, tied her. When he got through, she was gagged with a handkerchief and trussed like a turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran got up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Greer he said: “Get your coat and hat and go home. Margie and I will phone you from her apartment, later. We’ll leave shortly. It wouldn’t look good for all of us to be seen pulling out of this joint together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Corcoran and Margie strolled casually back into the gaming-room a little later, Greer was gone. Corcoran stopped at the roulette-table long enough to lose the fifty that Margie had slipped him. That was to make everything look okay. After all, he was supposed to have cashed a check … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four wrong guesses at the wheel, he yawned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s beat it, Margie. I’m tired,” he said loudly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She fastened herself to his arm. They went out; found a taxi. They headed for her apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You were swell,” she said. “Now Harry and I can be married, and — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Could I kiss the bride?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She gave him her lips in gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;and-finally-silence&quot;&gt;And Finally, Silence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab stopped in front of her apartment building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They went into the lobby. It was deserted and dimly lighted at this late hour. They made for the automatic elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a curtained alcove to the left, a hand appeared. It was a white, soft-looking hand wearing a yellow diamond solitaire and holding a revolver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the gun crashed, Margie Zaine screamed and clutched at her breast. Blood spurted through her fingers. She dropped her handbag and fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran made a grab for his automatic. He fired at the drapes. He knew he must have missed, because there was no answering fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bellowing, the private dick smashed toward the curtained alcove. As he hit the drapes, something thunked down on his head. He was stunned. Fireworks exploded inside his brain. He reeled drunkenly; pitched to his knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time he got up again, the alcove was empty. There was a doorway leading to the alley alongside the building. The door was open … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran stared stupidly at Margie Zaine’s sprawled form. Death’s waxen mist was on her Madonna face. Her handbag was open and empty. The money she had taken from Spot Shelton’s office wall-safe was now gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton, who had threatened her … Shelton, who had worn a yellow solitaire diamond on the ring finger of his white, effeminate hand … !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran snapped out of his daze. He was thinking of Harry Greer, now. Maybe the bank-teller would be next on Shelton’s list of victims. Maybe it was already too late —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinting out into the night, Corcoran grabbed a passing owl cab. It zipped him to Greer’s apartment house, an unpretentious three-story structure with exterior fire- escapes marring its old-fashioned red brick façade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran raced up to the second floor. He reached the bank-teller’s door and pounded on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Greer — let me in! It’s me, Corcoran — and hell’s to pay!” A muffled pistol-shot answered him. Then a heavy thump, as of a body falling. And finally, silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran hit the door. It bruisingly rebuffed him. He backed away and smashed at it again, putting his full two hundred pounds behind the impact. This time the portal gave way. He stumbled into the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;pinched-for-murder&quot;&gt;Pinched For Murder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An open window framed the iron fire-ladder just outside. In the room’s center lay Harry Greer, breathing heavily, with his eyes closed. Thick clotted blood wept from a raw hole in his left shoulder. A thin drift of gunpowder-smoke eddied in the dull light from a table-lamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran ran heavily to the window; stared outward, downward. He couldn’t see anybody. He returned to Greer and worked over him. At last the teller opened his eyes. “God … my shoulder … !” he groaned faintly. “Who drilled you? Was it Shelton?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I … don’t know! I was … getting ready to … start for Margie’s place … and a shot … came from … the window … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer sat up weakly. “What are you … doing here? My God … if Shelton shot me … he may go … gunning for Margie … You should have … stayed with her … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry, kid, but Margie — Margie’s dead.” Corcoran tried to break the news to him gently. “‘Take it easy while I try to do something to fix this shoulder of yours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Margie … dead … ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teller pushed Corcoran away. “Do something … .!” he cried hysterically. “Call the cops … trail that dirty rat … get him … kill him … !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His lips twisted vengefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Yeah. Trail Shelton. That’s a large order. He’ll be on the lam for sure, now. He must’ve got loose in his office; reached Margie’s place ahead of us. Then he blasted.He killed her — and thought he killed me, too. So he came here to bump you. But just as he fired at you from the window, he heard my voice out in the hall. He realized he hadn’t croaked me. And now he knows he’s in the soup; knows my testimony will convict him. He’ll go into hiding.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got to find him!” Greer sobbed. “Get going! I’ll phone the cops. Move, blast you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran went out. It was going to be tough, trying to locate Spot Shelton. Corcoran didn’t know where to start. Then he got an idea. He found a drugstore and a phone book. He looked up Jackie Allan’s name and found it. He made a note of her address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A taxi took him to a bungalow court. He rang her bell. When she opened the door, Corcoran drew his automatic and shoved the muzzle against her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “You’re pinched for murder, baby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was wearing lounging pajamas. Her wrists were red and chafed from the wire with which she’d been trussed back in Shelton’s office. There were marks on her ankles, too. The ankles themselves were slender and dainty, to match the rest of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said: “Pinched … for murder? What do you m-mean?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He backed her into the little living room and kicked the door shut behind him. He pushed her onto the divan and stood over her, glowering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What happened after I left Shelton’s joint?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why — why — I managed to spit that gag out of my mouth. I yelled for help. People came in and untied me and Shelton, too. Spot brought me home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Straight home?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes.” She seemed puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “You’re a liar, baby. You hated Harry Greer’s guts because he ditched you. You hated Margie Zaine for taking him away from you. So you gunned the both of them, to get even.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was preposterous, of course. Corcoran knew that. But he wanted to throw a scare into Jackie Allan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;to-save-a-guys-life&quot;&gt;To Save A Guy’s Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the color drained from her cheeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I — I don’t know what you’re talking about!” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Margie’s dead. You killed her. You tried to kill me. And you put a bullet through Harry Greer’s shoulder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I — I didn’t! My God, I wouldn’t — ” She reached up and grabbed his gun-arm. “D-don’t point that thing at me. And you can’t believe I’d — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at her, steadily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s just one way you can buy yourself out of this mess, baby. I want you to tell me where I can find Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the hallway, a voice growled: “That’s easy, snoop. Here I am. And this thing in my hand isn’t a saxophone. It’s a rod. It shoots bullets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “How did you get in here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve got a key,” Shelton said. “Why not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll be getting a key to the hot squat before long,” Corcoran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I gathered that. I was home listening to the radio when I heard a bleat go out for me on a murder rap. That’s why I’m here now.” He looked at the blonde girl. “Why did you kill Margie, babe?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I didn’t — I didn’t! That’s what I was trying to tell this copper — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s okay. I understand the setup.” The gambler glared at Corcoran. “You’re not arresting her, snoop. I won’t let you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton shifted his gun to his left hand, doubled his right. He hit Corcoran on the button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twice. Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran’s knees buckled. He took the count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he awoke, Shelton and Jackie were gone. The house was all upset, as if a hurried job of luggage packing had been accomplished during the private detective’s unconsciousness. Corcoran felt his bruised jaw. The flesh wasn’t cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stumbled out of the cottage. He walked four blocks before he found a cab. He gave the driver Greer’s address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And step on it — to save a guy’s life!” he panted. Seven minutes later he burst into Greer’s apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer had contrived to bandage his nicked shoulder. He stared at Corcoran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What — ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shelton’s still on the loose. He’s got a gun. He may be on his way here to finish you!” Corcoran said. “But we’ll trap him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“H-how?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you got a roscoe? He took mine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer opened a desk drawer. He brought out a revolver. Corcoran snatched it and jammed it three inches into the bank-teller’s belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The jig’s up,” he said grimly. “You bumped Margie. Where’s the dough?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer turned a pasty yellow. “Are you crazy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like a fox,” Corcoran snapped. “Listen. Shelton told the truth tonight when he said you only lost five hundred to him. When he told Margie you never intended to marry her. You were a smart skunk, Greer. You’d never swiped any dough from your bank. That was just a stall to make Margie fall in with your schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You planned to rob Spot Shelton. He looked like an easy touch. And you did a lot of groundwork before you pulled the strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You first tried to work through Jackie Allan; but when she wouldn’t work with you, you ditched her. You took up with Margie. Margie fell for your line. She really figured you loved her, wanted to marry her. And she believed you when you said Shelton had gypped you out of thirty grand. That was a lie. And besides, Shelton’s dice are straight … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, after Margie agreed to help you, you hired me. We pulled the heist; got the dough from Shelton’s safe. Shelton made threats. You saw a chance to get the money, be rid of Margie — and pin her murder on Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer gulped noisily. “You’re all wrong — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuts. You swiped Shelton’s diamond ring off his finger while he was tied to his chair, knocked out. Then you went ahead to Margie’s apartment house. You waited behind that drape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wore Shelton’s ring when you shot Margie. All I saw was your gun-hand — and the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You didn’t drill me. You wanted me alive — so that I could testify it was Shelton’s hand I saw holding the murder-gun. You just conked me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I came to and rushed here to your place, you fired a shot out your window, so I’d hear it. Then you fell on the floor and played possum. You wanted me to think Shelton had come here and drilled you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But the wound in your shoulder was from my bullet, Greer! I winged you when I shot through that drape after you drilled Margie!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, Corcoran! You’re crazy!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuts! I should have guessed it right away, when I looked at your shoulder the first time. The blood had already started to clot. But I was dumb. I was dumb up to the time Spot Shelton slugged me on the jaw in Jackie Allan’s bungalow a little while ago. Then I saw the truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wh-what do you mean?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shelton poked me with his right — but it didn’t cut my cheek. He wasn’t wearing his ring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was the tip-off. Maybe somebody else had the ring. Not Jackie Allan, because her hands were smaller than the one I saw through that drape. And why didn’t Shelton croak me in Jackie’s bungalow when he had the chance? If he’d been guilty, he’d have drilled me to keep me from spilling. Instead, all he did was biff me. He just wanted a chance to get Jackie away — because he thought she was the killer. He loves her; wanted to protect her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Jackie wasn’t guilty. But if Shelton thought she was, it meant he was innocent himself. Get it? So that cleared everybody but you, Greer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You had motive: greed. You had opportunity. And you had my bullet hole through your shoulder. You also had a roscoe — which I just tricked away from you. Got anything to say now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;turn-em-loose&quot;&gt;Turn ’Em Loose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer snarled: “You’ll never take me, Corcoran!” and swatted at the revolver in the private dick’s fist. Corcoran shot him through the other shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’ll suffer a little before they burn you,” he said. He was thinking of poor little Margie Zaine lying dead because she had loved unwisely … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search disclosed the thirty thousand dollars that Greer had taken from Margie’s handbag. And Corcoran also found Shelton’s diamond ring, under Greer’s mattress. Corcoran phoned police headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come and get the guy that bumped Margie Zaine,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve already got him. Spot Shelton. Picked him up with a blonde a while ago.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Turn ’em loose. They’re clean. And you might tell Shelton that a dumb cluck named Corcoran would like an invite to the wedding … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/odds-are-on-death/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/odds-are-on-death/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nice Corpses</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-9&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;funeral-pieces&quot;&gt;Funeral Pieces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basement of the flower store was chill with dampness; the naked light-bulb above the work table glaring harshly, piled up huge, crouching shadows in the corners, police coat buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It glinted on Detective Clint Fleming pushed his brown felt hat farther back on his crinkly black hair and contemplated the body at his feet. Then he turned and swung sharp eyes at the group huddled behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I suppose,” he said wearily, “none of you know anything about this—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three heads shook quickly, involuntarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint Fleming glanced down again at the body of the slender young man. A florist’s knife—the kind used for trimming flowers—was in his chest, in the center of a crimson splash on his white shirtfront. Only the green enameled handle was visible. The head and shoulders were part way under the worktable, and the thin little coroner was complaining bitterly as he crawled out, stood up and brushed off his knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why,” he asked no one, “do corpses always get themselves in such awkward positions?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He picked up his worn satchel, clapped his hat on his head, and said briskly, “I’ll send my report around as usual. Fellow’s been dead about ten hours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint Fleming nodded absently, and nudged the gilt letters that lay in confusion on the cement floor with the toe of his shoe. In his hand he held the letter U he had picked from the dead man’s fingers. The pigeonholed box that had held the letters lay overturned, empty. A cluster of M’s were scattered near the lifeless hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, cover him up,” Detective Fleming jerked over his shoulder to one of the blue-coated officers. Then he turned back to the silent three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The redhead was crying soundlessly into her handkerchief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right,” he said, “let’s get down to cases. Tell me again what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl spoke. Her name was Pat Murray; she was new in the store, learning the flower business. She had discovered the body of Fred Jensen that morning when she had come down to the basement to bring up some vases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who called the police?” Clint asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tall, sallow young man on the girl’s right answered. “I did. I’m Jack Unger. I deliver the orders. Pat came screaming up the stairs—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unger,” Clint repeated. He glanced down at the paper letter in his hand and his gray eyes narrowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young man flushed. “Just because that letter was—” he moistened dry lips— “in Fred’s hand, it doesn’t mean—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn it,” Clint interrupted sharply, “it means something! Why would he have picked out a U? You use these letters to print out sentiments on ribbons, don’t you? For funeral pieces?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At his last words the girl squeezed her blue eyes shut, pressed the back of her hand against her mouth. Her slim shoulders trembled under her smock. Jack Unger touched her arm lightly and she drew away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’ll be all right, Pat,” he said softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She did not answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;lilacs&quot;&gt;Lilacs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man on her left spoke for the first time. He was short and stocky,, his black eyes antagonistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, Mister,” he told Clint, “Pat’s had about all she can stand. We don’t know any more than we told you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked at him. A brief smile flickered on his lips. Then he shrugged. “Sure,” he said kindly, “but somebody has to ask questions. The Chief has plopped this case in my lap. It’s up to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint thought: this being a detective isn’t so hot. Nobody likes you —they’re afraid if they do you’ll turn around and pin a murder rap on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glanced at Pat and she looked hastily away. Any other time, under the right circumstances, a girl like that would smile if a fellow’s eyes showed that he thought— Clint broke off his thoughts. He hadn’t missed the look that crossed her face when Unger touched her arm. Or the fact that the paper U in his hand was the second letter of her last name. It was also the second letter of murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had Fred Jenson been trying to spell cut something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s the boss?” Clint asked suddenly. “Who is the Davies this store is named after?” He looked a question at the stocky, dark man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My name’s Herb Martin. Thomas Davies owns the store. He’s usually here, but he’s been home the past few days. Heart trouble.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s been notified?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. “He said the police are welcome to come out and he’ll tell them what he knows.” Clint made a wry face. “Helpful people rarely know anything of use,” he observed. He started to walk toward the stairs that led up into the shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wouldn’t take any sudden trips, if I were you,” he told them. Then, with his hand on the wooden banister, he stopped. He took r deep breath of the damp air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned to Pat Murray and asked slowly, “Isn’t that lilacs I smell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She nodded and pointed to a large table that stood against a gloom-shrouded wall. “They’re over there. We have more upstairs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint pursed his lips. His words, when he brought them out, were careful. “Last week I tried to buy some lilacs—I was told that the season has been over for a half a month. How come you still have them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl started to speak, but Herb Martin interrupted with,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So we’re lucky? So what difference does that make?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“None at all—I suppose,” Cliff told him slowly. Then he leaned forward and his words were chill, “You know,” he said, “I don’t think I’m going to like you. And if I were you—I wouldn’t make me positive of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he looked past the man. “You can have the body taken away,” he told one of the officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went on up the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;suspects&quot;&gt;Suspects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Davies seemed more than anxious to help and he sat in a deep leather chair, his bread face puckered into a frown of worry, his fingers picking at the front of his dressing gown. His false teeth flashed whitely when he spoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A terrible thing,” he said. “A terrible thing, really. Fred was a nice boy. Why anyone should—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He had no enemies?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Davies’ eyebrows drew down. “I don’t want to say anything that will put blame—but, well, he and Tack Unger were both interested in Pat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And she preferred Jensen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. “I don’t think Jack would have—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about Herb Martin?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ob, he’s all right. Bit of a temper, but—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint sighed. “You think Unger did it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies stiffened. “I didn’t say that! In fact—” his eyes narrowed— “this would be just the sort of thing Mike Slone would have wanted to happen. He—” He broke off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Slone has the flower shop on the next corner. He’s been fighting me for years. Plenty tough customer. Lately he’s been making threats.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What kind?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies waved a vague hand. “Says I ruin his business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint murmured deep in his throat. Then he stood up. “I’ll go around and see him.” He put out his hand. Davies took it, gripped it tightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to try to get down to the shop tomorrow,” the florist said. “Let me know if you find out anything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint grinned crookedly at him. “You’ll know,” he promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;yellow-roses&quot;&gt;Yellow Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint parked his car at the curb, and went o the door of “Davies Flowers” and rapped on the glass. Pat came to let him in. She was alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How come you didn’t go home?” Fleming wanted to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled thinly at him. “I’d rather work—it keeps my mind busy. There are a lot of orders to get out. Phone orders.” She jerked her red head at the crowd clustered outside the plate glass windows. “Would they love to come in and stare.” “Probably you can open the store tomorrow,” Clint told her. “But, where is everybody?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Herb is out having lunch; Jack is delivering.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Clint asked, “mind if I talk to you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shook her head and walked back to the counter on which she had been working. She picked up a snapdragon spike and with deft fingers stripped off the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint watched her until she had finished the bunch. Then she took the coppery blossoms, put them in a water-filled vase. Her hands stopped as Clint asked slowly, “Was Fred Jensen in love with you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stood a moment, her red lip caught in her teeth, then she answered, “Yes, I guess he was. I liked him—that was all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And Jack Unger?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned to him then. “Mr. Davies said that Jack killed Fred because of me?” she demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint lifted one shoulder. “Could be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t believe it,” she said hotly. “Simmer down—nobody’s accusing him. You like him, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pat tossed her head. “No,” she said flatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s been trying to change your mind—and Fred didn’t like that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well—” she began, then her voice trailed off. Nervously she picked up a glass bottle, unscrewed the cap, poured two white pellets into her palm and dropped them into the vase that held the snapdragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that?” Clint asked curiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aspirin. It makes them last longer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As long as three weeks?” Clint’s words were quick. “Or more?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl looked startled. “I don’t know—” she faltered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint leaned toward her, over the counter. “Doesn’t it strike you strange that you have flowers out of season when no one else has?” He pointed to a bowl of yellow roses in the window. “How long have they been there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pat followed his motion. “Well, they’re pretty expensive; they haven’t sold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About three and a half weeks.” Clint looked thoughtful. “See you later, chick,” he said abruptly, “I’m going down the street.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;u-in-murder&quot;&gt;U In Murder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Sloan’s store was called “The Patio.” It was smaller than Davies’ flower shop. A small, pasty-faced man came around the counter as Clint entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can I help you?” he began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You Mike Slone?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man bobbed his head. “That’s right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Detective Fleming,” Clint said. “Investigating the murder of Fred Jensen. Did you know him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Slone swallowed hastily. “Yes, I’d seen him around. Poor boy. I heard—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint leaned against a glass case, dug in his pocket, pulled out a crushed package of cigarettes, selected one and lit it. He blew out a cloud of blue smoke and asked, “Know anything about him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slone shook his head hastily. “Seemed like a bright boy. Lots of times I wished he was working for me—but I don’t know anything that would help you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint dragged on his cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Davies says you’ve threatened him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little man’s pale blue eyes widened. “I may have done some talking, but I didn’t mean anything by it, honest! He does a good business, and I guess sometimes I get jealous.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked thoughtful. “I see.” He shrugged, then, “Well, thanks. I’ll be going—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint left the store, got into his car. His eyes were narrowed, speculative. That gilt U—where did it fit? U for Unger, U in Murray, U in murder … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He steered his coupe through the traffic over to the West side where Jensen had lived. It was a red- bricked rooming house with a sign, “To Let” in a lower, dirt-smeared window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landlady leaned on her broom and waved him crossly up the stairs when he asked Jensen’s room number. He’d sent Wilson and the fingerprint gang over earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson opened the door at Clint’s knock. He grinned at the detective. “Though you’d be showing up soon.” Fleming glanced quickly around. “What you find?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson spread wide hands. “Everything—and nothing.” He waved a hand at the disorder of opened bureau drawers, clothes scattered on the floor, the bed ripped apart. “Place was like this when we came. The door had been forced. Somebody was powerfully anxious to find something—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint scarcely heard him, for he had walked a few steps, stooped and picked up a half dozen yellow pencils from the floor. He whistled a thin thread of a tune from between set teeth as he studied them. All the points were well worn down. There were teeth marks at the eraser ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seems,” he observed half to himself, “that our friend Mr. Jensen did a powerful lot of writing lately. Wonder what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;gardenia&quot;&gt;Gardenia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next afternoon Clint Fleming was exactly where he had been the day before—nowhere near a solution. He’d been to see the a solution. He’d been to see the chief —which did nothing for his ego, as Chief Cummings had said he’d better start showing some action, or else. And the “or else” had been punctuated by the slam of a big fist on the top of a desk … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked into the Davies’ flower store and Pat looked up from some violets she was stemming and came over to him. She looked better today —prettier, if possible. Some color had flowed back into her cheeks; her eyes had lost that reddened look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello there,” Clint said. He smiled, and Pat smiled back. This was more like it— “Your boss in?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl nodded, motioned with her red-curled head toward the balcony that ran half way around the inside of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s up in his office.” She rested quick fingers on his arm. “Have you found out anything?” she asked worriedly. Clint shook his head, and glanced past her to where Herb Martin and Jack Unger were standing. Neither smiled, and Herb’s eyes were chill as they met Clint’s In Unger’s, Clint saw sudden jealousy flare. Strangely, Clint wanted to grin—both those men were jealous of him! Of course, it was no wonder when a girl looked like Pat. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“See you later, chick,” he told her softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned and almost tripped over a flat, wood-slatted crate of roses that lay on the floor behind him. The roses were yellow-red and wrapped tightly in waxed paper. He bent and touched one of the buds with a forefinger—the flowers almost looked artificial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, behind him, someone snapped, “Keep your hands off those flowers!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He whirled and stared into the narrowed eyes of Herb Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why so touchy, Martin?” he asked quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man’s fist curled. “Roses cost money and I don’t want a dumb cop spoiling them—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint studied him coolly, then deliberately he bent down, broke off a bud and put it in his buttonhole. He gave it a final pat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So?” he suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin teetered close, his face dark with anger. Then, with an effort he kept his voice quiet. Over his shoulder he said, “Pat, fix Mr. Fleming a gardenia—he wants a boutonniere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, I already have one,” Clint told him, and turned and went up the stairs that led to Davies’ office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies was behind his desk. “Hello, Mr. Fleming,” he said. He pulled worriedly at his chin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint sat down in a straight-backed chair. “Now,” he began, “have you any idea why Jensen was here, alone, last night? Who closed the store?” Davies leaned back. “He did. I talked to Unger and Martin. They, and Miss Murray left the same time. Fred was going to clean up some things in the basement before he went home. I—” He broke off and stared at the rose in Fleming’s buttonhole. “Where did you get the Talisman?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint grinned. “It’s one of yours.” Davies seemed to be waiting for him to say more. Finally he asked slowly, “Martin give it to you?” “No—I took it. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies laughed falsely. “Martin’s very fussy about the roses. They’re sort of his department—” He tapped on his desk top with a pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint’s eyes were narrowed, watching him. “Yeah,” he said absently. Then he got to his feet. “Well, I’ll be shoving. See you around, Davies.” He went down the stairs and stopped at the counter where Pat was making the wired violets into a corsage. Her fingers were stained from the maidenhair fern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He kept his voice low, and for her ears. “Look,” he said. “Take care of yourself—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes widened. “Why—what’s the matter?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shrugged briefly. “I don’t know, but there’s plenty. Sometimes I get feelings—and I have one now.” He glanced around the shop. “The answer’s here someplace, if only I could find it—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abruptly he drew an order pad toward him and scribbled a number on it. He creased the sheet carefully and dropped it into Pat’s smock pocket. “This is just in case. If you hear anything, or see anything you think I ought to know about—call me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He caught Martin watching him, so he bent his head to the rose in his lapel. He took a deep sniff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This,” he said, “at least smells good—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;empty-buttonhole&quot;&gt;Empty Buttonhole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bell was ringing someplace. For a long time Fleming lay in his bed, his eyes closed, hoping it would go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t. Finally, with a sigh, he opened his eyes and reached for the alarm clock. His hand stopped half way through the motion—the room was dark. It was still night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sat up suddenly, awake now. He scooped the telephone receiver from its cradle on the nightstand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello?” he said sharply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A voice blurred at the other end. An excited voice; a voice shrill. Clint broke into the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy—I can’t understand you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Clint Fleming, isn’t it?” the voice wanted to know. He recognized it, then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it’s you, Pat,” he said quickly. “What’s wrong?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Clint—I’ve found out something!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes? What? Where are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m down at the store. I came back tonight. After you said you thought the answer was here, I decided to look around—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crazy kid!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I got to thinking about those Talisman roses. There’s something funny about those crates. I never—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint cut her off. “And what did you find?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—” she began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes—go on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no answer. Clint’s hand grew clammy on the receiver. He listened—the phone was dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat!” he shouted. Still the fear-starting silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one motion he had dropped the phone and was reaching for his clothes. There was only one reason why Pat didn’t answer—and that reason sent the blood from his face, leaving him white-lipped, trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He waited only long enough to pick up his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Clint Fleming careened his coupe through the deserted streets he suddenly reached up and felt at his buttonhole. The rose was gone; he had lost it someplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentally he damned himself—he’d had the answer on his lapel and never realized it! But what was the connection ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He screeched his car to a stop in front of the darkened flower shop, then he thought of calling the chief. But there wasn’t time for that now —not with Pat in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t expect the front door to be unlocked, but it was. It swung open under his hand and he walked into the store, his gun fisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat!” he called. “Where are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His voice echoed back at him, there was no other sound. Just the quiet, cool air, heavy with the scent of flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked softly to the basement door, opened it a crack. A light glimmered up from below, and he heard, now, a feverish rustling. Cautiously he started down the wooden&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stairs. The third step creaked under his weight, and abruptly the light winked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all—no sound, just the darkness rushing in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint stood where he was, poised, listening for the rasp of a foot, anything. There was nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He inched his wry forward, and again the stairs protested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, shattering the quiet, splitting the darkness, a gun spoke! Clint heard the bullet ricochet from the cement wall scarcely a foot from his head. But now he knew the direction, now he had a target for his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pulled the trigger twice, but his aim was wrong. Again the orange flame blossomed, and this time the slug was closer. Too close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He plunged down into the darkness, firing as he went, aiming a little to the left of the last flash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a sharp cry that slipped down scale into a moan—he hadn’t missed that time! He felt for the light switch at the foot of the stairs, flicked it. The shadows fled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the left, by a wooden crate, a man was sprawled. Fleming walked to him, turned him over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herb Martin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trickle of blood seeped out of his hair where Clint’s bullet had grazed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-roses&quot;&gt;The Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked at the crate. It was the same one he had seen earlier, only now the waxed-paper-wrapped bundles of roses lay scattered on the cement. He stooped, picked up a bunch. The buds were open—but not naturally—they had been forced open. The very center of the roses were missing. And then Clint saw the little pile of white-powder-filled capsules by Martin’s hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective whistled softly. “Dope,” he murmured. “So that’s the answer—they were smuggling dope in the roses. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would have to wait. Right now he had something more important to worry about—Pat was still missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned, went up the stairs, calling her name, searching the office. If she’s here, he thought, she’d answer—if she could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was no sign of the girl— she had disappeared completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was just passing the counter, on his way back downstairs, when his foot caught on something. He reached down and felt it. It was a string—no, it was a ribbon, a long streamer that unwound from the big spool on the counter as he pulled at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where was the other end? He tugged, the ribbon did not give. He hadn’t been able to find the switch that worked the fluorescent lights, so now he struck a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ribbon curled away into the gloom, toward the side of the store. Gathering it in his hand he followed it. It stopped at the crack of a small, narrow door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he knew. Pat was inside—in the refrigerator! He jerked open the door. The chill, icy air struck him as he went inside. He groped on the floor. His fingers overturned a vase, sent it crashing. Then he touched a shoulder, a face, soft hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t breathe as he bent over the girl—was she alive? She was, she stirred slightly and moaned. The other end of the ribbon spool was twisted in her fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He picked her up gently, whispering her name incoherently, and carried her out into the store. He laid her down. He thought savagely. Where is that damn switch—I have to see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time he found it, and the fluorescence flooded the room. In its soft glow he studied her face anxiously. Then he took a deep breath. She was going to be all right. Just knocked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes fluttered open and she struggled to sit up. Then she clung to him, sobbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all right, darling,” he soothed. “The roses—” she began brokenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all over. I know about them. Martin’s down in the basement, unconscious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then he—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hush, darling.” He helped her to her feet. “You all right now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She nodded, swaying a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint turned and went to the wall phone. He dialed a number, spoke briefly to the chief. Then he hung up and dialed another number. When a voice answered he said, “Davies— come on down, I’ve found your murderer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;fresh-flowers&quot;&gt;Fresh Flowers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cops were already there when the storeowner came hurrying in. His broad face was tense, and he looked as if he had fallen into his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to where Clint was standing, talking to the chief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who did it?” he demanded. “Was it Unger?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming shook his head slowly. “Davies, did you know that Martin was in the dope smuggling business?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man’s eyes widened and his face paled. “No—” he managed. “You mean, here, in my store?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint nodded. “Yes. That was why he didn’t let anyone touch certain crates of roses but himself—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And Fred Jensen must have discovered it,” Davies cut in. “And that was why he killed him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective shook his head slowly. “That may have been one of the reasons why Jensen had to die—but not the only one. Martin told me before they took him to the hospital. Jensen had discovered a formula for preserving fresh flowers. There’s thousands in such a discovery—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Jensen wanted to patent his formula, which was his right. For that, and because he was getting suspicious—he had to die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies shook his head bewilderedly. “To think that Martin killed Jensen—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A faint, hard smile flickered at Fleming’s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But he didn’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said—well, who did then?” Davies exploded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint’s voice was very quiet. “You did, Davies!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re insane!” The man backed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re the one who’s insane,” the detective said relentlessly. “Martin didn’t know actually who killed Jensen any more than I did—until I began to add things up. The flowers lasting longer in your store than anywhere else. The fact that Jensen’s room was searched. That damn U in Jensen’s fingers—I finally tumbled to the fact that the poor kid had been trying to spell out something … and ‘formula’ is about the only word with a u in it that would fit into the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wanted the discovery yourself, didn’t you, Davies? You pictured yourself cornering the flower market—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lie!” Davies cut in shrilly. Fleming went on savagely, as if he hadn’t heard. “You didn’t even trust Martin, so you did it yourself—and tried to pin it on Unger. Failing that, you would have let Martin die for the murder you committed. He’ll get plenty on the dope charge—but you, you’re going to get the chair!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his last words, Davies lunged at Clint, his short arms flailing. It was almost pitiful, the ease with which Clint’s rock-hard fist arced up and caught him on the point of his soft jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sagged to the floor without a sound, and disappeared under a wave of blue-coated backs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming rubbed skinned knuckles and walked to where Pat was standing, white-faced, her hand to her throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He put out an arm and drew her to him. She stared up at him with wide eyes. “How did you know for sure, Clint?” she whispered shakily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grinned and kissed her on the tip of her tilted nose. “There was one little thing that really set me thinking—those pencils I found in Jensen’s room. They were all badly chewed. And then I saw Davies playing with a chewed pencil. I knew it wasn’t his, that he had picked it up someplace— It might have been coincidence—but it started me thinking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But how did you know it wasn’t Davies’?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming laughed deep in his throat. “A guy with false teeth doesn’t go around biting on pencils, does he?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he looked at Pat a long moment. “How good are you at making bridal bouquets?” he asked suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because I got a feeling we’re going to be needing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/nice-corpses-like-flowers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/nice-corpses-like-flowers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Murder in Small Packages</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-paper-wrapped-package&quot;&gt;The Paper-Wrapped Package&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the newspaper truck pulled up and the late afternoon editions thudded on the pavement beside Gimpy’s stand, Benny Kerr got up from his park bench and started over. He’d read the latest on the torso murders, get a bowl of chili, and take in the double feature at the Bijou.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny admired Gimpy’s quickness, as the lame little newsdealer slashed the ropes on the bundle of papers and whisked headlines into view. During the past couple months, since the tool factory reconverted and he’d been laid off, Benny had come to the park every day and watched Gimpy work. Benny had seen the steady business Gimpy did in papers and magazines. He’d got to thinking that when there were plenty of cigarettes, gum, and candy again, Gimpy would be needing a helper. Benny meant to get that job. It might not pay as much, buck for buck, as working in the stockroom at the factory, but there’d be no layoffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny fished for a nickel, saw a big shot grab a paper from Gimpy, sit down, and turn to the stock market page. Benny eyed the black-eyed, black-mustached man cannily. Chances were the guy would be finished with the paper in a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny waited, bright hazel eyes studying the headlines: Second Paper-wrapped Torso Found in Warehouse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were the same headlines as in the earlier editions, but Benny swallowed. Because when it happens close to home, that’s what you do—you swallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smaller type said, Victim identified as Teresa Famette, employee of Acme Tool Co.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny shivered. Because when it happens to someone you know, you do that, too—you shiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tessie Famette, the second victim, had worked in the offices at the tool company and had often brought inter-department memos to the stockroom to give Benny. So had Rosa Scalise, the girl whose dismembered body had turned up first, about ten days ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The papers said the killer was a maniac who prowled the tenement district where Tessie and Rosa had lived. Yet he must he an inconspicuous man, for no one had actually seen him drop one of the paper-wrapped parcels that had turned up in sewers, in refuse cans, in subway stations and movie houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny Kerr blew his nose, winced at the swift pain in his nasal passages. Benny sniffled just as much now, in August, as in midwinter. Doc Kunz was treating him with some sort of medicine the doc had patented, but it didn’t seem to help much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Benny put his handkerchief away, his eyes drifted over the park bench up on the knoll, fascinated. One of the paper-wrapped packages had been found right there, a leg. Matt Hurley, the park cop, had sworn no suspicious strangers had been in the park that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny leaned forward. The big shot had tossed his paper on the bench and was hailing a cab. Benny swooped and grabbed the paper. He saw the package underneath it, snatched it up, and turned to give it back to the man. But the man was already in the cab. It moved away. Benny yelled, and stood there waving the package foolishly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was when he got the impact of the big shot’s glittering black eyes for the first time. The man was looking through the rear window of the taxi, the skin on his cheekbones drawn tight, his lips a white slash. His black eyes were like chips of hard coal behind which a fire blazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny couldn’t pull his gaze away from those hypnotic eyes until the man whipped around to the taxicab driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny saw the driver shake his head and gestured at the streams of traffic on both sides. He couldn’t stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eyes came back to Benny, burned through the window, burned into Benny’s scrawny little form, cataloguing every detail. Benny grabbed for his handkerchief. He was sniffling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;he-might-even-be-you&quot;&gt;He Might Even Be You&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab was lost in traffic, then. Benny was left clutching the oblong package. He hefted it, licking his Ups. There must be something pretty valuable in it. That’s why the black-eyed man had studied him; he wanted his package back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was heavier than it looked, pliable yet resistant. It was the size and shape of a roll of bologna. Benny couldn’t resist looking. He intended to stay right where he was, sure that the big shot would get out of the cab and hurry back here first chance. Just the same he couldn’t resist looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny pulled the string off one end, parted the paper. Then he stiffened and felt the hard seat of the park bench behind him catch his thighs, as his knees gave out. Every muscle in Benny’s skinny frame became a tight, twanging string. His hazel eyes glazed. His one look had told him he was holding one of those packages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the bull voice of Matt Hurley, the park cop, that brought Benny awake. “Benny! Hey, you forgot your package!” Benny skidded, shook his head, stopped. He saw that he was thirty feet from the bench where he’d found it. He’d been fleeing instinctively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley’s red-faced bulk plodded toward Benny. One massive, freckled paw shoved the package back into Benny’s hand. The other held the newspaper Hurley had picked up. He glared at the headlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I could just get my mitts on that guy!” Hurley burst out. “They say he’s a nut, but I say different. He’s a guy we probably know, somebody right down in our neighborhood, somebody who hangs around the park, too. He could be anybody at all. He might even be you, Benny. He left one of those packages right here under my nose. I’d just like to see him leave another one! What’s the matter, Benny? Sick?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Y-yeah!” Benny gurgled, his thin cheeks like ashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley slapped Benny’s shoulder. “Better tell Doc Kunz to give you regular medicine, not any of that stuff he makes up himself. See you tomorrow, kid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny watched Hurley’s blue-coated back move off. He scuttled to a refuse can, caught himself. No! If the package were found here, Hurley surely would remember Benny had had one. For a second, Benny tried to get enough moisture into his mouth to yell after Hurley. Then he recalled Hurley’s words. He could be anybody, anybody at all. He might even be you, Benny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny’s paper-thin soles slapped the sidewalk. He had to run. Hide. Get rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet he couldn’t get rid of it. He couldn’t drop it, throw it, not in this neighborhood. It was a magnet, sticking to him, sending its clammy coldness through the paper to paralyze his fingers. Benny fled to the only cover he could think of—his room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d forgotten the black-eyed, black-mustached man. Suddenly he thought of him again, glanced back over his shoulder like a scrawny hound dog might glance at a can tied to his tail. Benny didn’t see the man. He decided the man wouldn’t be coming back after all. Why would anybody come back after this, if he’d once got rid of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Benny was wrong. If he’d looked again, he’d have seen those black eyes hard on him, craftily waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny took his usual route home. Six blocks from the park, he turned right, five blocks more, right again. Down an alley, past the warehouse—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where Benny’s teeth chattered harder. Here, in this gloomy old building, was where Tessie’s torso had been found. There was a crowd around, though the homicide squad was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, Benny,” said Doc Kunz. Benny jerked. The gaunt black shoestring of a doctor was at his elbow, slightly bleared blue eyes studying him professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong, Benny?” Kunz asked. “Excitement too much for you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny’s lips worked. He almost blurted it out. He was reaching the point where he had to tell someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“N-noI I’m okay, doc I” Benny blurted and ducked toward the sanctuary of his room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll stop in and have a look at you after I see Mrs. Grady,” Kunz said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No! Don’t come near. I mean, okay, doc!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-black-eyed-man&quot;&gt;The Black-Eyed Man&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny ducked into the doorway of the tenement where he lived. He went up the first two flights fast, but on the third his chest began to hurt. He stopped, leaned against the narrow bannister, breathing jerkily at the musty, thick-hot air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black-eyed man was breathing rapidly, too. This sound was what sent Benny’s eyes skittering behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shriek tore at his vocal chords, never sounded. Benny couldn’t get it out. Then the black-eyed man was upon him, hand clamped over Benny’s mouth. The steel- strong fingers ground the bones of Benny’s jaw together, bruised Benny’s lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be quiet! Take me to your room. I’ll make you rich if you hold your tongue.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man shook Benny a little, eyes glowing even in the shadows of the stairway. He took his hands away tentatively, grabbed Benny again. Benny would have melted onto the steps without support. The only thing with strength was his heart, thumping, thumping. He even dropped the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black-eyed man scooped up the package, pushed Benny ahead. There was no sound from him. He might have slipped away, Benny thought, as he reeled up the last steps to his room, only he hadn’t. Benny could feel the man, back there. He could feel his eyes. Benny turned the knob of his door, tried to dive in and slam it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man was ready for him. He shoved Benny into the room, slammed the door himself, snicked the lock. Benny backed away from him, still unable to make more that little, squeaking sounds. He backed into the bed, fell on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death reached for his throat. Benny saw the slender, strong fingers stretch an l start for him. He saw the burning black eyes, the slashed lips under the black mustache. He scrounged back on the bed, hit the wall. He could go no farther. He felt his mouth opening, his tongue protruding, his eyes bulging even before the fingers touched him. He was choking himself, practically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt his head get thick. Blackness swirled around him. Then those hands were on him. But they weren’t choking him. They were shaking him, jarring him back to consciousness. And the black- eyed man’s low voice was warning, “Quiet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny saw why now. He heard the knocking on his door. He heard Doc Kunz’s voice insisting, “Let me in, Benny. I want to look at you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black-eyed man caught Benny’s chin in his hand, turned Benny’s eyes up into his own. The whole strength of the man’s personality was in the onyx stare he centered on Benny. That stare held Benny transfixed, sucked the little strength out of him, bored in under his hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Meet me in the park tonight at nine o’clock,” the man commanded softly. “I’ll be on the bench I sat on today. I’ll have money for you, a thousand dollars. That will be only the first payment. I’ll make you rich, understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Benny, let me in!” Doc Kunz roared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will you be there?” the black-eyed man hissed. “Do you want money?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny heard a voice not at all like his own pant, “Yeah! Yeah, I’ll be there! Yeah, I want money! Yeah, yeah, yeah!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He realized vaguely that something stronger than himself had taken over, instinct. He was saying anything at all to gain respite, anything to get this black- eyed monster away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man hesitated, trying, it seemed, to peel back Benny’s skull and look inside it. Suddenly he grated his teeth like a man risking all on a long shot. “I’ll give you five thousand for the first payment!” he said harshly. “Nine o’clock. The park. Be there. No harm will come to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man looked about the room for another means of exit, scorned the fire escape window, strode to the door, unlocked it and pushed past Doc Kunz brazenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kunz fell back in surprise. “I’ll be damned!” He turned to Benny as the man disappeared down the stairs. “How did you ever get him interested in your case, Benny?” Kunz demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny croaked, “Him? Is he a d-d-doc-tor?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, he’s famous!” Kunz said. “Dr. Haswell Falik. He’s a psychiatrist. He—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Benny was blacking out now. The strain was over. The reaction set in …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;meet-falik&quot;&gt;Meet Falik&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Benny came to, there was a pleasant stupor in his limbs. He was in bed. Doc Kunz was bending over him. The doctor’s words came slowly, as from a great distance. He was questioning Benny. Benny answered with no trouble at all. He didn’t realize that the morphine Kunz had given him was responsible for his sense of ease and well-being. He knew only that he was safe and sleepy. He told his story from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny heard Doc exclaim occasionally. He heard him mutter, too. But Benny didn’t pay much attention. Once, he looked up at Doc’s gaunt, cadaverous face, the lines of dissipation running from Doc’s nostrils to his lax lips, and thought vaguely that the doctor looked like a man who was smoking marijuana. The doc’s blue eyes weren’t a bit bleary now. The parchment-like skin on his high cheekbones showed spots of color. His long arms flapped about him, the fingers twitching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny heard the doc muttering, “Falik? The great Haswell Falik! The mind doctor gone the way of his patients. He’ll plead insanity, of course. The fool!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny saw the doc’s hollow eyes glow. Suddenly they were almost like those black eyes that could pin his heart to his ribs with just a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He was going to take advantage of me!” Doc Kunz mumbled. Then he laughed loudly and long. He didn’t laugh at anything funny, though. He cackled. He took a bottle from his bag and drank deeply. Then he tramped from the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny let blissful drowsiness overcome him. He went to sleep, troubled only by the sudden wonder at how Dr. Falik could possibly have been going to take advantage of Doc Kunz. Kunz was a seedy slum doctor. Falik was a big- shot psychiatrist. Doc Kunz had recognized Falik, because Falik was famous. But Falik hadn’t even noticed Doc Kunz. So why or how could he take advantage of him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Benny awoke, Doc Kunz was beside him again. “Listen, Benny, I know everything. Everything, understand? You told it all while you were half-conscious. Don’t be afraid, Benny. You’ve got to help me catch Falik.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc Kunz cackled at that and repeated, “Catch Falik! Ah, that’s good!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny felt prickles between his shoulder blades. He shook his head groggily. The doc didn’t look like himself at all, didn’t sound like himself. Benny sat up, pulling the sheet around his thin chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look, Benny!” Doc Kunz shoved a newspaper onto Benny’s knees. “The arm you found in that package didn’t belong to Tessie Famette at all. It belonged to somebody else, another torso victim, Benny. Falik’s victim!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny gazed at the newspaper, at a paragraph on an inside page which said, “Mr. and Mrs. Jason Devers today told the police that their daughter Jennifer, 22, has not been home for two days. Mr. Devers admitted that his daughter had been under the care of Dr. Haswell Falik, eminent psychiatrist. Dr. Falik insisted the girl was quite normal when she left his office, two days ago, but no trace of her can be found.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc Kunz cackled, “Of course, no trace of her was found. Falik killed her. Dissected her body, and started to get rid of it just like—Never mind, that was the Devers’ girl’s arm you found, Benny, not Tessie Famette’s. Now tonight, Benny I want you to meet—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Falik?” Benny cried. “No! I won’t! I can’t! Doc, I’m too scared of him! He’ll get me, too!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, he won’t Benny!” Doc said sharply. “Don’t worry. You’ll help catch him, that’s all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny shrank against his pillow. “No! I’m afraid. I’m going to tell the cops. I’m going to get Matt Hurley and—” The doc chuckled, “I’ve already talked to Hurley, Benny! He’ll be right on hand, don’t think he won’t. He’s going to be in the park. When Falik tries to—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tries to kill me!” Benny burst. “Is that it? You’re going to use me as bait!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Easy, now, Benny,” Doc soothed. “You don’t have anything to be afraid of. Hurley won’t let anything happen. He’ll be right there. He’ll catch Falik red-handed. That’s what we want, don’t we? Benny, you want Falik caught, don’t you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny sniffled. “I don’t care! I’m scared! Once I look at his eyes, Doc, I–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pshaw! Don’t look at them, then. You’re afraid Falik will hypnotize you? Nonsense!” Doc Kunz snorted. “I’m a doctor, too, Benny. Falik uses hypnotism, sure, but no one can hypnotize you if you resist them. They can’t do it with one look, either. Don’t be afraid of that, Benny. Hurley and I will be close. All you have to do is go with Falik, do what he wants you to do. He’ll lead us to the rest of the Devers girl’s body.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But, doc—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, Benny,” Doc Kunz frowned. “You want to co-operate with the cops, don’t you? You don’t want Matt Hurley to think you’re protecting Falik?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good! That’s the stuff. Now look. It’s only eight o’clock. Get your clothes on, but don’t leave here for about forty minutes. About a quarter to nine or a little earlier, go over to the park. Meet Falik and do everything he tells you. Got that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny peered at Doc’s burning eyes, his gaunt, lined face. The doctor looked like a buzzard, like a leering old buzzard getting ready to pounce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;but-no-hurley&quot;&gt;But No Hurley&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny forced himself to nod. He understood all too well. He was bait. Doc said he and Matt Hurley would be nearby, but Benny chewed his lips and sniffled. Benny wouldn’t let tears come to his eyes while Doc was there, but when the black, stringy man left the room Benny hugged the sheet around himself tightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He fumbled with his clothing. It was hot and muggy, but he went to the closet and put on a blue turtleneck sweater that was slack around his toothpick neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told himself he was okay. Hurley and Doc Kunz were on his side. He was already cleared so far as having had that package in his possession, because Doc had told Hurley how it had happened. Hurley believed Doc. But would the big cop continue to believe Doc if Benny didn’t play his part tonight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny trembled. He had to go through with it. If he didn’t show up, Hurley would figure Doc had been drunk and had spun a crazy story. Just the same, the cop would come back at Benny, drag him down to headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minutes ticked away with maddening slowness, yet with haste, too. Benny couldn’t understand it; his old alarm clock dragged and hurried at the same time. Twenty minutes whispered by. Another twenty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Suppose Falik comes here!” The words blurted out of Benny’s white lips, hung in the hot air in his tiny room echoed off the walls. For two full minutes afterwards Benny was incapable of motion. The paroxysms of trembling shot down into his legs. He scampered for the door. He stopped, fingers on the knob, ears actually moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone was coming up the stairs. Benny’s nostrils quivered, but he couldn’t breathe. He couldn’t even sniffle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The almost inaudible scrape of feet on the staircase were so light a mouse might be causing them. Only Benny knew it was no mouse. It was a human being, coming closer, coming toward the door, stopping outside, leaning his ear against the flimsy wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny Kerr moved again as he had done when he’d fled from the park bench that afternoon, instinctively, without conscious volition. He ducked out the window and clambered down the fire escape. It wasn’t until he was in the alley behind the tenement building that he became conscious of hi3 surroundings. It was black down there, a fearsome place to be caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny looked up, saw a shadow on the fire escape. He ran as he never had run before. At long last, the nervous energy found some place to spend itself. Benny’s thin legs turned into driving pistons. The hard slap-slap of his feet was a tattoo on the cobbled alley. It was a sweet sound in Benny’s ears. For as energy surged through his limbs, he knew he was running as a champion sprinter. Nothing on two legs would catch him if he kept this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another thing, too. If Falik was chasing him, then Falik wasn’t in the park. Benny could run there and yell for Hurley and Doc. They’d jump out and pounce on Falik then, with no more laying traps. They’d grab the black-eyed man quick. Benny would see them with his own two eyes. He knew he’d never have nerve enough to enter his room again unless he did see Falik captured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny passed the warehouse like a wraith. He went down an alley. Turn left. Left again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny slackened a little, approached the park warily. Hurley and Doc Kunz would be hiding somewhere, probably near the bench where Benny was supposed to meet Falik. Benny’s eyes darted toward that bench. His senses reeled. Falik was there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny couldn’t believe it, yet it was so. Falik was alone on the bench, waiting. Benny shook his head. Falik must have grabbed a taxi when he’d failed to catch Benny and hurried to the park. Benny wanted to cry. Now he’d have to go through with it after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glanced fitfully about. If he could get just one glimpse of Matt Hurley’s bulk, he’d feel better. But Hurley was nowhere in sight. There were a couple of old men scattered about on the benches, some kids, but no Hurley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;room-317&quot;&gt;Room 317&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s okay, Benny.” The voice came from nowhere. Benny jumped. It came again. “Don’t worry, Benny. I’m behind this tree.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny saw who it was, now—Doc Kunz. His long, cadaverous frame blended into the shadow behind a tree. He waved Benny toward the bench where Falik sat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny stumbled forward, walked up to Falik. “H-here I am,” he stuttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black eyes impaled him. In the night they seemed deeper, darker, yet more fiery, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falik’s lips and mustache didn’t move, but his words were clear. “Go across the street to the Grayson Hotel. Room 317. The door is open. Don’t talk to anybody. I’ll follow you. I’ve got the money,” Falik added quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny didn’t bother to nod. He made a beeline for the hotel, a third-rate place with a shabby, deserted lobby. The desk clerk glanced carelessly at Benny, then away. Benny skittered toward the stairs. He didn’t know why he avoided the elevator, but had he seen the pleased light in the black eyes behind him when the desk clerk paid him no attention, he would have stopped dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny climbed to the third floor. Room 317 was unlocked, as Falik had said it would be. Benny went in, switched on the lights. In a second, Falik came in. He looked Benny coldly up and down, then he looked away. For once, those black eyes stopped boring into Benny’s soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny held his breath. What was Falik waiting for? Why didn’t he say something, do something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny got his answer when the door opened again and Doc Kunz came in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc Kunz came in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc nodded to Falik. Doc took a little phial from his pocket. Doc said, “Ready, Falik?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was when the blinding truth flooded through Benny Kerr. Not all the truth, just the most important part for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc wasn’t on his side, he was on Falik’s side!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny charged for the door. Falik caught him from behind. Doc’s long stringy arms shot out in front. Falik dragged Benny back to the bed, forced him down on it, pinned him with a knee, used those steel fingers again on Benny’s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this time to force Benny’s mouth open, not shut. For Doc Kunz had uncorked the phial and was ready to force the contents down Benny’s throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did it. He jammed the neck of the phial between Benny’s lips as Falik’s fingers forced open Benny’s mouth. Benny felt bitter liquid trickling over his tongue, down his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew it was poison. He knew Falik and Doc Kunz were murdering him. He felt the poison hit his stomach. He felt himself grow weak. He thought, They’ll cut me up and wrap me in packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falik’s knee came off Benny’s chest. Benny tried to rise, couldn’t. A heavy lethargy was upon him. He could see dimly, hear vaguely, but he couldn’t speak or move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in a dream, he saw Falik go to the closet, pull out paper-wrapped packages. There was the package Benny had discovered, he could never mistake that. There was another package like it. There were two more like those, only larger. Then there was a fifth package, larger. But Falik handled it easily. Jennifer Devers hadn’t been heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You don’t have to drag them out,” Doc Kunz said thickly. “Don’t you think the cops will search the place?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you think they’ll believe its suicide?” Falik asked uncertainly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc Kunz cackled. “What else? Don’t worry about that. I’ve already talked to a cop, suggested that Benny was a little nutty. I talked to Matt Hurley about ten minutes before Benny was due to leave for the park. Hurley went over to question him, so he’s looking for him right now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falik nodded. Benny saw him only as a blur. Benny was realizing that he had fled from Hurley, not Falik. If only he hadn’t, he thought. If only he hadn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too late, though, and dying wasn’t so hard after all. It was pleasant, really. Like going to sleep, positive that you will sleep sound, without dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falik’s words drifted to him dimly. “You fool! Do you think I’m going to let you live to blackmail me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny heard a faint little popping somewhere. It didn’t sound loud enough to be a gun. But a second later, there was the bam of a Police Positive. Benny knew that was a gun all right. The first one must have had a silencer on it, he thought. He drifted off … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;might-even-be-me&quot;&gt;Might Even Be Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly it was much harder getting awake than it had been going to sleep. Sleeping had been peaceful. Getting awake again brought with it pain and nausea. The thick, rubbery thing in his mouth, Benny learned later, was a stomach pump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re tougher than you look, Benny boy,” said a voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny saw Matt Hurley’s red face beaming at him. “How did you—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy, kid,” Hurley said. “You’re a good little runner, but I’m not so bad myself. I chased after you to the park, caught up just in time to see you go across to that hotel. Falik followed you, and Doc Kunz followed Falik. I strung along and listened outside the hotel room door. I didn’t know they were going to feed you poison and leave you there with the Devers girl’s body. But when Falik took a shot at Doc Kunz, I jumped in and took a shot at him. Doc Kunz is dead but he talked. I only winged Falik; he’ll go to the chair.” Benny gagged a little. “They were going to kill me, leave me there with Jennifer Devers’ body so you’d think I was the maniac killer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley nodded. “But there was no maniac after all. Doc Kunz cut up the first two bodies to cover himself. What happened, Benny, was that Doc gave Rosa Scalise, the first girl to be found, some of his homemade medicine and it killed her. To cover himself, he cut her up like that, figuring the public would think a maniac was loose. Tessie Famette, the second victim, was Rosa Scalise’s friend who knew Rosa had been going to Doc Kunz. She got suspicious so Doc killed her too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny burst, “And when Falik killed the third girl, Jennifer Dever3, he tried to take advantage—” Benny stopped, recalling Doc Kunz’s mutterings that afternoon. “That’s what Doc Kunz meant when he said Falik was trying to take advantage of him!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right,” Hurley agreed. “Falik got the story of a secret marriage out of Jennifer Devers when he was treating her. He blackmailed her for months. Then she said she was going to the cops, and Falik killed her. He figured if he cut her up and planted packages around the neighborhood where two other torso murders had already been done, the^ same man would be blamed for everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only I caught him planting the very first package,” Benny shuddered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, you’re always hanging around the park,” Hurley shrugged. “It wasn’t so funny that it was you who saw him. The thing was you should have told me right away instead of Doc Kunz. The minute Kunz knew you’d found another package, he knew somebody else had committed murder. Even if he hadn’t seen Falik in your room, he could easily have searched the paper for missing people and figured out who had killed who. He saw a chance to frame it all on the dumb bunny who had blundered into it—you, Benny; so he went to Falik. They worked together until they thought everything was set.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley shook his head reprovingly. “You should’ve told me, Benny. You should’ve told me right off. Why didn’t you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benny shivered all over. “Because you said it—might even be me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/murder-in-small-packages/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/murder-in-small-packages/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You&#39;ll Kill the People</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-9&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-10&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-10&quot;&gt;Chapter 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;you-kill-me&quot;&gt;You Kill Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The orchestra gave him a couple of bars, for an introduction, and he stood there, still a little uncomfortable under the staring eyes of the TV cameras and a dozen assorted studio technicians, and gave out with his rich baritone on an oldie, something called Careless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sang with feeling. Professionally, he now called himself Burton, Buddy Burton, but he had been born plain Joe Caterisano, in a brick row house on the outskirts of Newark, NJ. His Latin blood showed in his raven black hair, in his slightly overripe but wholly natural gestures, as he punched emphasis into the worn-out words of the old song lyric. He was swarthily, masculinely handsome, and he sang, people said, like a bird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You kill me,” a girl had told him at a party, a few evenings ago. “I don’t know what you’ve got, but every time I hear you sing something inside of me starts to flutter and then I just go all to pieces.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll settle for that inside flutter,” he had gagged. “I don’t want to kill anybody, Miss Barney.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wished everyone well. The world, of late, had been a wonderful place to be in, from his personal standpoint. After he’d knocked them dead in the three nightclub bookings, his agent, Max Gittman, had got him this spot on TV, a fifteen-minute, three-nights-a-week summer sustain-er, and now things were coming his way so fast he was dizzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kid, you’re a shoo-in,” Max had told him. “Ever since you chucked that library of Como, Clark, Crosby and Sinatra in the ashcan, and started being plain Joe Caterisano—er, excuse me, Buddy Burton, that is —I could smell success on you. I mean strong, kid. Like garlic. I’ll make a prediction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What, Max?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Two years from now,” Max said, “you’ll be so fat you won’t know what to do with your money. You’re on the way, kid, and all roads lead up, in a hurry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrapped up his smooth rendition of Careless, giving it that characteristic Buddy Burton punch at the end, and a few seconds later the big red hand moved past the hour, and be could relax once more. The hungry eyes of the TV cameras no longer gobbled up each small derail of his face and figure for projection into millions of homes throughout the eastern half of the nation served by this TV network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rode the elevator down to the studio garage, and drove his car downtown and through the Tunnel, and an hour later be was relaxing in the living room of his modest house in the Jersey suburbs, listening to Marie tell him how she bad reacted to his broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t pick out anything to criticize, Joe,” she said seriously, a little loving frown on her pretty face, for she knew how he hungered for any small criticism which might help him improve on his performance. “You put those three songs over perfect.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on, baby,” be pleaded. “There must’ve been something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know what,” she said. “Even when you were talking with the announcer, you seemed—just natural. Like it wasn’t something somebody had written down for you to say.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was perfect then?” Joe kidded. “Better watch out baby. I’ll be getting swell-headed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No you won’t,” Marie said, and she smiled, a small and warm movement of her pretty lips. “You’re too sensible for that, Joe. You worked eight years for this and you’re thirty years old, a man with a wife and three children, and a sense of humor about things. I guess I know my husband by now, Joe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she kissed him fondly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-note&quot;&gt;A Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They went up to bed and at eleven-thirty, the phone rang. Joe threw a robe over pajamas and padded downstairs in bare feet to see what it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Burton?” the voice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Buddy Burton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You stink, Burton. I caught you on the TV tonight, and you stink.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had only just begun to be somebody, but he bad always known that once he got there he would have cranks to contend with. He couldn’t help grinning, remembering what he’d said to Marie about getting stuck on himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much danger of that, with characters around like this one on the other end of the wire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You may have something there, pal. Anything else on your mind? If not, I’ll go back to bed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put that voice or whatever you call it in mothballs, Burton. Go back to driving a truck for a living.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not till I have to,” he laughed, trying to keep this exchange on a good-natured level. “There’s more dough in the singing than in truck driving.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get off the TV, Burton,” the voice gritted. “That’s a warning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone clicked dead and he stood there frowning at it for a moment before he replaced it in its cradle. Upstairs, Marie said sleepily, “Who was it, honey?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just some squawk,” Joe said. “Wanted to tell me I can’t sing worth a damn.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie’s eyes opened, showing fright for a moment, and he said comfortingly,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess we’re really on our way now, baby. Max Gittman says you can tell you’re beginning to get there when people start pestering you this way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie was up earlier than he, because of the kids. She went down and brought the milk in, and promptly ran upstairs to show him a note that had been thrust under the kitchen door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been fashioned out of words and letters snipped from the New York newspapers. It said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GET OUT OF TV, KID. BIG MONEY AIN’T WORTH IT. HOW MUCH DOUGH CAN YOU SPEND SIX FEET UNDER?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m scared,” Marie said. Her eyes were wide, under the dark lashes, and her mouth trembled. “What are we going to do, Joe?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just some nut,” Joe said. “Some—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t dismiss it like that, Toe. This is a threat on your life. Take it to the police. Please?” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He frowned at the prospect, but looking at Marie, sensing her fear for his safety, he knew he had no real choice in the matter…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;whaddaya-want-me-to-do&quot;&gt;Whaddaya Want Me To Do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Under the kitchen door, hey?” the Chief of Police said. He bit the end off a stogie and stared hard at Joe across the tip of it, before striking his match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I been seeing you on my television, kid. You sing pretty. On your way, I’d say. Maybe another Sinatra.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you,” Joe said, and his cheeks reddened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now,” said the chief, “lemme get this thing straight. A guy phones you last night, tells you you stink as a crooner, and tells you to go back driving a truck, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right,” Joe nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You laugh him off, so this a.m. the wife finds the note. All right, now whaddaya want me to do, Burton?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know your business, Chief. What’s your usual—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Usually, in a case like this, we’d turn the story over to the newspaper and the publicity, plus the information we’re holding ourselves responsible for your personal safety, would be enough to scare whoever put that note under your door back in his rat hole.” The chief blew cigar smoke at him, and frowned thoughtfully through it. “But somehow I ain’t worried about your safety, Burton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What does that mean?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Judging from the way you’re coming along as a crooner, I’d say you got a smart business manager. Right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right. Max Gittman.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give Max Gittman a message for me, will you, kid?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What message?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell him my police department is gettin’ tired of bein’ the Patsy for every young Tom, Dick and Harry in show business that wants to stir up a fuss and get his name splashed around in the papers, complete with a picture showing his best profile to his public.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You think this is just a publicity stunt,” Joe said woodenly. “But it—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get outta here, Burton. I’m gonna tell you something. I got three girls home that are coming the dangerous age, and I don’t like crooners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I give you enough time already. Get out. Tell that Gittman what I said. You want publicity, you go out and earn it. Go overseas and entertain some of the boys that are fighting to keep this country safe for you crooners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I did my share of that,” Joe protested hotly. “I spent three years as a dogface, back in—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t cry on me, Burton. I lost two boys over there in the last one. Now get outta here, before I lose my temper.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;this-is-a-stick-up&quot;&gt;This Is A Stick-Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He drove in Tuesday afternoon to rehearse for that evening’s slow, and Alec Thornbush, the program director, remarked that he seemed nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s nothing,” Joe told him. “Been off my feed the last day or two, Alec.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got through the show better than he had hoped to, rising to the occasion like any seasoned campaigner, but he hurried down to get his car, when it was over. In the back of his mind was a nameless worry; somehow he was eager to be home again, to know that Marie and the kids were okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he nosed the car out to the street, he had to wait for the light to change at the corner. A man in a light tan topcoat, wearing a felt bat pulled low over his eyes, stepped casually up to the car, on the passenger side, opened the door, and slid in beside Joe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe felt a tightness in his throat as he peered toward the intruder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry,” he said, underplaying his role. “No riders.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess you said that a lot back when you were wheeling a truck for a living, didn’t you, Caterisano? This is a gun in my pocket.” He jabbed it through the tan cloth of the coat, stretching the cloth out to a little cone against the gun’s muzzle, so Joe could get the idea. “Drive,” he suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe saw that the street was momentarily clear and he swung out from the garage, heading toward the Avenue of the Americas. “This is a stick-up,” he suggested hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You recognized me. You want my money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Drive,” the man said. He kept his face averted. He had on thick-lensed glasses. His coat lapels were turned up, hiding his chin and partly concealing his mouth.“And don’t do anything I might not like, pal. You just did another TV show, Caterisano. After I asked you not to. You get me kind of mad, pal. I don’t know what I’m goin’ to do with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s this all about?” Joe said angrily. “I never saw you before, friend. Why should you have it in for me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Another thing,” the man said. “You went to the cops, after I left that note under the kitchen door.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I happen to know you did. Because I tailed you. You made me plenty mad, pal. What did the cops say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man not only talked mad, he looked mad. The gun again made a cone-shaped bulge against, the pocket of the tan topcoat, and, like a dog, the man seemed to be bristling with anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They laughed at me,” Joe tried to mollify him. “They seemed to think I was gunning for some free publicity at their expense, if yon must know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know something?” the man laughed. “I can believe that. I don’t think you’re lying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s your angle?” Joe said. “What do you want of me? I don’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pull up to the curb down there in the next block, Caterisano, and turn off that ignition. We’ll talk a little.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;mr-x&quot;&gt;Mr. X.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe parked at the curb and turned for a better look at his rider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man said, “Uh-unh. Yon keep staring straight ahead, through the windshield. Now, you asked what I want, and I’ve already told you, but I’m ready to give you one more chance, pal. I want you to quit singing. Get oat of show business, see? Find some other way to earn a living, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I worked hard for the break I’m finally getting,” Joe said. “What are you, some kind of a nut? You don’t know what you’re asking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m telling, not asking. Get out of show business, Caterisano, or—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Or what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll kill you,” the man said in a matter-of-fact tone of voice that sent a sharp chill up Joe’s backbone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?” Joe said. “Be reasonable. I’m entitled to at least some explanation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll give you some explanation,” the man said. “I’m a guy who never took to working for a living, pal. The way I get mine is my own business, see? And let’s say the cops would like to make it their business, but I’m just a little too smart for them. Get the idea?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More or less.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve never been mugged. I’ve never been printed,” the man said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t pull off many jobs, and when I do pull one off, I make it a big one. I operate solo. I trust nobody. I never go after anything but the hard cash. Jewelry has a way of fingering a guy, sooner or later. I won’t have anything to do with it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe said, “I guess I’m not very bright. What does all this have to do with my getting out of show business?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So far I’m an anonymous,” the man said. “I’m Mr. X. Oh, I been seen by a few people. But you know, it’s kind of funny how little help that is to the cops, pal. A guy walks into a place and holds it up, let’s say, for a couple of thousand, and gets away clean. So the guy on the unhappy end of the stickup goes to the cops and gives his description of the man, and what’s it add up to? Tall, dark, maybe handsome, dressed in this or that color suit. So what of it? What are the bulls going to do with it? Nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If there’s a gimmick here somewhere,” Joe said wearily, “I still don’t get it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t worry about it,” the man said. “Start the car. Get it rolling. When we get down to that next stoplight, I’ll be getting out, pal. And you’ll keep on rolling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see,” Joe said and it did not occur to him to disobey the man’s curt instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One thought I’m goin’ to leave with you, pal. Get out of show business. Break clean, see? One more TV show, like tonight, and I’m goin’ to have to do for you. You can make your own choice, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe had come by now to the stoplight. It was red. He pulled up, waiting. The man opened the door and stepped onto the paving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just drive on when the light changes,” he said. “Don’t look back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light changed. Joe started the car, started across the intersection, and pivoted on the seat for a quick look at his man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bright headlights from the oncoming traffic flickered momentarily across the man’s face, spotlighting him, half-blinding him for one instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Caterisano got a very good look at the man, despite the lowered hat brim, the turned-up lapels of the coat, the eyeglasses. A sharp pulse of surprise slid through his tense body as he drove the big car down the street, and he said softly, “Well, I’ll be damned. So that’s his angle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;i-aint-buying&quot;&gt;I Ain’t Buying&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chief of Police stared at Joe across the glowing tip of a mangled cigar and said, “I checked that claim of yours, that you put in a couple years as a dogface in the war, kid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Three years,” Joe said. “Not a couple. I was at the Normandy beachhead, and in the Bulge, and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And in a psycho ward for a couple months, after, accordin’ to my information,” the chief said. He scowled at Joe, obviously still not liking what he saw, still disapproving the way Joe earned his living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe you’re havin’ a relapse,” he suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tell you, the guy means to kill me,” Joe said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Sure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw his face. He’s a dead ringer for me, Chief. I’m sure of it, even if he did have on those cheaters. Are you such a knucklehead that you can’t see why he’s scared?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kid,” growled the chief, big shoulders bunching up within the confining blue uniform coat, “you better go easy. You ain’t that big a shot yet, you can talk to me that way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Joe said wearily, “suppose I was a big shot. Like say, Sinatra. A big enough shot so that everybody, well, practically everybody, knew what I look like. And this guy happens to be a dead ringer for me. So what happens, the next time he tries to pull off a job, Chief?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Somebody gets a good look at him. Ordinarily they couldn’t describe him, except in a general way. But this time—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’d say,” cut in the chief, “he looks just like Buddy Burton, the famous crooner on TV and in the movies. Is that what you’re selling me, kid?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s what I’m selling. A couple more months on TV and I’ll be fingering this guy. And he knows it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief stared ruminatively at him through a cloud of cigar smoke. “This is like something out of a crummy paper-back, cops-and-robbers story. Go back and tell your friend Gittman, or whoever dreamed up this one, that I ain’t buying. I still ain’t handing you any free publicity, kid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is on the level,” Joe protested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, sure,” the chief scoffed. “Go on. Get outta here, kid. You told your story. I listened, but only because I’m paid to listen to stories. But I ain’t paid to believe ‘em. And I still don’t like crooners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I want a police guard when I put my next TV show on,” Joe said insistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You want publicity, kid. Go buy yourself some. You’re makin’ money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief sat there, grinning impudently at him, still mangling the fat stogie between his wide lips. Joe threw up his shoulders in a tired gesture, and walked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-show-must-go-on&quot;&gt;The Show Must Go On&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hadn’t told Marie anything, but she noticed. That tension was in him, working away all the time, making its presence felt in small signs that reached the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Joe what’s wrong?” she said. “What’s the matter?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Joe, were you threatened again? Did that man—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Honey, everything’s all right. Honest. Now, don’t you worry your pretty little head over nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got his gun out of mothballs, the one he’d picked up on the other side, during his Army service, and he took it down to the studio, had it in his coat pocket as he rehearsed the new show for that evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He ate his light dinner in the luncheonette down on the street level, with Alec Thornbush. He kept looking around, as he nibbled at the food, and Alec said shrewdly, “What’s eating you, pal? What’s with this hunted man act?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I dunno. Working too hard, I guess. Just nerves, Alec”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That satisfied Alec They got up and Alec picked up the check for both of them, and walked toward the cashier’s cage with it Joe tarried to leave a tip, got up, and almost bumped into a man with a bat pulled down over his forehead, wearing glasses, a man who bore a striking resemblance to Buddy Burton, of TV fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello,” Joe said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get sick,” the man suggested. “Throw up or something. Don’t go on tonight, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m show folk. There’s a tradition. The show must go on,” Joe said slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll stick around,” the man said. “I’ll be right here, in the building. I guess you know how things stand, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who was that?” Alec asked, as Joe joined him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just a guy, Alec.” Joe glanced at his watch. “Getting toward show time. Let’s get up there”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock in the studio said a quarter of the hour. Joe Caterisano, or Buddy Burton, faced the TV cameras and exchanged a few lines of banter with the announcer, Ben Barlow, and with Kitty Anderson, his feminine guest star. He sang a song and the studio audience, the far greater audience watching his image on TV sets throughout the city, noticed a strangeness in his manner as he sang this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was obviously tense. His gestures were jerky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the big red hand moved past the hour and the fifteen-minute show was over, Joe suddenly turned to Ben Barlow, and snapped, “You think you’re pretty smart, don’t you Ben?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The portly announcer stared at him. “What’s the matter with you, kid? Are you nuts?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You loused me up on my lines,” Joe gritted at the startled announcer. I’m wise to you, Ben. Tryin’ to make me look bad. I’m onto your game. You never did like me, did you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kid,” Ben Barlow said smoothly, trying to put a pudgy hand across Joe’s shoulders and steer him off stage, away from the startled eyes of the studio audience, “you’re kind of mixed up. You—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take your hands off me!” Joe said. He had the gun out of his pocket. “I don’t like you either, Ben. You know why?” he said, pointing the gun right at the popeyed announcer. “You look like a Kraut. That’s what you look like to me, a Kraut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kid, kid,” Barlow said weakly. “Take it easy. You’re upset. You—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up,” Joe said. He heard stealthy footsteps behind him and wheeled to see Alec Thornbush sneaking up on him. “Back off,” Joe grated, “before I have to plug somebody with this thing. It’s been a long time, but I guess I still have the knack of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alec Thornbush stood still, not breathing. He appeared to have lost all desire to play the hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;running&quot;&gt;Running&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe half-ran from the television stage, brandishing the gun with the air of a man who itched to kill somebody with it. He raced toward the hallway. The receptionist stared at him. She wore glasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, Mr. Burton—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Baby, give me those glasses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whatever—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The glasses, baby. The glasses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He let her see the gun. She seemed to freeze for a moment. Slowly, like a person confronting a deadly snake, she slipped the glasses off and handed them to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way out of the reception room he paused beside a coat-and-hat rack long enough to appropriate a tan coat and a tan hat to match it. He ran out into the hallway just as Jimmy stopped at that floor with the number five elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man started to step out, but backed up quickly, staring at the gun Joe brandished. Joe followed him into the elevator, pointed the gun at Jimmy, and said, “Take her down a floor or two, kid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” the kid gulped. “What kind of a gag is this, Mr. Burton? That thing looks real. Quit pointing it—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s go down a floor or two Jimmy. Nice and easy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You heard me all right, didn’t you, Jimmy?” Joe asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jimmy looked at the gun. Jimmy said, “Yes, sir. Okay, Mr. Burton. Down, nice and easy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look here,” snapped the man Joe had backed into the elevator, “you can’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a portly, red-faced man with an officious manner. Joe pointed the gun at him and said, “Shut up, please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man gulped. His mouth closed and he was sullenly silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop here, between floors,” Joe suggested. “We’ll sit awhile, Jimmy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Mr. Burton,” the kid said placatingly. He stopped and they stood quietly in the motionless elevator for perhaps three minutes. The portly man’s face grew increasingly sullen, but he didn’t say anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right,” Joe said. “Street level, Jimmy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid took him down. He walked out into the tiled corridor, with the glasses in place over his eyes, the hat brim turned down over his brow, the gun in his hand hidden under the topcoat he had borrowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-gun-in-his-hand&quot;&gt;A Gun In His Hand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man came over from the other side of the newsstand and stood nonchalantly beside him. Jimmy had hurriedly closed the door of the elevator behind Joe, taking his important passenger up where he’d intended to go in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man said, close to Joe’s ear, “Pal, you should’ve known better.” His voice was almost plaintive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s in my blood,” Joe said. “I just had to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the gag with the glasses? And that hat you’re wearing. It don’t even fit you, pal…Walk, friend. I’m focused on you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re taking a chance, aren’t you?” Joe stalled, and he was wondering how long it would take them to get here. A phone call from up above there shouldn’t take more than a matter of seconds, and the cops had radios in all their prowl cars, didn’t they? A guy gone berserk, with a gun in his hand, should rate faster action than he seemed to be getting. “You can’t get away with this,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Walk, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe I called in the cops. Maybe they’ve got the building staked out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Walk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe I don’t even walk. Then what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re makin’ me nervous, Caterisano. Walk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind them, an elevator’s doors opened, and passengers disgorged from it. “There he is,” somebody said, and some of the hardier souls edged carefully across the tiles toward Joe and his nameless companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Which one?” somebody was gasping. “Which one is Burton?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pal,” the man hissed at Joe’s ear, “you been up to something. I—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first cop came in then. He must have been an excitable rookie. He came barging in with his gun out, just asking for trouble from an armed man gone berserk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man at Joe’s side swore gutterally and shot through his coat pocket. The cop groaned and went down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe knew he was almost certainly next in line for it, and he acted upon instincts developed during his hitch in the Army. He shot the man, his gun still hidden under the topcoat draped over his right arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hit his man in the chest, mindful of the crowd in the corridor, of the very real danger to all those present. The man went down like a stone, coughing and gasping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe kicked the gun out of his fingers, dropped his own gun, and the tan coat he had used to conceal its presence, and lifted his hands high as more of the cops spilled into the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-10&quot;&gt;Chapter 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;thanks-for-the-publicity&quot;&gt;Thanks For The Publicity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right,” the chief said, disgruntled. “I guess I you an apology, kid. That dumb rookie, O’Hara, will live, and it could be he owes his life to you. The corpse could be your twin brother, so that proves you were telling me a straight story.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who was he?” Joe asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“John Davis,” the chief sighed. “Accordin’ to the identification card in his wallet. We got nothing in our records to tab him, and that checks with the story you said he told you. One of those smarties. A top operator, but working alone. I guess you did the public a service when you plugged him,” the chief admitted, somewhat grudgingly, it seemed to Joe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But did you have to be so melodramatic about it? Where was the need of staging that nut act, up in the studio?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wouldn’t listen to me,” Joe grinned. “I had to do something drastic. You put the bug in my bonnet, Chief. I really ought to thank you for that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t thank me for nothing,” the chief snapped. “I still don’t like crooners.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, thanks for the publicity, anyway,” Joe grinned. “I’ll get a big play from the papers, on this. And a sponsor, if I know the radio business. Be seeing you on your TV set, Chief.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned his back on the chief, who was muttering into the mangled stogie, and went out to his car. He drove pretty fast, on the way out to Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie would be waiting up, to hear all about it, and they always garbled things on those newscasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/youll-kill-the-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/youll-kill-the-people/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Bells</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-avenger&quot;&gt;The Avenger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At two bells The Boy determined to commit murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was no swift decision. On the night the Libertine lifted anchor at Melbourne—and Black Michael flogged him with a rawhide lash— the desire to slay had been impregnated in him, a terrible sore whose putrefying poison daily seeped into his blood and brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite suddenly, standing there in the shadow of the longboat, he perceived the death of his soul. Black Michael was responsible. He had inoculated him with a dreadful serum of evil that wiped out the germs of his strength; had proceeded, while he was in this weakened condition, to loot his being of all finer instincts. For that Black Michael must die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The avenger. That was his role. Tonight he would become the champion of his slain self and write in crimson the final chapter of a bitter story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he stood there on the deck, swaying with the drunken pitch of the two-masted, square-rigged vessel, it all came back to him—came back for the millionth time, with a burning sharpness that made him visualize, as though etched with steel upon his brain, the lamp-lit Australian water-front, the slinking shadows along the quay; made him feel, as if experiencing again, the sickening emotions following the blow and the return to consciousness in the hold of the trading brig bound for eleven degrees south of the equator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Til break you yet, boy—I’ll grind you under my feet—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was Black Michael’s threat when he sought to resist the big-fisted, rum-loving skipper. Then followed the first flogging, stripped and lashed to the beam. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recollection of it was gall in his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that life for him consisted chiefly of two things: the lash and rum —the whip to break his body, the liquor to break his brain. These were linked by labors so offensive, so repellent that he welcomed the hours of drunken sleep when for a brief while his senses were drowned in oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all this darkness there were two candles: the friendly attitude of the first mate and the queer companionship of the brig’s mascot, Kerachi, a Rajputana parrakeet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the vessel reached the white coral walls of Papeite, Black Michael demonstrated that he could keep a threat; The Boy was broken; the slender thread between strength and weakness snapped … like the string of a fine instrument struck by brutal hands; and when the Libertine cast moorings in the blue lagoon of the Tahitian capital he was still aboard, with a bruised body and a bruised mind, knowing in his tortured heart that some day, when the courage was given him, he would kill the master of the brig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Tahiti the ship passed through the coral traps of Les Isles Dangereux, sailed around the low archipelago into the phosphorescent waters of the Marquesas … to Havana; and there, in Atuona Valley, he received the gift of courage—from The White Lotus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three days ago—the one time he had gone ashore—he had seen her clinging to the doorframe of a thatched bamboo dwelling. “Old Babache’s kid … a leper,” he heard someone say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she had smiled at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hour after that, when the longboat was putting away from the beach, and the tawny maidens of Hiva-oa ran out waist-deep in the green bay to wave farewell, she was there, her gold hair falling like glinting fire about her pale, spray-dashed face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ia ora na i te Atiia. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Marquesan girls she sang that farewell—this White Lotus that he had found dying in the mulch of the South Seas. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sight of her was to him a light that pierced his poisoned, vapor-clung brain. And because he had seen her, this pallid leper-child, he knew that the hour had arrived when the master of the Libertine must pay the penalty for having murdered his soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet what would she think if she knew? But she would never know. Hiva-oa, dreaming its eternal dreams beneath the brooding thunders of Temetiu, had already slipped into the past—and in its dreams she lay, a part of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shuddered again. Yes, he would kill Black Michael. He was below in his bunk now—drunk, as usual. With the skipper gone, the first mate, Cardigan, would come into command—and then …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crept across the wet deck and down the companionway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A door in the rear of the lazarette, which was just off the main cabin, admitted him to a passage amidships, beneath the deck, leading forward to a space in the fo’castle where he and five others of the crew bunked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the bulkhead door he paused. A sooty slush-lamp, swung from the blackened beam, cast sluggish light upon six bunks arranged in double tiers along the bulkhead. It was a foul place, reeking of vile sea odors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the bunks were occupied. The lower tier of one supported the hulking body of a bullet-headed mulatto, clad only in short breeches, while above him lay the boatswain, a Creole from New Orleans. They were both asleep and breathing heavily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thrusting the weapon under his belt, he retraced his steps along the passage amidships and in the gloom of the main cabin groped toward Black Michael’s quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A terrible fear laid frigid fingers upon his heart as he reached the door. For a full minute he stood transfixed to the spot, his breath caught in his throat; then he grasped the knob, turned it and the door swung open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within, the closed porthole—a pale eye of dread—stared at him. The air was close—tainted with rum and human flesh. He listened for the sound of breathing, but only the monotonous murmur of the bilge water and the creak of straining timbers could be heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He drew the knife from beneath his belt—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leper child came to him then … a blinding flash of spiritual pallor, the shining recoil of his dead self that sprang through the darkness of his soul and smote him paralyzed for the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Black Michael must die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me reached the bunk; looked down upon the indistinct, sprawling figure. A wave of hysteria swept him, swamping his courage. He wanted to run, to throw himself upon his mattress and weep out the sorrows that twisted his heart. But—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… A swing of the blade, a sickening sound … and it was finished. He never released his grip on the hilt; held it as though it were a member of his own body; withdrew it and fell against the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some time he lay with his shoulders pressed to the panels, at bay, facing the specter of himself; but when at length the fear-paralysis released him, he burst out of the door, closed it, raced through the main cabin and up the companionway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air on deck seemed to lift from his brain the mantle of a loathsome vapor. Here in the tropic moisture of the night, where the wind swelled amongst the waving spars, his reason returned, swept over him like a cold and shuddersome flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glanced fore and aft. The decks were deserted but- for a lone figure on the poop deck. The watch—he could recognize him—a form planted as a piece of statuary upon the wheel-grating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He slunk past the forward hatch and climbed the ladder to the fore-poop. A stinging spray, flung over the bowsprit by a long gust of wind, struck his face sharply. It seemed to awaken him to the fact that he still gripped the knife, and with a shudder of repulsion he let it fall to the deck planks. For an instant he stood above it, looking as one fascinated upon the glinting thing; then he touched “it with his bare foot … shivered … and pushed it across the deck until it disappeared over the bow….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sobbing breath was drawn from his throat. He turned and fled down- deck—as one pursued by the horrors of the nethermost hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching his quarters he found the mulatto and the Creole still asleep; the slush-lamp hung from the blackened beam, swaying with the heave of the brig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A chill started him to trembling and he knelt beside his bunk, removing a flask from beneath the mattress. As he lifted it to his lips a sound behind him made him pause with it in mid-air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get below, you dirty lubbers! … Bahdsoodai! …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned his head sharply. Neither the mulatto nor the Creole had altered his position—but perched upon the beam was a feathery green body. His rigid muscles relaxed as he recognized Kerachi, his friend, the Rajputana parrakeet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He raised the flask to his mouth. The vile Tahitian rum was like vitriol, searing a path from his throat to the pit of his stomach. It choked him, but when he ceased coughing he took another gulp—another. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Step lively, lads! … Adrushtam! … Two bells, mate!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two bells. Those words startled him. That was just before he—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shuddered; swallowed quantities of the liquid fire; drained the bottle and fell with his face buried in the reek of the mattress. The flask slipped from his nerveless hand—struck the floor with a distant thud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“O, God—” he moaned. Hot tears burned his cheeks as he lay there sobbing in the awful abandonment of drunken grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All hands aft!” shrieked the parrakeet, then began to swear in Hindustani and Mandarin. That was the last thing he heard, the grotesque profanity of the little bird. Like a barque severed from its mooring-lines, his brain was carried downstream on the current of slumber….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His labored breathing had hardly joined that of the other occupants of the foul place when the big mulatto sat up cautiously, a stealthy, anticipatory smile spreading over his negroid features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rose, the movement bringing into visible play the thick, heavy-corded muscles beneath the bared brown skin; stood an instant looking up at the sleeping boatswain; crept across to The Boy’s bunk and slipped one hand under the mattress …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;dead-about-an-hour&quot;&gt;Dead About An Hour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sharp cutwater of the Libertine broke the phosphorus into javelins of green brilliancy, her yards, slightly checked, ran with easy motions beneath bellied topsail, while the deck-timbers creaked and groaned as the vessel wallowed in the heavy sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Cardigan, the first mate, standing alone at the wheel, firmly gripping the spokes at right angles, these sounds blended into a fierce, savage tune that vibrated responsive chords in his seaman’s being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since six bells he had been on watch, listening to the lawless song of the sea, and except on two occasions, when the cabin boy emerged from the main companion, the decks had been deserted during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At thought of The Boy, the first mate felt a tinge of sympathy. Poor chap. Only seventeen. And shanghaied—but, after all, life was a rather grim affair; it had been none too kind to him. He—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four bells jangled out. A moment afterward he saw the big body of Bjornsen, the second mate, emerge from the rear companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s the captain?” inquired Cardigan, as the Norwegian, a great hulk of sunburnt physical manCrook, reached his side and took the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A faint smile traced itself on the big blonde’s face. “Below in his quarters, I suppose, sir—with a belly full of rum …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan did not smile, merely nodded, saying, “Stearns will relieve you,” and moved down the ladder to the main companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching Black Michael’s door he entered without knocking. In the vague half-light supplied by the porthole he could make out the skipper’s huge body sprawled full length in the berth. The odor of rum was heavy on the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Captain!” he called, gripping one shoulder and shaking it. “Captain, wake up! … Hullo!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter exclamation was brought forth as his hand accidentally brushed the cheek of the recumbent man! It was cold, clammy. He quickly felt the heart. An oath left his tongue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He fumbled in the pocket of his pea-jacket and withdrew a box of matches. Igniting one he lit the slush-lamp and in the better light examined the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dead,” he muttered to himself with a semi-professional air. “Two incisions—one just below the heart, the other above. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Cardigan was not yet thirty-five, there were times when he seemed at least forty. This was such an occasion. About his lips was a grim tightness, a truculence that suggested inflexible metal beneath the bronzed exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Struck in the dark, I’ll wager,” he said to himself, running his fingers through his gray-shot hair whilst he continued his investigation. “Dead about an hour or I’m … And two distinctly different instruments, one a straight blade, the other curved.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one time he had studied surgery—in the days before the gray appeared in his hair. He … But that was an ancient story, a sheaf torn out of his life and laid away in a crevice of his memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first surprise caused by the discovery, he experienced a feeling that bordered on satisfaction. No love had ever existed between him and the master of the brig, and after The Boy was shanghaied at Melbourne there was open antagonism, a hostility that resulted in Cardigan’s decision to leave the Libertine at the end of the return voyage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Black Michael was dead, he mused, murdered—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this juncture his eyes, involuntarily lowered, were captured by a bright object on the floor. He stooped, picked it up and perceived that it was a small, curved blade—a murderous Malay knife that bore ugly stains. As he recognized it he felt a shock like nothing short of a volt of electricity— for the weapon was his own, a relic of the days before the gray appeared among his dark hairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a slim, dark-eyed Malay girl, down on the drowsy shores of the Archipelago where the restless surf drums to the tune of lawless love, and … But that, too, was an ancient tale, laid away in lavender with the other poignant recollections. She had given him the knife, this brown maiden, as she lay dying in his arms, and it was the only tangible remembrance of a still smouldering passion… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His face settled into sterner lines. This was undoubtedly the blade with which the incision was made. But how had it been obtained from his cabin and why was it used? The most logical answer for both was: treachery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His first impulse was to wipe the soiled blade upon his handkerchief, but he refrained, for Cardigan and discretion were synonymous. Bloodstains often proved incriminating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, innocent though he was, he decided, he dared leave no evidence where it might be discovered and used against him. This weapon was sufficient proof that he had an enemy aboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He first considered throwing the knife into the sea, but this proposed means of disposal he immediately dismissed; he would sooner separate himself from an arm than the weapon. He would hide it; there were many places on the ship where so small an object would never be found—and the place that appealed to him as one less frequented was the paint-locker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After covering the body with a sheet, he quitted the cabin, locked the door and made his way to the paint-locker. A moment later the Malay knife lay hidden behind a pile of cans and Cardigan went up on deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An impalpable mist was drifting in from the dark waste of waters, smoothing out the sharp lines of the Libertine and giving to her the look of a phantom craft as she rode the steadily increasing swell, her lights burning hazily, like nebula-belted planets in the fog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the forward hatch Cardigan encountered Stearns, the midshipman, a sallow youth of twenty-one or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go below and send the hands aft, Mr. Stearns,” the mate ordered, “every man Jack of them… Then he moved to the poop-deck where Bjornsen stood as one petrified at the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bjornsen,” he began, “the captain has been murdered, stabbed twice. I have sent for the crew to notify them. I’m in command now and I want your hearty support.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Norwegian nodded, his stolid face unaltered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five minutes later the crew was assembled below the poop, a nervous, shuffling crowd, looking up with uneasy eyes at the first mate. Scum of the Fast and West they were, washed together on the tides of the Seven Seas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are they all here, Mr. Steams?” inquired Cardigan of the midshipman, who was climbing to the poop-deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All but the cabin boy, sir; he’s down in the fo’c’s’le drunk as—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll see him later,” interposed the first mate. Then he cupped his hands about his mouth to make himself heard about the wind and sea. “Men, I’ll be brief. A crime has been committed aboard this brig. Just before six bells I was in the skipper’s quarters—and when I returned a few minutes ago I found him dead—murdered.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He paused to observe the effect of this announcement upon the men. Rows of sullen eyes looked up at him—eyes in which there were mingled fear and questioning. What a ghastly lot they looked, huddled there in the mist, thought Cardigan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of you”—he made a sweeping gesture with his bronzed hand—“one of you killed him. And I’ve called you here to ask if the guilty man is willing to confess and thus lighten his punishment, or, in the event a confession isn’t forthcoming, if anyone knows anything that might be instrumental in locating the murderer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long silence England Charlie, third mate, a big, gaunt cockney, with a red face and red hands, spoke up: “You said one o’ us wus th’ murderer, sir, but ’ow d’ we know you didn’t croak ’im?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this there was a murmur from the men. Encouraged, the cockney continued. “You’d be th’ one to benefit by ’is snuffin’ it—an Hi arsks, ’ow d’ zve know you didn’t send ’im orf?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan met his gaze coolly and smiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re justified in saying that,” he admitted. “But I was at the wheel from six bells to four bells—and if any man aboard understands post mortem conditions he can examine the body and see that the skipper has been dead just about an hour—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you could ’ave lashed th’ wheel,” persisted English Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan’s jaw shot forward at an ugly angle. “Are you trying to accuse me, Charlie?” he demanded. There came no reply and he went on, “More than ever I’m determined to leave nothing undone to find the man who killed the captain—and as a first step every one shall submit to a search for evidence—now. I’m in command here and I intend to assert my authority. Sykes, you and Stearns help me. Meanwhile, no one will leave the deck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cardigan started to descend the ladder he heard a savage oath, and, pausing, fastened his eyes upon the men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did someone speak?” he rapped. Ladd, a seaman, answered—“Jim Hickey here said he’d be damned if he was searched—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s a lie, sir!” broke in the bullet-headed mulatto, the great muscles in his arms standing out like whipcords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan moved down and confronted the mulatto. “Did you say that?” The boatswain, a Creole, stepped forward. “Eet ees so, m’sieur; I, ‘Poleon Moncrief, hear’ heem. W’at ees more” —he cast a malicious glance at the mulatto, who stood with clinched fists, glaring at him—“I know w’y zat nigger he not want to be search’. I was een my bunk trying to go to sleep w’en ze cabanne boy he come below an’ drink a dam’ lot of rum. An’ w’en ze boy he fall asleep zat nigger he sink I not ’wake an’ get up an’ go to ze bunk of ze cabanne boy an’—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blasphemous oath left the mulatto’s thick lips. He made a move to spring at the Creole, but Cardigan placed himself between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“—He steal ze cabanne boy’s pay. I saw heem take eet from under ze mattress. An’ zat w’y he not want to be search’, m’sieur—because he know you fin’ too much money on heem.” Cardigan turned upon the huge, brown-skinned figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that the truth, Hickey? Aren’t you willing to be searched?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mulatto glared at ’Poleon Moncrief, spitting out a stream of vile oaths. “It’s a lie, sir; a damned, stinkin’ lie—made up by that—!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a quick, stealthy movement the Creole leaped around Cardigan and flung himself at the mulatto’s throat. Together they went to the deck, rolling upon the moist timbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cardigan stooped to separate them the mulatto freed himself by a sudden wrench and gained his feet, dashing along the deck toward the forward companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mate started in pursuit, but halted as his eyes fell upon a belaying pin that lay upon the deck not many feet away. Hastily arming himself with this formidable missile, he sent it spinning through the air after the fleeing figure. It caught the negro in the back of the skull; knocked him flat upon the deck planks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan, followed by several of the crew, reached his side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s out for some time,” reported the first mate, bending over him. “Two of you lads carry him below and lock him up— But wait!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He ran one hand into the rear pocket of the mulatto’s trousers, producing a black leather wallet. Opening it he withdrew a wad of bills, which he swiftly counted and returned to the wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He smiled grimly. “All right, men; below with him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-thing&quot;&gt;The Thing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the very midst of a dream The Boy was shot into consciousness. For a moment he could not remember where he was. He seemed to be caught in the teeth of a monster that shook him horribly, mercilessly. Half-remembered objects separated themselves from the chaos and he heard a distant voice pronouncing his name. Yet for some inexplicable reason he was unable to reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually he extracted himself from the teeth of the monster; gradually objects settled into their regular places. Above him was a familiar face. As he recognized it sleep dropped from him as though severed by a blade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get up,” he heard Cardigan say, while he shook him vigorously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy lurched to his feet. As he brushed one hand across his lips he inhaled his breath, an odor that sickened him. Invisible hands seemed to jerk aside a drowsy fabric, revealing in their biting sharpness the incidents before his drunken sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His soul shrank, dwindled with fear. Black Michael’s body had been found and the mate had come to accuse him—But how did he find out? The only incriminating evidence, the knife, had been thrown into the sea… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought you promised me never to do this again,” reproved Cardigan. “But we’ll discuss that later. Come with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy was dreadfully afraid. The blood pounded in his temples, beat so loudly that it seemed to boom out his guilt. God! How could he meet Cardigan’s honest gaze—knowing in his heart that he had wielded the knife that finished Black Michael?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some manner—he knew not how—he forced himself to follow the mate along the passage amidships and when they reached the cabin his fear increased to a panic as he perceived that Cardigan was making directly for Black Michael’s quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stood with a rapidly pounding heart behind the mate while he inserted a key in the lock and turned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within, the slush-lamp, turned low, threw quivering shadows upon the walls. The air was warm and unpleasantly heavy with the smell of stale rum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there in the bunk it lay, covered with a sheet—The Thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan closed the door and turned the lamp higher. Mercy of God, thought The Boy, was he going to draw aside that sheet and …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boy,” commenced the man, halting beside the bunk. “I brought you here to show you this.” And he turned back the sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something worse than horror reached up and clutched at The Boy’s throat. He half closed his eyes; dared not shut them entirely, for The Thing fascinated him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The captain has been murdered,” Cardigan continued. “A few minutes ago I happened on the fore-poop. I dropped a wallet and it fell overside— but fortunately caught in the projecting space under the bowsprit. And when I picked it up I found this with it—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He withdrew an object from the pocket of his pea-jacket. A cry leaped to The Boy’s lips—died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There before him, sharp and ugly in the flickering glow of the slush-lamp, was the knife with which he killed Black Michael!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now come here,” commanded the mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He obeyed, the cabin reeling dizzily about him. What use was there of trying to hide the truth now? Cardigan knew and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look,” was the sharp injunction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he looked … at The Thing on the bunk. As he saw the exposed chest a shriek of sheer terror was wrung from his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, no!” he cried. “I didn’t stab him twice—I didn’t! Only once, in the dark … and then I ran—” He shuddered. “O, God, what have I said?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a broken sob he sank to his knees, burying his face in his hands&amp;lt; An instant later fingers closed over his shoulders and lifted him to his feet— fingers that were not rough but firm and determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said what I wanted to hear,” announced Cardigan. “Look at me, boy… . There … Now, I’m going to question you and I want the truth, the truth—before the God that you just called on… . When did you stab Black Michael?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A little after two bells, sir—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why? Because he had mistreated you? … How did you do it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I …” And there followed a stumbling, detached account of his movements from the time he left the deck until he surrendered to sleep in his bunk in the fo’castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s fortunate for you that I found the knife,” remarked Cardigan when he had finished, “for it has your initials upon the hilt. I saw you come on deck twice while I was at the wheel; one time you went near the bowsprit but not until after I found the knife did I attach any importance to it.” He paused, resuming after a moment. “It’s quite evident that two people stabbed the captain—you and an unknown person. But who stabbed him first? Who is the real murderer? These are skeins that must be untangled. All I require of you is a close mouth and an open&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then—then you’re not going to lock me in the brig?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are free: only remember my instructions—and regard them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy stared at him. He was dazed, stunned. Instead of a blow he had received kindness. Kindness. New and loftier emotions stirred within him; he tried to speak, to utter words that would convey his gratitude to the mate; he could only stand and stare mutely. Nor was that dumb look, mirroring his deepest and most profound emotions, unobserved by Cardigan; it came to him as an illuminating signal-flash from The Boy’s soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now run along,” he said, not unkindly, opening the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In silence The Boy passed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he moved through the cabin, which was faintly lit by a hanging lamp, his brain groped in a labyrinth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some one else had sought to end Black Michael. Who was the owner of this other hand that had driven a blade into the skipper’s breast? And which of the two had accomplished his purpose, he or the unknown person?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his agony he prayed that it was the other, for though a short while ago The White Lotus had seemed a lamp that lighted the way to this ghastly action, he now saw, with the cold clearness of returned sanity, that with blood upon his soul he was severed from even spiritual companionship with this pallid leper-child who had impressed herself so deeply upon his memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how could he ever find out? It all seemed very hopeless… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he neared the fo’castle he saw a vertical strip of yellow light cleaving the dark passage from the bulkhead door. Voices within were murmuring in hushed conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was almost in the opening when a sentence, flung against his ears with the sting of a whip, cemented him to the spot: “I only struck once, I tell you, once—yet there are two wounds. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those words, spoken in a voice that was lowered to a tone just above a whisper, yet strangely familiar, brought forth his breath in a gasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crept nearer the source of light; peered within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slush-lamp was turned low, casting flickering shadows as it swung with the motion of’ the brig. Five of the bunks were vacant; the sixth, near another bulkhead-door, opposite The Boy, was occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moncrief, the Creole, sat on the edge of the bunk, a cigarette between his thin, moist lips, and at his side, face and shoulders hidden by the boatswain’s slender body, was another man. That bunk was used by the Chinese cook, The Boy knew, yet the one who lay there was not the Oriental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were talking again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By gar, eet ees ghastly, m’sieur,” commented Moncrief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes—a ghastly failure,” spat out the other. “’Poleon”—a note of intensity came into the voice—“I see but one thing to do now. By four in the morning we should be near the coral reefs—they’re just a mile off course. Wajo, the Polynesian, will be at the wheel; we can overpower him—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sacre dam, m’sieur!” broke in the boatswain. “Do zat—zat?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why not? To reach Tahiti means investigation by the authorities. If the brig goes down she carries all evidence with her. We can escape in the longboat; islands are numerous along here—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But, m’sieur, ze knife of ze first mate zat you lef’ in ze—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“God knows what became of it! When he found the body he must have hidden the damned thing—and if I knew where … But no; I’m afraid to try it now. The second wound is what has scared me off; it’s a sign to warn us.” Then he swore a volley of oaths so vile that they burned The Boy’s ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With the captain killed,” went on the voice, after a moment^ “and the first mate disposed of by the incriminating evidence, we could have easily bought the crew over to us. With me in command we could have gone straight to Melbourne for the cargo of rum. McAllister would have paid well when we delivered it to him at Hiva-oa, for when his cursed natives have plenty of rum they do more work—and since the French government has restricted the— Oh, well, what’s the use to talk of it? You got the best of the deal; I had the dirty work of killing the swine. It was too big an undertaking for two men to try——”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But, m’sieur—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, ’Poleon; the only thing to do now is save ourselves. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pregnant dread was spreading through The Boy’s body, a sensation of abysmal emptiness. The coral reefs; the Polynesian. Then they intended to—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he could learn who stabbed Black Michael first! But did he want to know? Yes, the truth was far better than horrible uncertainty. Yet he dared not enter the fo’castle alone; he must go and bring Cardigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he turned to creep away a sudden plunge of the vessel sent him flat upon the deck of the passage with a sound that seemed loud enough to be heard from stem to stern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was almost on his feet when a lean figure appeared in the bulkhead door. Instantly he recognized Moncrief. He made a dive toward the lazarette, but the boatswain was too quick for him; he flung his lithe body upon him and bore him to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy opened his lips to cry out and the Creole’s fist descended upon his mouth. The pain stung him to action. With a desperate wrench he freed himself and fell against the bulkhead, but before he could move a second figure was momentarily silhouetted upon the light in the oblong aperture—a figure that hurled itself upon him, pinning him to the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again he tried to scream—again a fist bruised his lips horribly. He felt blood dripping from his chin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, don’t—” he cried, his mouth throbbing with pain. Something crashed down upon his skull and as he fell, plunging into what seemed a depthless abyss, a picture was photographed upon his brain—that of a dark, sinister figure silhouetted upon the glow in the bulkhead door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the world reeled, a drunken universe—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;off-the-course&quot;&gt;Off The Course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A knock on the door of his quarters brought Cardigan out of a light sleep. Sitting up on the edge of his bunk he called, “Come in!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening of the door admitted a wavering blade of light and in the frame, outlined upon the pale illumination from the main cabin, was a form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s Stearns, sir,” announced the man. “I’m sorry to wake you up, but I have something queer to report.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan rose. “Wait a second till I make a light.” Then a moment later when the slush-lamp cast its ill light upon his nearly-clad form he added, “All right, Stearns, what is it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The midshipman’s sallow face seemed paler than ever; he shifted uneasily from one foot to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve seen something that I don’t quite understand, sir,” he began. “I had just been relieved by Wajo and was going toward the fo’castle when I happened to glance athwart the brig. I saw what looked like two shadows; then I realized they weren’t shadows but men—two of them, moving along the port deck. They disappeared behind the after-cabin as soon as I saw them, but I got the impression that they were carrying something—or—or someone. A minute later I could have sworn I heard a cry. It scared me a little, sir, after all that’s happened on this brig, so I hurried down in the fo’c’s’le. I didn’t know what to do— and after about an hour I decided to tell you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you did right,” commended Cardigan—for while the midshipman was telling his story something insidious had taken root in his brain, an alarming possibility that caused him no little apprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m going on deck,” he announced, removing his pea-jacket and cap from a peg on the wall. “Return to your quarters and say nothing to the men of what you’ve seen. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He followed Stearns into the poorly- lighted main cabin, and as the midshipman reached the top of the companion- way, gripping the brass rail to keep from being hurled back by the dangerous roll of the vessel, the mate moved through the lazarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midway in the dark passage leading into the fo’castle he collided with something that sprang away from him and swore lurid oaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who’s that?” demanded Cardigan. “Hinglish Charlie. ’Oo th’ blurry ’ell’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The first mate. Is the cabin boy in the fo’c’s’le?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, sir; Hi ayn’t seen ’im this evenin’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, help me look for him. You start at the bow and I’ll go aft.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together they passed through the main cabin and at the top of the companionway staggered out upon the deck, gripping the wet lee rail. Here they separated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blanket of fog had been dropped from the dark sky and the peak-gutters snarled and roared as the heavy sea, dashed inboard, was sucked back again to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clinging to the drenched rail the mate moved aft. Near the long-boat amidships, a human form darted suddenly around the corner of the aftercabin and ran into him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan was thrown roughly against the rail, and as he gained his balance the figure, head down, lurched past him toward the main companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who’s that?” he bellowed, hollowing his hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For answer the figure plunged on; gained the companion; vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan swore savagely. Moving across the slippery timbers, he reached the companionway and descended. Below, in the main cabin, the door of the lazarette gaped at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With quick strides he made his way toward the fo’castle. The passage was not dark this time, for during the interval that he was on deck a light had been made in the crew’s quarters and it sent a pale, trembling shaft through the bulkhead door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the entrance to the fo’castle Cardigan halted, an exclamation on his lips—for he stood face to face with English Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How the devil did you get here?” he demanded suspiciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cockney indicated the entrance opposite the bulkhead door, through which opening the bottom of a flight of stairs was visible. “I came down the steps, sir. I just stopped a minute to make a light ’ere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought I sent you to find the cabin boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You did, sir—but Hi ayn’t found ’im yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan whirled about and at that moment a voice behind him shrieked: “Two bells, mate—two bells. …” The sound brought him around again and the cockney, grinning, pointed to a feathery green body perched on the upper tier of one of the bunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan swore as he made his way alone to the main cabin. Damn him, who was this fellow who had slunk past him on deck?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the lazarette door he paused to consult his watch. Ten minutes to four. From the timepiece his eyes rose to the compass in the deck-beam overhead. He could distinguish the tiny figures on the white disc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good God!” sprang from his lips. Who was on watch? Wajo—and the fool was headed off the course … toward where the coral traps lay—“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took a step to cross the main cabin and at that very instant—so exact is the time-table of Fate—a sudden titanic shock hurled him flat upon his back. The fall partially stunned him, and as he lay there trying to marshal his scattered faculties the bow of the vessel seemed to leap up, rolling him against the cabin bulkhead. Following that loose objects tumbled down; glass shattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a moment of struggle, Cardigan succeeded in getting to his feet. Finding himself in darkness, he realized that the lamp had been broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A splotch of misty light showed him the companionway, and, slipping and stumbling across the slanting floor, he groped his way to the foot of the stairs, where his outstretched hands found the brass rail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He ascended. On deck charging billows broke in white foam over the gunwale, sweeping angrily against the cabins and masthead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed a deathless period to Cardigan before he reached the break of the poop; here he gripped the ladder and looked over his shoulder at the wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bow was thrust up into the throat of the fog, the stern so deeply sunk that the main-chains dipped, while a list to the port permitted the sea free entrance through a tear in the bulwarks. She had evidently struck with tremendous force; the forward mast was down and the deck, below the fore-poop, in splinters, where broken spars had crashed through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grasped the situation instantly, realizing the urgency of keeping a cool head. The bows were jammed between the rocks and at any moment the wounded ship might slide back off the reefs—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His teeth snapped shut and he climbed the ladder. As he stood upright on the poop-deck, peering into the mist that masked the remote end of the vessel, a vague shape slid across the timbels at him. Instantly he saw that it was a man and tried to steady himself for the encounter that he knew was unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of the jar that he expected, a smashing blow was delivered full in his face, and with mingled surprise and pain he realized that it was an attack rather than a collision. The moment he hit the deck he was up again, sending his fist into a yielding paunch. The figure went down without a cry, doubled in a knot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment Cardigan stood above his antagonist, waiting for him to rise; then, believing him rendered breathless by the blow, he bent over to ascertain the identity. He had no sooner abandoned his guard than he regretted it, for the knotted form straightened out and sprang at him—but not too swiftly for him to see the swarthy face of ’Poleon Moncrief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’re the traitor aboard!” bellowed Cardigan. “You killed—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more they came together. This time they clinched; went to the slanting deck, rolling over and over until they struck the rail, where the force of the impact separated them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaping to his feet, Cardigan stood ready, and when the boatswain rose a well-aimed blow between the eyes sent him reeling against the gunwale. He crumpled up. The first mate bent swiftly and gripped him about the waist; lifted him and hurled him, clawing and kicking, overboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the body of Moncrief was swallowed by the fog Cardigan staggered back against the wheel. His heel encountered an object, and looking down he saw the Polynesian, Wajo, stretched out beside the wheel-grating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He dropped on his knees to examine the body, and at this juncture someone scrambled over the break of the poop, looming tall and sinister in the mist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Cardigan?” The voice belonged to Stearns. “The whole bow’s smashed—clear to the main hatch! Who in the name of—” He stopped as a roll of the vessel sent him sliding across the wet deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Grip yourself, man!” cried Cardigan, rising and moving to his side. ‘‘Remember, you’re midshipman on this brig! … Let’s make for the longboat. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mate led the way from the poop to the long-boat, where a group of men, smears of dark animation in the fog, were struggling at the davits. English Charlie’s voice rose above the clamor as he sang out orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you find the cabin-boy, Charlie?” * asked Cardigan, reaching the cockney, who stood with a dripping tarpaulin thrown over his shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, sir—an’ Hi looked from bow to stern!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor beggar, thought Cardigan. His fears were confirmed. The two figures Stearns had seen in the mist loomed as sinister elements in the fate of the cabin-boy; the cry seemed conclusive evidence that evil had befallen him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gripped himself and ordered: “Charlie, send two men below to fetch provisions and blankets—and have them step lively!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As two of the crew disappeared in the fog, headed for the companion, English Charlie drew himself into the life-boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everything in shape?” queried Cardigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aye, aye, sir! Oars, mast, canvas and water!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is the rudder shipped properly? … Here come the provisions. In with them, men… . Get the lines clear and the boat ready to swing! One of you tail on the falls! … Lower slowly—slowly or you’ll swamp her! Stand by, lads! Now, ease off—ease off!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaning over the slanting rail Cardigan saw the dark shape of the boat plunge downward, saw it strike the sea and ride free of the hull, borne on a white surge. How small, how helpless it looked, down there in the mist, thought Cardigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are all hands there?” he called, as the last man shot down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All but the men for’ard, sir,” answered a voice from the misty smudge below. “They didn’t have a chance when she struck. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan, preparing to swing down the line, felt a peculiar reluctance to abandon the brig. Suppose, after all, the cabin-boy was somewhere—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thought sped like steel through his brain. The Malay knife. He was leaving that behind. Queer that one should suddenly remember a fragment of sentiment amid such chaos—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lay her nose close in, lads!” he ordered over the rail. “I’m going to have a look below. If I’m not back in four minutes don’t wait. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He made his way to the companion, climbing down the almost inverted stairs into the main cabin, where the water reached his waist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusting more to his sense of direction than his outstretched hands, he groped his way aft, beneath the decks, to the paint-locker. In the misty ghost- light that spilled through the nearly demolished deck above he found the nail- riven iron door and drew back the bolt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a shriek of hinges it swung out —spitting a large object in the waist- deep flood. Cardigan swore aloud as he perceived it to be a human body; bent over; lifted it; cursed again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the cabin-boy—bound and gagged!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the half-light he could see the mutely imploring eyes—dark pools of pain. With haste he secured the Malay knife and severed the bonds, afterward removing the gag from the bruised, swollen mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… God, sir,” burst out The Boy, “they knocked me in the head, ’Poleon Moncrief and another … I couldn’t see his face, but he said—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell me later,” cut in Cardigan. “We haven’t time now; the ship’s sinking… . Can you walk? … I’ll help you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mate half-dragged The Boy along the passage and into the main cabin; here he set him on his feet and thrust him toward the vague gray light in the companionway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As The Boy began the ascent, clinging to the rail, he heard a crash behind him, a ripping and splintering of broken timbers, and, looking back, he saw something long and dark, the shape of a spar, plunge from aloft and smite Cardigan on the head. With a splash the first mate sank beneath the ugly water in the cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy shrieked. For an instant he stood motionless, paralyzed, then stumbling down the stairs he groped in the flood for the body. Almost instantly he was rewarded. With trembling fingers he sought the heart. It was beating. He laughed hysterically and began to drag the limp form after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midway up the companion-stairs he was brought to a standstill by a sound below, a half croak and half shriek: “On deck, you lubbers! … Sahibhai! …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He understood. Kerachi, the parrakeet, was down there in that black hole—but he could not go back until he had carried Cardigan to safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A form suddenly blotted out the square of foggy gray light that defined the companion. Following that English Charlie’s voice called, “Mr. Cardigan!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here!” answered The Boy. “For God’s sake take him! He was hit by a spar! … I’ve got to go back—after the parrakeet!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he turned to descend the cockney gripped his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come back, yeh blarste’d little fool! You’ll be drowned—” But The Boy broke away and plunged down into the cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hush that seemed intensified rather than ruptured by the dull, ominous pounding of the waves against the sodden hull brooded in the bowels of the vessel—as if the very timbers of the stricken brig were smitten dumb with dreadful expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It corrupted The Boy with terror, this hush, but he forced himself to stagger through the water into the flooded passage amidships. Ahead, the bulkhead door hiccoughed yellow light. It gave warmth to his chilled soul, and in another instant he reached the entrance to the fo’castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slush-lamp lay against the beam, spluttering feebly with every heave of the vessel. The foul hole was half-inundated and a great wound in the port bulwarks bled a steady stream of sea water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kerachi!” called The Boy, searching in the flood for the little bird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if answering him, the parrakeet, perched upon the top of the furthest bunk, croaked: ”Chota hasri, sahibs…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a thing occurred that drew The Boy’s heart into his throat: a human hand rose suddenly from behind an overturned table that floated near the second bulkhead door … clawed at the air … sank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Help … pleaded a faint voice. “A spar … pinned me here … in the passage door… . I’m killed unless. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blood in The Boy’s veins seemed for the moment sucked up. The voice! Pain had weakened it to scarcely above a whisper, but he recognized it, this voice that he would remember until Death wiped free his brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m coming!” he answered, suffused With fright and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he moved forward a sudden lurch of the brig sent the lamp crashing against the bulkhead. He stumbled; clutched at something tangible; clung. With a sense of aching despair he realized that he was denied the sight of—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darkness had hardly shut its jaws upon the foul hole when the parrakeet shrieked: “Two bells, mate, two bells … “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An instant of frightful silence came on the heels of the bird’s speech, then: “God, how did you know?” shrilled the voice. “That was when I stabbed him. … As I pulled the knife out two bells struck… . ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boy felt a sudden quiver of the planks beneath his feet, heard a ripping sound forward … and a sudden convulsion of the water flung him backward. Terrified, he regained his balance and groped until he found and pulled himself through the bulkhead- door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How he made the main cabin he never knew. After a period of breathless struggle, bruised and hurt, almost strangled by the deepening flood, he reached the foot of the now inverted companion-stairs and began to climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was almost at the top when a great wave, hurled through the companion above, descended upon him and bore him, gasping and choking, into the liquid blackness below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world swung around in giddy chaos. He experienced a terrible plunging sensation; torrents of delirious water passed over him; pitiless night swirled its black currents about his struggling body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buoying himself upward, battling against the legions of water, he strove to attain the surface. His thrashing arms struck something hard. At the contact his body went rigid with horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ceiling of the cabin. Trapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fierce exultation possessed him— the glory of struggle. He tried to fight, but the liquid death crushed him. He screamed—was choked. He knew the torture of suffocation, a seemingly endless period of terror and pain such as he had never known, even when the lash of Black Michael curled about his bare skin; and a vivid, blinding flash of the concentrated events of many years leaped like hundred-hued lightnings athwart his drowning eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of this glow, surrounded by tiny reeling stars, he saw The White Lotus … burning with the fire of palest moons—a figure that faded, became as destroyed moonlight, a vanishing glory that perished the very instant that it flashed to light his way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“la ora na i te Atna …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark sluicegates closed upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;do-dead-men-laugh&quot;&gt;Do Dead Men Laugh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“’Ere she goes, mateys—look!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first thing that Cardigan heard, a sentence that clove the fabric of unconsciousness and left him lying, pained to the soul, in what seemed a vast, misty cavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt intermittent sprays upon his face and tried to struggle to a sitting position, but an intense burning in his skull made him fall back. He opened his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Charlie … where are you ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An instant afterward a huge face, seeming wraithlike in the fog, materialized in the dusky vacancy above him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She’s just gone down, sir!” the third mate said in a husky voice. “Gawd, it was orful … with the little fool aboard—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You mean—?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yerss. ’E dragged you up the companionway and Hi ’elped lower you into the long-boat. … We’d ’ardly got away, sir, when she went back orf the rocks … straight down.” He paused, then: “Shall Hi call the roll, sir?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan shuddered involuntarily. “Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He saw English Charlie rise; his head was lost in the mist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Watkins!” began the Britisher. “Here!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sykes … Ladd	… Cheng Su … Olsen … Huldricksson … Hickey—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The nigger was locked in the brig,” put in a voice from the rear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stearns!” went on the cockney. “Moncrief—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He went overboard. …” This from Cardigan in a half-whisper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, “Bjornsen. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Bjornsen did not answer. Nor could anyone account for the big Norwegian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardigan went to his grave wondering who had struck Black Michael first, ’Poleon Moncrief or The Boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And perhaps the spirit of Bjornsen, knowing this and possessing a grim sense of humor, chuckled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But do dead men laugh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/two-bells/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/two-bells/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ironclad Alibi</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;breakin-out&quot;&gt;Breakin’ Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Ryan tossed aside the magazine he’d been reading by the dingy light of a bulb overhead. But he didn’t get up from the cot, as Sheriff Capehart came along the shadowy corridor that led back to the cellblock. Nick was a slim, dark young man with sly features. He was openly contemptuous of everybody in his hometown of Piney Point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheriff Capehart, a heavy, middle-aged man with phlegmatic grey eyes, came up close to the bars and stood looking at Nick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grinning slyly, Nick asked, “You come to turn me loose, sheriff?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I didn’t,” grunted the sheriff. “I came to ask if you want to confess killin’ my brother Sam before I go to bed.” “Surely you don’t think I’d kill anybody!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I sure do! You hid in Sam’s hardware and jewelry store until after he’d closed and was working on his books. You made him open his safe, cleaned out from it all the watches and rings and money and suchlike, then you killed him. You killed him, because he knew who you were.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick looked grieved. “Sheriff, you make me feel bad. Here I am, a hometown boy who went off to the big city and made good. Then, when I come back to visit my poor old father, you throw me in the clink and accuse me of murder. Why, you knew me when I was a kid—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s just it—a thievin’, window breaking alley rat! And I’ve heard a lot of worse things about you since you went off to Pittsfield. Mixed up with Sledge Mangrum’s bunch up there, ain’t you? And you didn’t come home on a visit— you come to rob somebody!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What makes you think I killed Sam Capehart?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because you’d been hangin’ about his store for the last couple of days. You were seen to go into the store just a little while before he closed the day he was killed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I went out again by the back door. I could prove that by your brother Sam, if he wasn’t dead.” There was open mockery in Nick’s laugh. “Anyway, I’ve got an air-tight alibi. The night Sam Capehart was killed and robbed, I was at home all night. That’s a pretty hot alibi, ain’t it? My own father’s word?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheriff growled, “Tebe Ryan’s a lazy, booze-swillin’ thief and always was! He’d sooner lie than tell the truth.” /But it’d carry weight in court. Maybe I killed Sam Capehart. Sheriff, but you’ve got no proof and you know it. That lawyer I brought down from Pittsfield is pretty slick. He says that if you don’t produce some evidence, you can’t hold me any longer than tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheriff sighed. “Looks like he’s right. I know you killed poor Sam, but I can’t prove it. Reckon I’ll—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll stay still, if you want to live!” a cold voice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheriff Capehart turned and looked surprisedly at the two men who had stepped from the shadowy corridor behind him. One was chunky and dark, the other tall, with pale eyes and a hooked nose. They had wicked-looking automatics in their hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheriff said belligerently, “What’s this? What’re you two doin’ here? Don’t you know I’m the sheriff?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, we know it,” snapped the tall man. He shoved the sheriff back into the corridor. “Get up front, Fatty!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Ryan got up from the cot. He could see the two shoving Sheriff Capehart along the corridor. He heard the sheriff protest shrilly, “Hold on here! I’m the law—you can’t—” He saw the automatic in the tall man’s hand rise and fall, saw the sheriff wilt down to the floor and lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two came back to the cellblock. The tall man said, “Get the keys, Blackie.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark man took a ring holding several keys from a nail on the wall. He opened Nick’s cell door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right, Nick,” the pale-eyed man said coldly. “Get your hat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick was puzzled. He didn’t know these two. He backed to the cot and sat down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll sit this one out,” he said. “That dumb sheriff’s got nothin’ on me. I’ve got a hot alibi. I’d be a sap to break out of here, when I’ll be out legally in twenty- four hours anyway. I’m not goin’ anywhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s what you think, smart aleck!” The tall man slapped Nick, hard, caught him by the shoulder and flung him toward the cell door. “Step out, fast!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick didn’t argue any more. He didn’t know yet what cooked, but he knew that these two weren’t here as friends, as he had at first thought. The men with the guns were close behind him as he went along the corridor, stepped over the sheriff’s still form, went through the sheriff’s office at the front of the one-story brick building and onto the street. The street was deserted, for it was after midnight and only dimly lighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;settin-in&quot;&gt;Settin’ In&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dark sedan was drawn up at the curb half a block away. Blackie slid under the wheel, the tall man got in the back seat with Nick. The automatic was still in his hand. Blackie started the engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Which way, Jake?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Straight for Pittsfield,” Jake said. “We’re safe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sedan moved out of town and at a moderate speed northward along the highway. Nobody spoke for a couple of miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Nick said angrily, “Would you mind telling me what the hell this is all about?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sledge wants to see you,” Jake said briefly. “He heard you were in that hick jail. He sent us to get you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sledge Mangrum? What’s he want to see me about?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know what about. It was a crazy thing, Nick, killing Sledge’s kid brother Joe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Somebody’s crazy, all right! But if somebody killed Joe Mangrum, it wasn’t me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sledge thinks different. He knows you and Joe had some trouble over a chick, knows you threatened to kill the kid. So when Joe was found in a back room of Marty’s place with a blade in his gullet—with Marty swearing you and Joe had come in together—Sledge started looking for you. It gave me the creeps, hearing some of the things Sledge swore he’d do to yon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick was quiet a moment, feeling cold and leaden in his stomach. He wasn’t really on the inside of Sledge Mangrum’s gang, only on the fringe, because Sledge had turned thumbs down on him. He knew little about Big Sledge, but he’d heard things that made his insides curl up, about what Sledge did to those he didn’t like. He knew Sledge’s kid brother Joe, a wicked, strutting little rat. They’d fought over a girl one night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d heard that Sledge Mangrum loved only one thing on earth—that vicious, swaggering kid brother of his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Nick said. “When did Joe get it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Last Monday night, about midnight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then I can prove I didn’t do it. I was here, in Piney Point, last Monday midnight!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe. In a jail cell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, that wasn’t till Tuesday. I was—” Nick stopped. At midnight Monday he had been in Sam Capehart’s store. It was just about then that he’d killed a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tires whined on the pavement. The pines on each side of the highway were dark and still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blackie said over his shoulder, “Remember what Sledge done to Mack Parker the time Mack double-crossed him? Mack’s mind never was right after that. They had to put him away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick blurted, “Damn it, didn’t I say I didn’t kill Joe?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell that to Sledge,” Jake murmured. “But it’ll take more than just your word, or your old man’s, to make him believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What if I could prove I was two hundred miles from Pittsfield at midnight Monday?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’d be fine for you, but I don’t think you can.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, I can,” Nick said eagerly. “You know why I was in the can?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We know all about it. So what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know what time Sam Capehart was killed and robbed?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About midnight, they claim, on Monday—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was me that pulled that job! I couldn’t have done that, and killed Joe Mangrum in Pittsfield at the same time, could I?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blackie laughed. “No soap, Wick. We know that dumb sheriff just picked you up on suspicion. You didn’t croak old Capehart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I did, I tell you! If I showed you the loot—the watches and rings and stuff—that would prove it, wouldn’t it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake said slowly, “Nick, you’re a sneaky, blood-thirsty little rat. But you show me that and I’ll tell Sledge you didn’t kill Joe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick took a deep breath of relief. “A couple of miles ahead a gravel road turns off to the left into the woods. Follow it, and I’ll show you where the stuff is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five minutes later the sedan was bumping along a crooked, forest-hemmed side road. At a word from Nick, Blackie stopped the car at a narrow concrete bridge. Nick got out, followed by Jake with the gun, and went down into the dry creek bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black satchel was cunningly hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the road, in the glare from the car lights, Jake opened the satchel. It was crammed with glittering jewelry and money. Some of the price tags carried the name of Sam Capehart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That satisfy you?” Nick asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It sure does,” Jake said. But he didn’t put away his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headlights of a car approached swiftly along the old gravel road. The car stopped and a heavy figure got out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right, boys?” Sheriff Capehart asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, sheriff,” Jake said. “He’s your meat, well-done!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That coldness was in Nick Ryan’s stomach again. He knew suddenly that he’d been a sucker. He said furiously, “You double-crossin’ snakes! Joe Mangrum’s not dead! You two don’t belong to Sledge Mangrum’s gang!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did they tell you that?” The sheriff snapped a pair of handcuffs on Nick’s wrists. “Why, they’re just a couple of boys from over at Rockport that I got to help me. They wouldn’t hurt a grasshopper. It was a real hot alibi you had to prove you never killed my brother Sam, Nick. But not hot as the chair you’ll soon be settin’ in!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/the-ironclad-alibi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/the-ironclad-alibi/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Satan Hogs the Camera</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;horse-opera&quot;&gt;Horse Opera&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Carl Connor, K-T’s best director, was putting the finishing touches on the next take, my eyes wandered over the Hollywood studio lot. Over to the left were the red-tiled office buildings blistering and peeling under the torrid August sun. Lazy-looking employees wandered indifferently across the shaggy lawns. In fact, King-Tanger Studios seemed to have gone to the dogs in the three years I was away. Why, when Uncle King was alive—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Mister Kelley!” Connor snapped at me sarcastically. “Anytime you’re ready!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” I grinned. “Shoot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His sharp eyes, owlish under heavy glasses, pinned me down. “I hope you know what’s going on!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” I said blithely. “Good old B-7 Western! Just as Kirk Tanger steps out, I jump in and take his place for the scrap. Then I leap on my—rather his— faithful nag and ride away down the set with bullets nipping at my ears.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an outdoor set, the old saloon front, and dusty cowtown street that I remembered so vividly from the old days. Like everything I’d seen on the lot in the three days I had been back from overseas, it looked on its last legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kirk Tanger, who had been co-owner with my Uncle King of K-T—and who now owned it all—was the star. He didn’t seem to like my coming back at all, though he hid his dislike under that famous back-slapping personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But under Kitty Riley’s persuasion, he offered me a job doubling for him in the horse opera. He knew I could handle my dukes with the best of them, and that years on my uncle’s ranch had made the feel of a pony under me the most natural thing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take him up on it, mostly so I’d be near Kitty. I didn’t like the way they acted in the clinches. Kirk Tanger was ten years older than I. But we did have about the same build. He’s six foot one, rangy and slim, with wide shoulders and narrow hips. He’s got curly brown hair and a self-important swagger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The director grunted. I watched Tanger ham it up with his favorite heavy, Lank Rennagan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve run this cowtown long enough, Jake Carson!” Tanger cried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rennagan, big, dirty-faced, ugly, mugged and taunted him while the cameras rolled. “Why, you lily-livered pup. I’ll—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanger, ye hero, started circling him. I waited for my cue. It came when Tanger backed up and enveloped the camera eye for a split-second. I darted in swiftly and made with the fists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast and furious action followed. I popped about his ears while his haymakers whizzed around mine. I was careful to pull my punches. The sound effects would help the illusion along, plus additional speeding up, and spliced-in close- ups of Tanger’s pretty puss, so the movie-goers would think it was him all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played it up hot and heavy, like the freckle-faced kids in the front row like it, then I flattened the “bad guy,” leaped on Tanger’s pinto, and raised dust down the fake cowtown street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cameras ground on. This was a cheap quickie. Tanger wasn’t wasting any film. Guns roared behind me. I thought I felt something zing past my ear. The thought made me grin. As if anybody would be using real bullets? But when I ambled back for a retake, Kitty, who was the femme lead, stared at me with wide hazel eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jack!” she cried. “You’re bleeding!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ear did sting, so I put my hand up to it. It came back red. “Must of nicked it in the scrap,” I smiled casually. After three years as tail gunner a little scratch like that doesn’t seem anything to get excited about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanger walked up just then. He looked pale under his bottled suntan. I noticed a blood vessel in his temple hopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on over to the dispensary, pal,” he said. “I’ll touch it up for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-live-bullet&quot;&gt;A Live Bullet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed him into the little studio dispensary, wondering what was up. Why was Tanger calling me pal, all of a sudden, when everybody on the lot knew Kitty had tossed him over for me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked a little like brothers, dressed alike in the same flashy Western breeches and boots. Mine were a little roughed up after a hard day’s shooting, and my face didn’t need fake tan. It was browned permanently by South Pacific trade winds. The lines around my eyes and mouth didn’t get there from cutting up around Hollywood spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, Kelley,” Tanger said, booting the door shut behind us, “you didn’t nick yourself fighting. A live bullet did that!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I examined it critically in the mirror. Could be. “What makes you think so?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw the puff of smoke from the harness shop window. I ran around fast as I could, behind. I got just a glimpse of the man who shot you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’d he look like?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Couldn’t see his face because he wore a black mask.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mask?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Don’t you get it, Kelley? Both you and I—and Rennagan too, when he’s pulling a trick—wear a ‘masked rider’ get-up in the picture. Another masked rider floating around the lot wouldn’t excite any comment!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I winced as he painted up my scratch and taped it. “Smart guy,” I whistled. “Now, who do you suppose wants me out of the way?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanger shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not you. Me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You?” I asked innocently. Offhand I could think of half a dozen reasons, all of them blonde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanger’s pretty face writhed, “I can’t tell you what it’s all about, Kelley, but believe me. I know. The man who’s out to get me doesn’t know I use a double. He doesn’t know you. Now, here’s what I want you to do …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw it coming. I knew all along Tanger had something up his sleeve when he brought me in here. I shrugged noncommittally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got to do it, pal!” he insisted desperately. “It’s important to the whole studio. Without me this picture will never be finished. If it isn’t, no more K-T. He’s out to get me. He’s a cold-blooded killer. Will stop at nothing! You’ve just got to help me, pal!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sighed, facing him. “Just what do you want me to do about it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He slapped my shoulder, his face glowing with relief. “I knew you’d do it, pal!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I winced. This pal stuff didn’t set well with me. It was a lot different from the way Tanger acted when I first got back. Oh, well. That was because of Kitty. Tanger had been trying to convince her she ought to marry him ever since I left. From the way she, herself, had been acting, I wasn’t sure he hadn’t succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Easy on the orchids,” I murmured. “I haven’t said I’d do anything yet.” The sore look that flashed in his eyes vanished quick-like. He put on a bland ingratiating tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing to it, Kelley. All I want is for you to pretend to be me for the next few days, until the picture’s wrapped up. Live at my place in Beverly Hills. Go to the premiere tonight. Use my car and chauffeur. Why, it’s a breeze!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t much care for the breeze that bullet made fanning my ear,” I reminded him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s five grand in it,” he said. Funny how the mention of a nice round sum like five thousand dollars can change a guy’s mind. Kitty and I could get married. I could buy in with Old Karpis at his movie horse-trainer ranch out in the Valley, as I’d always wanted. As Tanger said, three years of it had made me rather immune to the smell of danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said, “Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-top-kick-of-k-t&quot;&gt;The Top Kick of K-T&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night was typical Hollywood. The heat of the day had cooled down considerably. The sky had shaded down to a deep, rich cobalt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat back luxuriously in Tanger’s smooth limousine, wearing his best tux and smoking one of his best cigars, while Jim, his chauffer, sent the hade spinning down the Sunset Strip out of Beverly Hills, then veering onto Hollywood Boulevard toward the nest of fanning arc-fights that stabbed their wag prettily toward the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood was doing itself proud at this big-time premiere. As top-kick of K-T, it was Tanger’s duty to put to in an appearance. Tonight, with my face deftly made up, I was Tanger. He himself would come, slip in with the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim braked the car smoothly in front of the mobbed entrance canopy, which was flanked on either side by bleacher seats that had been rigged up for the occasion. With hundreds of movie fans’ eyes drilling me as they babbled their criticisms, I stepped down the brightly lit carpeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I saw Kitty. She was breathtaking in a knockout of a blue evening dress with silver sequins. I forgot I was putting on an act and hurried up to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, Kirk!” I took her arm, then noticed her staring at the neat square of tape on my ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, you’re not—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shushed her quickly, and we went in. During the show I spent my time trying to dope out this deal. I hadn’t had a good chance to talk to Kitty since I got back, with Tanger monopolizing her, and had hoped to later. Somehow, in the mob, I lost track of her. Then a couple reporters buttonholed me. I had to lam out before one of them found out I wasn’t really Tanger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the car. It was parked around the corner on a shady little side- street, as I had instructed. That’s one thing about Hollywood. Two blocks off the main drag and you might be m some quiet little hamlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Jim,” I said, hopping in. “Let’s go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chauffeur’s cap ahead of me nodded, and we were off, suddenly. I happened to glance m the mirror over the chauffeur’s head. “Hey, you’re not Jim I” I yelled, “Who—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He flashed a pistol, managing to keep his eyes on the road and on me in the little mirror as we swerved around a corner on two wheels and started east op into the Hollywoodland hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sit still, Tanger!” he snapped roughly. “This is where you get took!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;end-of-the-line&quot;&gt;End of the Line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t bother to disabuse him of the idea that I was Tanger. I was worried about his driving. It was as if he had suddenly gone nuts. He took those hairpin turns on two wheels. All I could see were his eyes and a rough pen of makeup. He was a bad actor, all right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lit a cigarette and sat back. The long car hurtled upward through the brilliant night, then suddenly braked at the brink of a five-hundred-foot drop. It was a lonely scrubby stretch, with the city spread out below like a jeweled pattern. He leaped out, flung open my door, shoving his gun to my face. “All right, chiseler,” he snapped. “This is the end of the line.” He might he a ham-actor, as I decided, but he wasn’t acting now. This was the real McCoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grinned back at him impishly. “Take it slow,” I soothed. Then I jumped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of my sudden lunge sent him reeling back a step, with a grunt of surprise. His gun flung lead between my crooked elbow and my midriff. I could feel death tickle my ribs with the end of his scythe. I put everything I got into a swift uppercut. His head snapped back. My other fist cracked down on his gun-hand, sent the roscoe flying off into all those spangled lights, into oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a snarl he was out of his spin and on me. His fingers reached for my throat. Then we were waltzing dreamily on the graveled edge of that cliff. I had his wrists and was trying to pin them back. He shook loose and started slugging and gouging. He was no mean shakes. He knew a thing or two, must have learned it from the Japs, it was that dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He faked, as if I’d hit him too low. I fell for it. In the second I relaxed his fist came up. Everything swam around me. Or maybe it was me who was swimming, going around and round on the black wall of the hell-deep whirlpool. Above me hung an ugly paint-smeared puss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed out at him feebly, yanked. He moved back, but I caught his shirt. Buttons scattered. Then I went down into that whirlpool, with a faint faraway sound like a siren screaming—or maybe a girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was one shred left of my shattered consciousness. One chunk of knowledge that stayed with me through the aeons of bad dreams that followed. It was the sight of the slugger’s swirling black chest—and of a triangular red mole on his throat, on the lower part of his left breastbone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-raw-deal&quot;&gt;A Raw Deal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feel of soft hands on my forehead helped me out of it. It was nice. Pain shot through me in seven directions, but those cool hands helped a lot. When I opened my peepers, relief rolled over me in a tidal wave. I wasn’t in some nasty old Jap prison camp; I was in Kitty Riley’s apartment. She was looking down at me with sorry, anxious eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What gives?” I wondered, with a low groan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Easy, soldier,” she soothed me, in that low husky voice of hers. “You’ve had quite a time for yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered everything. I sat up quickly. “What happened?” I demanded, feasting my eyes on her soft taffy ringlets and wide kissable lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were at the premiere, remember?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure. I lost you in the mob. Go on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I bumped into Kirk. He yanked me out of a side door with him.” Her voice was like dripping honey. “I had my coupe. Kirk offered to drive me home, and on the way I noticed your car. The driver seemed to be hopped up, so I insisted that we follow you. Of course my jalopy can’t keep up to Kirk’s limousine, which you were in, so we lagged behind, making those hills the best we could. We reached you just as you went into your tailspin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about the pug?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Got away. Jumped in the car and beat it. As I said,” she smiled, “my little coupe is no match for that big bus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What happened to Jim?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kirk called me a few minutes ago to see if you had come out of it yet. It seems Jim got a message, ostensibly from his boss, telling him to leave the car and hurry home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded, scowling. “So Jim went, and my would-be killer took his place. Did you notify the cops?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty shook her shiny curls. “Kirk said no. He looked you over. Said you would be okay, and wanted it hushed up. It all has to do with whoever he’s afraid of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Got any ideas about that?” I asked casually, lighting a cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No-o.” She looked thoughtful. “Wait. Yes, I have. You know Mocardai?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The gambling house king? I’ve heard of him. He’s a nice character to cross.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kirk owes him money. A lot of money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried my legs and found I could stand up, if a little shakily. “Jack,” Kitty said, in a low different voice, “why don’t you go away?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What for?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I don’t know what this is all about, exactly, but why stick your neck out?” I eyed her carefully. She looked sincere enough, but then, Kitty’s quite an actress. On a hunch I asked, “What’s about the studio?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a pretty bad way, Jack,” she wagged her blonde head. “Seems as if nobody will take a chance on Kirk Tanger, since your Uncle King died. It’s all rather odd.” She put her soft hand on my arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jack, I’ve always thought you got a raw deal. King meant to leave his half of K-T to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled crookedly. “That was before I enlisted. King’s doctor could have kept me out, he thought. I couldn’t see it that way at all. You know King. As long as you did things his way everything was fine. The minute you crossed him he dropped you like a hot grenade. Tanger stayed. I didn’t. That’s the whole story in a nutshell.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty looked so genuinely sorry about it that I planted a kiss square on her wide lips. It tasted wonderful, but I still wasn’t sure. “Good-bye,” I told her and scrammed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;last-will-and-testament&quot;&gt;Last Will and Testament&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four hours I slept, then went out to the studio. It was a good half hour before shooting time. Contrary to propaganda, a star’s day starts real early and lasts real late sometimes. With a quickie Western like this one, it was even tougher. Tanger was shooting it on a shoestring, and a frayed one at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out from the gateman that Tanger’s office was vacant, so I slipped in the back way. I used one of my uncle’s keys which I had found among his personal effects. I left the blinds down while I went over the joint. Since Tanger wasn’t going to let me in on his little secret I was going to probe it out for myself. If I was going to continue dodging bullets, I was going to know why. Furthermore, as Kitty hinted, there was something mighty funny going on at K-T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw that one of the desks had been taken out. A single big mahogany affair filled the center of Tanger’s private office. I tried the drawers first. Nothing unusual. Then I turned my attention to the metal wall cabinets. At first I found nothing there, either, until I found a green strongbox tucked way down in at the bottom. It was heavy so I set it down on the floor. The lock was a good one, but I remembered King’s key ring and tried them, one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my knees by it, I flung the cover back and combed through its contents. I whistled when I found it. The envelope was marked, Last Will and Testament. Herbert J. King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My uncle. It was dated July 8th, just three days before he died. I broke the seal and started reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I, Herbert J. King, being of sound mind and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard the back door snap shut softly behind me. I whirled in time to catch just a glimpse of a black shadow wearing a mask. Before I could get to my feet he lunged, pounced on me like a panther. My head hit a corner of the cabinet. For a few seconds all I saw were stars. When I came out of it he had vanished out of the back door, the envelope and will along with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sprang after him, muttering a few choice words I had picked up in New Guinea. I flung open the door in time to see Kirk Tanger striding bare-headed toward the office, dressed in cowboy togs, his spurs jingling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked surprised to see me coming out of the back door of his private office, but only smiled amiably. “Waiting to see me, Kelley?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah.” I watched him narrowly. “I want some information.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He smiled that famous smile. “I get it, Kelley. Since tangling with a gunman last night, you figure it’s time I let you in on what it’s all about. Eh, pal?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, pal, I was on my way to find you. It’s like this. I ran up a sizable gambling debt with Mocardai, and he doesn’t like waiting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And he decided to take it out of your hide?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s it,” Tanger nodded. “Last night I got him to call off his hounds. I convinced him that I can settle up as soon as this picture is finished, which will be in a few days. He’s willing to wait.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All nice and smooth, but it didn’t set well in my craw. It matched what Kitty had told me last night, but that just put her in the shade alongside Tanger. Well, maybe you couldn’t blame a girl for changing her mind about a guy, once she found out he was not going to inherit half a movie studio. Just suppose, for instance, that Kitty hadn’t just “happened” to follow me last night. Suppose Tanger wasn’t with her at all. Suppose that he—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That did it. The rising tide of anger inside me swept up into my brain. I made a quick grab at Tanger’s silk collar,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What goes on?” he grinned, good-naturedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing,” I mumbled. “Nothing at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked away fast, stiff-legged. I was wrong. Dead wrong. There was no triangular red mole on Tanger’s chest. No mole of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-triangular-red-mole&quot;&gt;A Triangular Red Mole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s takes were to be some of the last big scenes. All the location shots were completed, processed and ready for cutting in the lab, having been filmed the week before up in the Sherwood Lake country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the usual barroom free-for- all, with the usual collapsing chairs and bottles busted over heads. It played havoc with the flimsy set, making it unlikely that it would stand up under another such brawl or even a retake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Connor, the director, barked out orders for the final to-the-death battle between Lank Rennagan, the heavy lead, and the hero. In the eyes of the public, Kirk Tanger. Actually me. Tanger wouldn’t dream of risking that pretty face of his before the cameras, any more than he would risk it in real life. Or would he, I wondered, if the stakes were high enough. A couple of telephone calls had told me a lot that I hadn’t known before, and was never intended to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connor’s heavy voice bawled instructions. Mopping his bald dome that glinted under the heavy lights, he finished, “Adlib it. But make it good! We don’t want to have any retakes! Can’t afford it! Make it real!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rennagan grinned at me wolfishly. There was an odd gleam in his eyes, but it didn’t really register until a little later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cameras rolled. Rennagan came at me, mugging ferociously. I slipped under his lunge and landed a make-believe punch on his jaw. His head went back and he sprawled on the floor. Then he was up again and at me. We clinched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of his slugs landed hard, but it can’t be entirely faked. I thought nothing of it until his hairy arm grabbed me suddenly and yanked me down behind the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happened fast. His left hand seized my throat and forced me flat against the floor. Then he grabbed a half-smashed bottle, a real one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a glimpse of his hairy chest. There was a red mole on it. A triangular red mole. So now I knew! Rennagan was the one I had tangled with last night. He was going to finish the job now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studio accidents do happen. He’d purposely got me behind the bar, out of camera range, so he could make it look like that. “This time you’ll stay out!” he whispered. I saw the ragged edge of glass swing down at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweating blood, I yanked to one side in time, swung a roundhouse into his solar plexus. He gave a howl of anguish and let the bottle drop. My boot went out into his belt, and sent him flying into the open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leaped after him. Fury was upon me. I forgot all about cameras and movies. All I knew was that Rennagan had tried to kill me, at least twice. I plastered my fists all over his greasy pan. I hit him over and over again, until I was out of wind. Then, as he sagged, I cracked out once more, with all my weight behind it. He dropped without a sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bravo!” Connor applauded behind me as the cameras stopped. ‘‘Best scrap I’ve directed in fifteen years!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;yellow-bellied-4f&quot;&gt;Yellow-Bellied 4F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swayed there a moment, getting back my wind. Ignoring Connor’s orchids, I walked up to Kirk Tanger, who was standing off to one side with Kitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He meant to kill you!” Kitty cried tremulously. “I saw it in his eyes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” I said, stroking my cut knuckles. My eyes were on Tanger. He was pale. The smile on his pan looked lopsided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nonsense!” he said, trying to laugh it off. “Why Rennagan’s the best heavy on the lot!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That why you picked him to get rid of me last night?” I demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“W-What—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t you think it’s about time you quit play-acting? You’re not that good!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He drew himself up. “I don’t know what you mean, Kelley.” He started to stalk away, insulted. I stuck out my arm and twirled him around so I could look him square in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You milked your way into Uncle King’s favors ever since he picked you up on the street and brought you to K-T. When you became a star, you bought in. When I enlisted, and you yellow-bellied your way into a 4-F classification, you put on the pressure. You all but kissed his boots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You knew he had a bad heart. So when he told you about the new will he made, in my favor, you decided both he and I had to die. In his case it was easy. A drop of something in his heart medicine would do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You hid the new will. You didn’t dare destroy it, because there was a witness, King’s valet. So you paid him off and got him to leave town. When I got back, you faked up this gag about somebody who was after you, and offered me five grand to take your place in order to make my death look completely accidental. You hired Rennagan to do your dirty work. But he bungled the job last night, so you told him to finish it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You knew I found that will in your office, because you were the masked character who stepped in on me. You knocked me down and ran out, tucked the will under your shirt and pulled off your mask, then came back, pretending you had just got there!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanger’s lips twitched. “You can’t prove any of this!” he retorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No? I checked the time you really came in the lot gate with the gateman. It matched. I found out from King’s valet’s mother where he had gone. I called him long distance. When I told him what I suspected, he came clean, told me all he knew about the new will, dispossessing you and making me controlling owner of K-T. Now, hand it over!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I haven’t got it!” Tanger cried. “I burned it! I mean—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, no, you didn’t!” Kitty told him, her eyes blazing with disgust. “I met Jack just after he left you. He told me to keep my eyes on you every second!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grinning, I grabbed his pretty silk shirt and ripped it open. There was the will, tucked partway under his wide belt. I tossed it to Kitty, then grabbed Tanger by the belt and studied his pretty pan speculatively, as if wondering where I was going to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cowered back. “No! No!” he whimpered, having seen what his pal Rennagan got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t hit him!” Kitty cried. “Please don’t!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why not?” I demanded, scowling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remember, dear,” she said sweetly, “This picture isn’t quite finished yet, and he is the star. We’ll need his slimy puss for some closeups, as is. As wife-to-be of the controlling owner of K-T I say we’ve got to be prudent! Mangle him later, dear!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pushed Tanger away and drew Kitty close to me, grinning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyhow,” I said. “Here’s one fade-out clinch where the double takes over!” I signaled to Connor. “Let ’em roll, professor!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/satan-hogs-the-camera/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/satan-hogs-the-camera/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
