<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tales of Murder</title>
    <description>A murder mystery short story &amp;amp; novel site.</description>
    <link>localhost:3000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 14:11:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 14:11:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Remember Jeanie</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;morgue-bait&quot;&gt;Morgue Bait&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years Bay Street was the place. Bar whisky for eight cents a shot or a double slug for fifteen. Waterfront Street. The dirty grey waves slapped at the crusted piles and left an oil scum. A street to forget with. A street which could close in on you, day to day, night to night, until you maybe ran into an old friend who slipped you a five, and somebody saw you get it; there at dawn an interne from city hospital would shove your eyelid up with a clean, pink thumb. “Icebox meat,” he’d say. “Morgue bait.” And maybe, as he stood up, he’d look down at your hollow grey face and the sharp bones of your wrists and wonder how you’d kept alive so long. So very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something happened to Bay Street. It acquired glamor. Reading the trend, the smart boys came down and bought up the property and built long low clubs with blue lights and bright music and expensive drinks. The shining cars lined up along the curb, and the people with the clean clothes gave ragged kids two bits to make certain the tires weren’t slashed while they were inside the places with the bright music and the soft women. The doormen at the new places had no time for the men in broken shoes who were living out the last years of addiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the men of Bay Street moved to Dorrity Street—one block over. Many of the displaced little bars moved over. The red, blue and green neon flickered against the brick flanks of the ancient warehouses, and, in the night, the steaming chant of the jukeboxes, the hoarse laughter and the scuff of broken shoes was the same as always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard sat on the stone front step of an abandoned warehouse and stared at the street, shining in a light misty rain. The rain made pink halos around the neon of the place across the street. “Allison’s Grill.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard thought vaguely that if the rain increased, he’d have to get under shelter. He didn’t want to go inside; he had come out because he had been sick. The muscles of his diaphragm still ached with the violence of his retching. He turned the ragged collar of his dark blue suit coat up around his neck. He wondered if he ought to walk down the alley and see if anybody had tried to move in on him. Two weeks before, he had found a sturdy packing case and, at dawn, had dragged it down the alley and put it under a fire escape. The effort had left him weak and panting. He had filled it with clean burlap and it made a snug bed. The fall rain was chill; the packing case wouldn’t be any good in the winter. He forced that thought out of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a dark man, with a sullen face. Once he had been solid, almost stocky, but the flesh had slowly melted off him during the past year. He was still capable of sudden, explosive bursts of energy. His hair was long and his square jaw was dark with several day’s beard. His cheeks were hollow and there was a dark wildness in his puffy eyes that the shadows concealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across the street an old man with matted white hair lurched out of Allison’s and fell on one knee. He got up and went on, limping and cursing in a thin, high voice, watered down by age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard heard the slow tock, tock of heels, heavy heels, coming down the sidewalk on his side. He knew who it was without looking. He scowled down at the sidewalk. The slow steps stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;i-like-it-this-way&quot;&gt;I Like It This Way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked up. Patrolman Clarence Flynn, tall and solid, stood looking down at him. Flynn’s raincoat had a cape effect across the shoulders that made him look larger than life size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said softly, “You okay, Frankie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give me a cigarette, Flynn,” Bard said hoarsely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flynn handed him one, lit it. Over the match flame the two men glanced briefly into each other’s eyes—and looked quickly away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same gentle tone, Flynn said, “When are you going to straighten out, Frankie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I like it this way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You were a good cop, Frankie. You straighten out and you could come back in; your record’s good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I like it this way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You look sick, Frankie.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m fine. You got a beat to walk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flynn shrugged. He handed the half pack of cigarettes to Bard and walked on. He stopped ten feet away and said, “She wasn’t worth this, Frankie; no woman was worth this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard called him a foul word and snapped the half smoked cigarette into the street. After he could no longer hear the sound of Flynn’s heels, he tried to light another one. His hands shook so badly that he couldn’t do it. The matches were damp. They sputtered and went out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt in his side pocket to make certain that the fifty-cent piece was still there. It was cool against his fingertips. He stood up, swaying slightly, and then walked across the street, pushed his way into the heat and smell of Allison’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar was of plywood laid over some heavier substance. Naked bulbs were laid behind the bottles on the back bar, and the light glowed through—amber. The place was narrow and rectangular—with the bar on the left and booths on the right. A jukebox sat against the far wall, bubbles rising endlessly up through the colored tubes. Arther Allison, a small trim man with Truman glasses and a grey Colman mustache, in a spotless white shirt, waited on bar, his quick eyes flicking ceaselessly from face to face. Allison was a watchful, careful man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader waited on the booths and, on occasion, acted as bouncer. Jader was tall and heavy with weak eyes that watered constantly. He, too, was watchful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underneath the bar, to the left of the beer taps, was a small drawer. There were usually a few small packages in that drawer. Summer and winter a small hot coal fire burned in the basement. In the winter, the fire heated the building; in the summer the radiators were turned off. On the under edge of the drawer containing the packages was a small loop of wire. Either Jader or Allison could, by yanking on the loop of wire, drop the bottom of the drawer. The little packages would then drop down a chute into the fire. It was safer that way. For every package held and relayed to the proper pickup men, there was a small fee of ten dollars. Five for Jader and five for Allison. On some days as many as eight packages spent varying lengths of time in the drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allison and Jader were very watchful and cautious men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Frank Bard walked in, there were four men at the bar. He knew three of them by sight; the fourth was a stranger. Two of the booths were occupied. In one were two Swedish merchant seamen, and a thin painted girl with hair the color of ripe tomatoes and a wet, smeared mouth. In the second booth were two quiet men wearing dark topcoats. Bard glanced at them and guessed that they were waiting for one of the packages to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard di	d a curious thing. He held the door wide, and, as he walked over to the bar, he smiled down over his right shoulder. He said something in a low voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stepped up beside the stranger, still smiling down at a point about six inches from his right shoulder. Allison moved over toward him and said, “You got the money, Frank?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took the fifty-cent piece from his pocket and said, “The usual for me and Jeanie, Arthur.” Allison poured two straight ryes and smiled tiredly as he put one in front of Bard and one in front of the empty space. Bard said, “You wouldn’t rather sit in a booth, would you, Jeanie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the hell do you keep asking her that, for?” Arthur said. “She never wants to sit in a booth; she always stands up here at the bar with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard looked vaguely indignant. “It’s polite to ask her, Arthur.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stranger, a lean man in work clothes with a pinched, bitter mouth, looked with pained disgust at Frank Bard and then at Allison. “What the hell goes on?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allison looked amused. “Oh, Frank comes in here all the time with Jeanie.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard turned and looked at the stranger. “Jeanie and me, we like this place. She likes to come here even if 3he did have a little bad luck here a little over a year ago.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stranger looked into Bard’s eyes and moved back a few inches. “Bad luck?” he inquired politely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Jeanie was in here late one night and some lush hit her with a bottle. Hit her right over the left ear. I guess my Jeanie hasn’t got such a tough skull. Funny how it didn’t break the bottle, hey Arthur?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;jeanie&quot;&gt;Jeanie&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader came over, his pale eyes watering. He said, “Damn it, Arthur, what did you let this dizzy punk come in here for?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur grinned. “Nervous?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, the guy drives away trade.” He turned to the stranger. “Mister, a drunk bashed her head in with a bottle and got clean away. We give the cops a description but they never found the guy.” He paused and glanced at Bard, who was talking to Jeanie in a low voice, almost a whisper. He continued, “And this thing used to be a cop. Jeanie was his girl. He’s been on the skids for nearly a year, and every time he comes in here he’s got that damn imaginary woman with him. I tell you, it’s enough to drive me nuts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur grinned tightly. “Where’s your sense of humor, Jader?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader looked again at Bard, cursed and wandered off. The Swedes were pounding on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard bent low over his glass of rye. He lifted it with a quick motion, and downed it. It caught in his throat. He gagged, but it stayed down. He stood for a moment, savoring the glow of it, feeling immediately stronger, more confident. He glanced at the wall above the back-bar, whistling softly. His lean hand, dirt stained into the knuckles, reached slowly out, shoving the empty glass over toward Jeanie. The hand hooked around her full glass and brought it back. He glanced down, as though surprised to see the full drink in front of him. He drank it with steadier hand and smiled at Jeanie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Taste good to you, honey? If I had the dough, I’d buy you another.” He looked down at his dime change. He glanced over and said, “What was that, honey?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He beckoned to Arthur. “Arthur, Jeanie says …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I know. She wants a beer chaser.” He picked up the dime, drew one beer and set it in front of Jeanie. Bard whistled again, while his right hand stole out and slid it over. He drank it quickly and, again looking at the wall, shoved the glass over in front of Jeanie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stranger said, “You were a cop?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard looked at him and drew himself up, looking for a fraction of a second, out of the wise, confident policeman’s eyes. The expression faded and his eyes once more looked hot and wild. “What’s it to you!” he demanded hoarsely. “I don’t see you buying me and Jeanie no drinks; buy ’em and we’ll talk to you, Mister.” The man took hold of Bard’s shoulder with what was almost gentleness. He turned him so that he faced him directly. The work-hardened hand came across, smacking solidly, fingers open, across Bard’s jaw, knocking him against the bar. The hand came back in a backhand blow that straightened him up again, splitting his underlip at the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard stood unsteadily, his hands at his side, grinning foolishly at the stranger, his eyes filling with tears from the burning pain in his lip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur said, “Take it easy!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stranger said, “That’s for being a lousy cop; that’s for nothing. You there, set up drinks for Prince Charming and his lady.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks,” Bard said humbly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Think nothing of it, Prince.” The man turned his back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard drank the two drinks and stood holding onto the edge of the bar. His face greyed and he said, “Excuse me, honey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He lurched off to the men’s room and was ill. He came out in a few minutes, still shaking, his clothes soiled and stopped by the bar. He said, “Come on, Jeanie.” He walked toward the door. Jader crossed close beside him. With wild fury, Bard grabbed Jader’s arm and spun him around. He said, “Why the hell don’t you watch where you’re going?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He bent over suddenly, as though helping someone up from the floor. He snarled at Jader, “Okay. Okay. Go around knocking women down and don’t apologize. You all right, honey,” he said softly, making brushing motions in the air. Jader grunted, balled a large white fist and slowly drew, it back, his wet eyes narrowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur snapped, “Jader! Cut it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big hand unclenched and Bard walked to the door, held it open with a small bow and then walked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader said, “Arthur, I’m not going to stand for …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up!” The grey eyes were cold behind the lenses, the mouth a thin tight line under the mustache. The girl with the Swedes giggled shrilly. Jader turned and walked toward the back of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the alley Frank Bard stood, his hand on the corner of the packing case, looking up at the night sky. The rain had stopped and small clouds scudded across the moon. Bard dropped to his knees and crawled into the box. He lay with his face against the damp wood and tears ran down through the thick stubble on his cheeks. He reached awkwardly into his side pocket and pulled out a small package. He unwrapped the paper. It contained a small cool metal tube that still contained lipstick. Her lipstick. He held it close to his nose. It held the elusive scent of her. His fingertips touched the little skein of hair. Her hair. Long and pale and delicate—amazingly golden. He wrapped the package and replaced it in his pocket. After a long time, he slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-back-booth&quot;&gt;The Back Booth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader was in a good mood. The drawer was almost full of packages and the first pickup was due in an hour. Arthur Allison had gone to the races. It was the first time Jader had been alone in the place in many months. He liked the feeling of being trusted. The sun was hot on Dorrity Street. It slanted through the smeared front window, lighting the dim interior. One old man was asleep, his head on the booth table. Jader planned to wake him up and get him out soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glanced across the street and his cheerful smile faded. He saw Frank Bard coming diagonally across the street in the sun, looking down at a spot six inches from his right shoulder. Jader could see his lips moving. Jader’s lip curled as he saw Bard’s grey, shapeless shoes, the tired scuff of his walk, the stained, baggy trousers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stepped over into the doorway as Bard opened the door. Jader didn’t move. Bard said, “Hey! Let us in!” He took a dollar out of his side pocket and held it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want no screwballs in here,” Jader said sullenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s Arthur? Arthur lets us come in. Get out of Jeanie’s way, Jader.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re not coming in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard stared at him for a few seconds. “Arthur won’t like to hear about this. You got a public place here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You stand up to the bar and talk to the other customers. The hell with that noise; you drive away business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Bard considered that statement solemnly. “Okay. So Jeanie and me, we’ll take the back booth in the end and we won’t talk to anybody, will we Jeanie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader glanced down the street, saw a familiar sedan coming. It would be best not to delay pickup. He moved aside. “Okay, come on in and take the end booth. I’ll be with you in a minute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard stood aside as though to let someone come in, and then followed. Jader waited until Bard was out of sight in the booth before slipping the package across to the slim, dark man who had ordered the beer. The man drank up and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader poured two ryes and walked back to the booth with them. Frank Bard smiled up at him. “No, she’s sitting right there across from me, Jader. Maybe we should take a booth oftener. It’s nice and private back here in the end. Jeanie says it’s nice and clean. Clean ashtray and everything. She don’t mind being in the booth where she got hit. Do you, Jeanie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader scowled. “‘The place is good and clean because I clean it. Stop the chatter and give me the buck; there’s a dime extra for table service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you made me come back here!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a dime extra.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Jader. Okay.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader rang up the half dollar and took the change back. He threw it on the table. Bard said, “The front way is the only way out, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” he answered and walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went behind the bar and stood with his fat arms on the bar, looking gloomily across at the old man sleeping. Some of the flavor had gone out of the day with Frank Bard’s arrival. He seldom showed up in the afternoon. It was just damn bad luck that he had to pick that afternoon, Jader thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He scowled as he heard the low sound of Bard’s voice. Jader couldn’t imagine why Arthur permitted Bard to come around, in fact, why he seemed amused to have Bard around. It was the type of wry joke that Jader couldn’t savor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he heard Bard call him hoarsely, he pushed away from the bar, drew two more ryes and walked slowly back to the booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stood in front of the booth and reached out to set one rye down across from Bard. The big white hand stopped in midair and Jader stared at the ashtray. There were two butts in the ashtray. The tip of one was crimsoned with lipstick. For a moment he thought wildly that he hadn’t cleaned it. And he suddenly remembered Bard’s saying it was clean. The shot glass slipped out of his white fingers and dropped, overturning on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’d that come from?” he said in a high, thin voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The cigarette butt? Jeanie smoked it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t say that!” Jader said wildly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t you like women smoking? That’s old fashioned,” Bard said severely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’d it come from?” Jader demanded again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you, from Jeanie.” Bard suddenly leaned his dark head over and looked at his shoulder. He chuckled mildly. “She was sitting right beside me here with her head on my shoulder when she smoked it. Look here.” From the surface of the dark blue coat he plucked two long strands of shining gold—held them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader’s mouth worked and the other glass dropped at his feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bard said, “You see, Jader, you only thought you killed her.” His tone was quiet, as though explaining to a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jader made a strangled noise. His wet eyes widened. “I killed her. She couldn’t … . She couldn’t … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;jader&quot;&gt;Jader&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned then and looked into Frank Bard’s eyes. His underlip hung away from his teeth and he took a slow step away from the booth. Somehow Bard was in front of him. Jader clenched his white fists and struck blindly. He missed and went off balance as Frank Bard’s thin, dirty fist smashed his mouth. He fell heavily to his hands and knees, going over onto his side as one of the grey, broken shoes landed against the side of his head. One of the white hands lay, as still as lard, against the floor. Frank Bard set his heel on the fingers and swiveled his entire weight, slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked quickly to the front door and locked it. The old mas still slept. He went behind the bar and carefully opened the drawer. Allison and Jader were cautious, watchful men—but who suspicions or fears a mad alcoholic? He set six neat packages on the top of the bar, opened the cash register and took a nickel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sergeant Sullivan, Police Headquarters.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sully, this is Frank Bard … don’t interrupt me … I’m at Allison’s Grill on Dorrity Street. I’ve just taken over the joint. Jader confessed to killing Jean Palmray. The angle is that she was trying to do some independent spying to help me along and they got wise and Jader killed her; I think he only meant to stun her. I’ve got a bunch of junk here. Six small packages. Send the boys. And have Arthur Allison picked up out at the track. Yeah.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hung up, walked back and looked at Jader. The man was beginning to stir. Bard kicked him in the head again and walked back to the bar. He was suddenly enormously tired. He still held the small golden tube of lipstick in his fist. He slipped it into his pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They wouldn’t take a lush back on the force, even if he had done what he set out to do one year before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took a bottle off the back bar and pulled the patent gimmick out of the top of it and tilted it up to his lips. Drunk or sober, he had remembered to pretend that Jeanie had been with him. That was what had counted. The buildup. And after a year of buildup, Jader had cracked wide open. It had been tough, pretending that she was always beside him, looking at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tilted the bottle, and as the sharp liquor filled his mouth, he felt a soft touch on his arm. He spun quickly, spraying the liquor onto the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man was still asleep in the booth and Jader was still silent on the floor. The door was locked. In the distance an approaching siren moaned softly. The bottle slid from his nerveless fingers and shattered on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/you-remember-jeanie/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/you-remember-jeanie/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Mountain Comes to Mohammed</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;right-under-your-stupid-noses&quot;&gt;Right Under Your Stupid Noses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detective Sergeant Forbes made a gesture of exasperated frustration with his big hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tell you, Mr. Carter, Donovan or Greene or I have had Louie under our eye every minute of the day since you first put us on the case,” he protested to the district attorney; “and at night one or the other of us has camped outside the door of his hotel room and peeked through the keyhole. If he’d contacted Landis, we’d have seen them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right, Mr. Carter,” Detective Donovan affirmed earnestly. “That guy hasn’t even been to the men’s room without one of us tag-gin’ along; he just couldn’t have met Landis without us knowin’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He just couldn’t have, but he just has,” District Attorney Jeff Carter amended with deadly calm. “Or maybe you two think he pulls those phony tens and twenties out of his hat, the way a magician does rabbits. Louie and Landis are meeting somewhere, and meeting regularly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His voice rose to a sudden roar. “What’s more, they’re doing it right under your stupid noses. Now get back on the job, and this time try tailing Louie with your eyes open; you can tell Greene the same goes for him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two detectives muttered hasty “Yes, sirs,” and departed from the district attorney’s office with an air of injured dignity which implied that they considered themselves unjustly impugned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the office door had closed behind them, Jeff spoke to his younger brother Stephen, who had been slouched sideways with his feet dangling over the arm of the visitor’s chair while he waited for the district attorney to be ready to go out to lunch. “I’ve never known Greene or Donovan —let alone Forbes—to fall down on a simple assignment of this kind before,” he remarked; “yet the facts prove they’ve slipped somewhere. But I’m hanged if I can figure out where.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen pivoted about on the end of his spine until his feet came to rest upon the floor in front of him. “Just who are these chaps, Louie and Landis, Jeff?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Counterfeiters,” the district attorney answered. “Lonesome Louie Madden pushes the stuff— gets it into circulation—and isn’t especially important. But Big Ben Landis is the brains of the gang; that’s why I want to use Louie to lead us to him. Naturally, the Federal men are working on the case, too; but they’re leaving this particular angle of it for my office to handle, and I’d like to show them we can make good. Only for some reason that’s a complete mystery to me, the best men on my staff seem unable to follow a trail that must be as broad as the back end of a Mack truck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe Landis is passing the money along to Louie through some other member of the gang,” Stephen suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff shook his head. “Landis doesn’t operate that way,” he replied. “He claims that the middle man is the weakest point in a counterfeiting ring—which is pretty much the truth—so he doesn’t use one. He manufactures the stuff himself, from engraving the plates down to the actual printing, and doles it out to two or three legmen, who pass it on small purchases, and turn what they get in change back to him—less their commissions, of course. He never gives any of them more than a few hundred dollars at a time, for fear they may get ideas about skipping out and going into temporary business for themselves. That’s how I know he must be contacting Louie practically every other day or so. The thing that’s got me beat is, how does he do it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Could be he’s leaving the stuff somewhere for Louie to pick up,” Stephen offered. “Say a box in the railroad station, for instance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m afraid that’s out, too,” the district attorney said. “I’ve got the daily reports hare from Forbes, Donovan, and Greene ever since they’ve been on the case.” he gestured toward a manila folder of papers on the desk in front of biro, “and not one of them so much as mentions Louie’s having gone anywhere near a railroad station or any other place where he could pick up a package that might contain two or three hundred dollars in phony tens and twenties. All he does when he goes out is stroll about the center of town for an hour or so and make a few small purchases with his phony money. I can’t let it go on much longer; yet if I pick him up now, I’ll lose the only chance I may get to catch Landis.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Landis is wearing a disguise when they meet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff smiled briefly, also ironically. “It would be easier to disguise a hippopotamus than Big Ben Landis,” be observed. “The man must ‘weigh over three hundred pounds. But let’s forget about him while we have lunch.” He reached for his own hat on the clothes tree in the corner, then tossed Stephen his. “I don’t want my appetite spoiled.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen caught the hat with one hand and placed it at a rakish angle upon his dark head. With the other hand, he picked up the folder of reports from his brother’s desk, and took it with him,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-little-friendly-call-on-louie&quot;&gt;A Little, Friendly Call On Louie&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late in the afternoon, having a free hour or so, Stephen went over the reports carefully in the privacy of his own law office. He learned from them two things that he considered significant. The first was that every morning at exactly ten-thirty, Lonesome Louie left the cheap hotel where he was staying to go for a walk, during which he merely strolled aimlessly about for an hour or so, then returned to the hotel; the second was that he repeated this procedure every afternoon at exactly one-thirty. Stephen smiled with satisfaction at the reports. They had told him precisely what he wanted to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening during dinner, he brought up the subject of Lonesome Louie and Big Ben Landis. “What would you say, Jeff,” he began, “to my going along with Sergeant Forbes tomorrow morning when he goes on duty?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The district attorney looked up suspiciously from his plate. “What for?” he demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I know how we can make Lonesome Louie lead us to Big Ben Landis.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff snorted skeptically. “This isn’t a problem in deduction, Steve,” he pointed out. “It’s a matter of routine tailing that doesn’t call for any fancy mental gymnastics, but just for ordinary police training and practice; which Forbes has had, and you haven’t. If he hasn’t been able to spot the way Louie makes contact with Landis, how can you expect to do it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Still, I don’t guess it’d do any harm if I tried,” Stephen persisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff was forced to concede the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning Lonesome Louie was temporarily disconcerted upon descending from the unclean flea-bag that was his room, to find two tailers instead of the usual one waiting for him in the lobby of the hotel—especially when he recognized in the smaller of the two the younger brother of the district attorney. But his generally lugubrious countenance relaxed in a confident grin when, as he sallied forth, both Stephen and the big sergeant fell into step behind him in the usual way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You see, Mr. Stephen,” Forbes said, discouraged, after they had played a kind of shadow tag with Louie for the better part of an hour, “he doesn’t meet anybody or do anything worth battin’ an eye at. He acts more like a man who’s just out to kill time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen smiled in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forbes, how right you are!” he murmured, but he didn’t sound in the least discouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louie continued to lead them a merry, if somewhat leisurely, chase for another half hour, then he headed back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, instead of taking up their former position on the scuffed leather bench in the lobby facing the staircase and the perpetually out-of-order elevator, Stephen waited until the man they were tailing had disappeared from sight up the stairs; then he began to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll just pay a little, friendly call on Louie,” he remarked to the sergeant. “I’ve a notion this is his time to be receiving company, although I don’t guess he’ll be expecting us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they unceremoniously flung open the door to Louie’s room, the enormous fat man who was there with Louie sprang up with a violence that sent his chair crashing over backwards. His hand made a quick jab toward his hip pocket, but stopped midway when he saw the muzzle of Sergeant Forbe’s police automatic trained upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Landis,” the sergeant said with grim satisfaction, “you can reach, but it’s not gonna be for anything you can touch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-mountain&quot;&gt;The Mountain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the district attorney’s office an hour or so later, Stephen lolled in the visitor’s chair and cocked one leg indolently over its arm. “It was all perfectly simple, Jeff,” he drawled. “I spotted it as soon as I read those reports, and noticed that Louie went for a walk every day at exactly the same time in the morning, and again in the afternoon. After he’d left the hotel —with Forbes or Donovan or Greene, as the case might be, following—Landis simply walked in and waited in his room for him to come back, when he gave Louie a fresh supply of the counterfeit money and collected his share of the real money Louie had got in change when he passed the phony bills. Then, when Louie went out for his afternoon walk, Landis left again. It was all perfectly safe and, as I said before, perfectly simple; so simple that I’d have spotted it even without reading the reports.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That,” Jeff stated flatly; “I don’t believe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen smiled with the bland ingenuousness that always set his older brother’s teeth on edge. “But it’s true, Jeff,” he protested. “If Louie wasn’t meeting Landis—and it was plain that he wasn’t, or Forbes or one of the other men you had tailing him would have spotted them—then the only other way for them to make contact was for Landis to meet him. You all made the quite natural mistake of expecting Mohammed to go to the mountain, whereas,” his smile became even more ingenuous, “this was one of the rare instances in which the mountain came to Mohammed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/the-mountain-comes-to-mohammed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/the-mountain-comes-to-mohammed/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Masked Alibi</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-rude-cabin&quot;&gt;A Rude Cabin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the gathering gloom of the Adirondack forest a twig snapped sharply. Corporal Hal Robberts, New York state trooper, halted, his whipcord body of his tensing beneath the trim gray and black uniform. For a moment he listened, his gloved hand sliding back to the comforting assurance of the big .45 Colt belted around the sheepskin coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he pushed slowly forward. A snow- covered branch caught the toe of his snowshoe, tripping him. Simultaneously came the whiplike crack of a rifle. Something tugged sharply at the trooper’s fur cap, whined off the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the echoes of the shot died, Robberts was wriggling his way to the shelter of a nearby spruce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some crazy poacher.” he muttered. There was no one else it could be for on this particular assignment the lean-faced trooper earned no warrant in his pocket. But knowing the peculiar breed of men in the mountains Robberts slid the .45 into his hand and waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a fool would charge that hidden rifle with only a revolver. And Robberts was no fool. There w ere plenty of men in this remote section of the Adirondacks—men who had lived alone until their minds had slightly cracked—who would shoot down an officer if they feared arrest for some petty poaching offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stealthily, foot by foot, the trooper wormed his way from the shelter of the pine. Taking advantage of every available bit of cover, ears keenly alert, eyes striving to pierce the gathering gloom, Robberts began a tortuous circle that should bring him to the rear of the spot which he had marked as the origin of the ambusher’s shot. Suddenly, he stood erect with a muttered exclamation of disgust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trampled spot in the snow behind the bole of a huge spruce marked the ambusher’s waiting place. Robberts picked a spent cartridge from the ground. But that meant nothing, for the cartridge was a .32-40, which would fit a third of the woodsmen’s rifles. For a moment, he stared at the webbed tracks of snowshoes that led off into the gloom, debating. Then he shrugged; no use to swing out on the trail tonight for in ten minutes pitch darkness would envelop the mountains. But he could camp nearby, and in the morning trail down the maker of those crisscrossed tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For fifteen minutes the trooper slogged on through the snow and increasing cold. Suddenly he halted, staring at a steady gleam of light that flickered from the darkness a few hundred yards ahead of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later Robberts was standing before a rude cabin from which light streamed through dingy window panes. He paused for a moment, striking a match and examining a pair of snowshoes hanging from a peg in the outside wall. But these were not the webs worn by that would- be killer back in the timber. Robberts knocked, then pushed open the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;amos-norton&quot;&gt;Amos Norton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bulky man, face covered with a heavy growth of beard, arose and peered at the trooper through thick-lensed spectacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Howdy, officer,” the man said pleasantly, glancing at Robberts’ black-striped breeches protruding from beneath the sheepskin coat. “Cold, ain’t it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Plenty,” agreed Robberts, throwing cap and coat upon the bunk. “I’m looking for a place to hole up for the night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You’ve hit it,” the bearded man returned cordially. “My name’s Fred Dorgan. Been trapping some here, tryin’ to make out the winter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any luck?” asked Robberts idly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorgan pointed with pride to several rows of furs hanging across the walls of the cabin. “Not bad. Average catch, I’d say. Take it easy while I rustle up a little grub. What takes you out this weather, if it isn’t an official secret?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No secret,” the trooper said easily, “in fact, you may be able to help me. I’m Corporal Robberts, state trooper, from the Malone barracks. A bunch of us have been busy the past week searching for that big transport plane that crashed somewhere in the mountains. I happened to be assigned this territory. Haven’t heard or seen anything of a crash around here, have you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorgan shook his head as he sliced bacon into a frying pan. “Nope, but that don’t mean that the plane couldn’t have cracked up not far away. Here in the cabin, with the wind howling outside, sounds don’t carry from very far. Any passengers in the plane?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robberts shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, just the pilot and co-pilot. The ship was carrying a bank shipment of currency though, and there’s been a great row raised about it.” He fished a paper from his pocket and opened it. “Pilot Walter Amsden, thirty-two, slender, brown hair. Copilot Frank Monroe, twenty-six, tall, redheaded. That’s their description.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell you what,” Dorgan volunteered, “I’ll make the rounds of my line early in the morning, then go out with you. We might stumble on something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short time later Robberts pushed back from the crude table and reached for his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some one took a pop at me with a rifle, back in the timber tonight,” he said casually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trooper fished the cartridge from his pocket, and rising, crossed to where a Winchester hung on the wall. But the weapon was a .30-30, and. the empty shell in his hand was a .32-40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who’s got a grudge against the troopers up here?” Robberts snapped abruptly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorgan hesitated. “No one I know of, unless—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unless what?” barked the trooper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to get any innocent party in trouble,” Dorgan said uneasily, “but there’s a queer old nut a few miles north of here that’s apt to do most anything. Took a crack at me one day.” “What’s his name?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Amos Norton,” Dorgan answered, “he’s got a .32-40 rifle, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve heard of him,” Robberts said grimly. “One of the patrols brought him in to the precinct one day for poaching. He swore then he’d kill the next trooper he met in the woods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, if we’re going to hunt for that crash in the morning, we’d better turn in,” said Dorgan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not yet dawn when Dorgan returned from his inspection of his trap line, and a short time later both men were slogging through deep snow into the timber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve got only a few traps left out,” Dorgan explained his short absence before dawn. “Been thinkin’ of tryin’ a different part of the country. Old Man Norton ain’t what I call a desirable neighbor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short distance from Dorgan’s cabin Robberts called a halt. “We’ll separate here, and cover as much ground as possible. If either of us finds anything he can fire two quick shots to call the other. You tell me where Norton’s shack is, and we’ll meet near there, and pay the old boy a visit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-tri-motor&quot;&gt;The Tri-Motor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Dorgan had given detailed directions for finding Norton’s cabin, the two separated. For an hour Robberts followed the course of a small winding river. Suddenly, a small black object near the foot of a spruce caught his attention. Curiously, the trooper strode to the spot and looked down at a fine pine marten, securely imprisoned in a steel trap. The little animal was frozen stiff by the intense cold. Robberts examined the trap staring for a long moment at the initials scratched in the steel. When he straightened a long whistle of satisfaction escaped his lips. Mind busy with a dozen thoughts he resumed his search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forenoon was half gone when Corporal Robberts broke through a protecting fringe of brush and gazed out over the frozen expanse of a tiny lake. And in the center of the lake lay a heap of blackened wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hal drew his Colt and fired twice into the air before hurrying toward his find. When Dorgan came trotting across the little lake a short time later, Robberts was still examining the remains of what had once been a big tri-motored Douglas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What a way to die!” Dorgan whispered in horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was pointing at the snow-covered figure of a man sprawled a few yards from the wreck. Nodding in sombre agreement, Robberts turned the body over, gazed down into the features of a young man wearing the leather coat and goggles of a flyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s Co-pilot Monroe, all right,” Robberts muttered. “Must have been thrown clear and struck his head on the ice. See, there’s a bad wound there”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the pilot himself?” asked Dorgan. Robberts pointed to the ghastly little heap of bones, charred leather, and cloth that he had salvaged from the debris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s hope the crash killed him,” Dorgan mumbled nervously. “Let’s get away from here, corporal. This mess gives me the creeps!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You’ve forgotten something,” Robberts retorted. “There’s supposed to be a box of currency around here somewhere!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of fifteen minutes’ futile search Corporal Robberts gazed at Dorgan with a queer light in his steel-gray eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe it burned with the plane,” Dorgan ventured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Impossible,” snapped the trooper. “The box was fire-proof. Dorgan, there’s dirty’ work here. Some one’s salvaged $75,000 from this crash and made off with it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorgan said nothing, but his lips slowly framed a name. Robberts nodded, strapped the snowshoes again on his feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re making a little call right now on your friend, Amos Norton!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sun danced blindingly on dazzling white snow as the trooper and Dorgan cautiously approached Norton’s ramshackle cabin. A tenuous thread of smoke eddying from the crazy chimney was the only sign of life about the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hand on holstered Colt ready for instant action, Robberts boldly approached the cabin. A hard shove of his shoulder sent the rickety door flying wide open. Gun in hand, the state trooper lunged through the doorway, Dorgan at his heels. One brief look showed that the single-room cabin was empty. But a can of water simmered on the stove, and supplies and equipment were scattered carelessly everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Looks as if he’s coming back, anyway,” remarked Robberts. “Watch for him, Dorgan, while I take a look for that money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;aint-seen-no-plane&quot;&gt;Ain’t Seen No Plane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thorough search of the cabin revealed no trace of the missing currency. Robberts stepped outside and glanced keenly around the cabin walls. A sizable pile of firewood was stacked neatly against one end of the shack. The next moment the trooper began a systematic dismantling of the piled wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly he straightened, a gleam of triumph in his eyes. In his hand was a shiny metal box. The missing money container! Eagerly he opened it, peered inside. Crisp green bank notes, neatly packed in a small bundle, partially filled the box. Carefully Robberts counted them, whistling softly in satisfaction. Though only a small portion of the lost cash was in the box the tall man in uniform seemed hugely content as he hurried back into the cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Found part of it,” he jerked at the watching Dorgan. “Enough to convict the old fox, anyway. He’d hid it in the woodpile.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good!” Dorgan smiled, then—’’Look out! Norton’s coming!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robberts ducked down, then cautiously peered through the dirty window. A lanky old man was shuffling through the snow toward the cabin, rifle swinging from one hand. Dangling over one shoulder were the furry carcasses of a fox and several mink. As the trapper came closer Robberts stared with interest at the crafty, lined face and small, glittering eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amos Norton suddenly stopped, his eyes falling to the trampled tracks in the snow. At the same moment Robberts leaped through the doorway, his Colt swung up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put ‘em up, Norton!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an animal-like snarl Norton swung the rifle to his hip and fired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crashing report of the police .45 boomed upon the cold air as Norton’s bullet whistled inches away from the trooper’s head. As the rifle, smashed by the impact of the big revolver bullet, dropped from his hand, Norton leaped forward with a shrill cry, a long-bladed hunting knife springing like magic into his hand. Robberts was plunging at him, grimly shoving his gun back into the holster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shot cracked from the cabin door, missing Norton’s head narrowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop it, you fool!” the trooper yelled over his shoulder. “I’ll handle this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the trapper closed in, eyes gleaming with maniacal rage. He slashed once, downward, as the trooper ducked. The blade sliced the sleeve of the sheepskin coat from shoulder to elbow, then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robberts had the knife wrist in a grasp of iron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment the two men were locked in a motionless embrace of straining muscles. Norton’s strength was enormous for a man of his age, and for a moment Robberts was hard put to hold his own. Then with a lightning twist Robberts slid his free hand behind Norton’s neck, clamping it with his left upon the upraised knife hand. Exerting every ounce of muscle he possessed the trooper jerked. Norton fell heavily; the officer’s body dropped on top. A moment of furious scuffling in the snow and Robberts arose, dragging the manacled trapper with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bad business, Norton, shooting at an officer, and robbing wrecked airplanes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You dirty, interferin’ state cop!” Norton mouthed, spitting snow and invective from his snarling mouth. “I’m sorry I missed ye last night!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you admit shooting at me, and robbing the mail plane?” Robberts snapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What? What’s that about robbin’ a mail plane?” Well-feigned astonishment spread over the trapper’s dirty face. “Sure I shot at ye, and I’m sorry I missed! But I don’t know what you’re talking about when ye speak of a plane. I ain’t seen no plane!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robberts held the packet of money before Norton. “Ever see that before?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-pilot-of-the-douglas&quot;&gt;The Pilot Of The Douglas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The look of bewilderment vanished from Norton’s crafty features, to be replaced by fear. Abruptly he shut his traplike mouth and refused to speak again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No use in staying here any longer,” Robberts grunted to Dorgan. “Bring his gun and come on; we’ll’ stay tonight at your cabin and I’ll take him in in the morning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Dorgan’s cabin Robberts secured his captive firmly to the bunk, then turned to watch Dorgan as the big man built a fire in the rusty stove and started preparations for supper. When the simple meal was over, Robberts leaned his chair against the door and smoked for a moment lazily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hope you don’t have any trouble taking Norton in tomorrow,” Dorgan, said finally. “You just let me know when you want me to testify, and I’ll be on hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” the trooper drawled, “I don’t expect any trouble. Of course, handling a pair of prisoners isn’t a kid’s job, but I guess I can swing it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A pair of prisoners!” Dorgan wheeled in surprise. “Why, where’s your other one?” Robberts rose slowly to his feet, his right hand hooked carelessly in the wide cartridge belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Slow down, mister,” he shot back, all the softness gone from his voice. “I arrest you, Walter Amsden, for the murder of Fred Dorgan and Frank Monroe! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a pregnant moment the silence of death hung over the stuffy little room. Dorgan wheeled slowly from the stove, his face for a moment a malignant mask. Then his features relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’re you talking about, trooper? You’re telling me that I’m Amsden, the pilot of that Douglas? You’re crazy! Your own description of Amsden says he was a slender man with brown hair. Well, take a look at me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m looking at you,” Robberts said quietly. “You were pretty clever, Amsden, but you slipped up on two or three little things. I first became suspicious when I looked around while you were supposed to be making the rounds of your trap lines and found that there wasn’t a sign of extra clothing about the place. A slender man, who’d dyed his hair, might put on a lot of additional clothes to make himself look bigger. So I kept my eyes open. This morning I found a marten in a trap marked with Dorgan’s initials. That meant you didn’t know the location of Dorgan’s traps!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A fine lot of rot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, that isn’t all,” Robberts said placidly, “you interrupted me. You planned this ‘crash,’ Amsden, for some time, marking the location of both Dorgan’s and Norton’s cabins. You even had the dye to change the color of your hair with you. You simply landed on that lake, probably already having killed the co-pilot in his seat. You came to Dorgan, got all the information about him and Norton you could. Then you killed him, changed clothes with him, and after placing him in the plane and leaving Monroe clear for future identification, you burned the ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But just to make sure, you planted a small part of the money at Norton’s cabin. When he took a shot at me last night, he was playing right into your hands.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorgan, or Amsden; shifted his feet nervously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But here’s what’s going to send you to the chair, Amsden!” Robberts cried suddenly, pointing to the shiny money box. “Your big mistake was in leaving the money you planted on Norton still in the box. For the paint on that box wasn’t even scorched, showing it was taken from the plane, before the burning, not after! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;silence-like-a-bombshell&quot;&gt;Silence Like A Bombshell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the words fell upon the silence like a bombshell, the room erupted into violent action. With a lightning swing of his arm Amsden seized the pan of scalding dishwater from the stove and flung it straight at Robberts’ face. As the trooper attempted to duck his foot slipped and he went half to his knees. Half of the contents of the pan splashed agonizingly into his face, blinding him. Instinctively his finger contacted upon the trigger of the Colt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bullet smashed through the flimsy stove, scattering a shower of flaming coals upon the floor. Simultaneously the roaring form of Amsden crashed into the trooper, rocking him with flailing, vicious blows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He groped, once, for the gun dangling from its lanyard. Instantly Amsden’s fist closed on his wrist, while the pilot’s other muscular hand gripped the trooper’s throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a mighty effort Robberts brought his right knee up to Amsden’s stomach, shoved with all his strength. The murderer staggered, mouthing maniacal curses, suddenly whirled and lunged toward the rifle standing in a: comer. Frantically Robberts fumbled for his .45. Amsden’s rifle came up, leveled, just as the trooper’s hand closed over the butt of the Colt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red murder stared from Amsden’s glaring eyes as Robberts squeezed the trigger. Two thundering reports filled the cabin, pounded on Robberts’ ears through a fog of pain and powder smoke. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amsden slumped, completely cowed, in a comer, nursing a shattered shoulder. On the bunk old Amos Norton regarded the trooper with admiring eyes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By cracky, you state cops kin fight, at that,” he said excitedly. “I ain’t goin’ to crack down on a state policeman agin! I had you figured for a bunch of nosey snoopers, but anybody that kin figure out a mess like this is okay!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/the-masked-alibi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/the-masked-alibi/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Case of the Frivolous Wife</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have one, Janie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonia Priestly held out a large and freshly-opened box of liqueur chocolates to Jane Wilmot, her invalid husband’s nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurse Wilmot frowned. Unlike Sonia, there was nothing light and frivolous about her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What! At this time in the morning I” she declared frigidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonia laughed. “Go on, Janie. Do you good. Just like a pick-me-up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It seems such an awful waste of money to me. A big box like that just for one person.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, but I haven’t bought them. They’ve just come by the eleven o’clock post. A present, Janie—from an unknown admirer! Try one of the goldpaper ones—they’re Benedictine.” Almost grudgingly Nurse Wilmot put her hand into the box and took a liqueur chocolate wrapped in gold-coloured foil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You won’t tell Mr. Priestly, will you?” she said sharply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again Sonia laughed. “Oh, he won’t mind if you have a little pick-me-up,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t mean that, Mrs. Priestly. I mean about the unknown admirer! I’m sure it s none of my business how you behave towards other men, but it is my business when it affects my patient. And he’s looking much better today. If you tell him some man has sent you chocolates, it will only worry him and send up his temperature again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonia picked out a cherry brandy chocolate and popped it into her mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He never gets to know anything about my amusements through me,’ ’ slid said meaningly. “They’re quite harmless, anyway. Why shouldn’t I dance or go on the river if men my own age ask me to? John can’t expect me to sit beside his bed all day long. John–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly her voice stopped. Her hands darted to her throat, and she gave a strangled gasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurse Wilmot stared in horror at her patient’s young wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Priestly, what’s the matter?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I feel so—so–” But without another word Sonia collapsed on the floor and passed into a state of semi- consciousness. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later she was dead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-poisoned-chocolates&quot;&gt;The Poisoned Chocolates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hollis, the Priestlys’ medical attendant, was at the house within half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can’t understand it,” said Nurse Wilmot. “Ono minute she was talking to me as gay and happy-go-lucky as usual; the next, there she was stretched out on the floor. I should never have believed she’d got anything wrong with her. But there—you can’t tell with those that bum the candle at both ends, can you? Many’s the time she’s never come back to the house until two or three in the morning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was nothing wrong with Mrs. Priestly’s constitution,” said Dr. Hollis coldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing wrong! But–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Priestly was poisoned,” continued the medical man. “By one of the alkaloid group. Every symptom suggests it, and I’m certain an autopsy will prove it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse’s face paled. “Poisoned! It’s impossible. She—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Poisons of that type act quickly, as you probably know, nurse. What hliad Mrs. Priestly eaten just before she collapsed?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jane Wilmot leaned forward tensely. “Oh, it must have been the chocolates!” she declared. Her face went even whiter. “And I ate one myself— just before she did!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, yours couldn’t have been poisoned; you would have been in a coma by now. Chocolates, eh? Where did she get them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They came by the morning parcel post. From an unknown admirer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hollis went to the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The phone’s in the hall, isn’t it? The sooner the police are on this the better.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A minute later he returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How about Priestly?” he asked. “Has it given him a shock?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurse Wilmot shook her head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I haven’t told him,” she replied. “I wouldn’t take the responsibility of doing so. Poor man! It will upset him badly, I’m afraid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hollis went upstairs to break the news to the invalid John Priestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man took it almost without any show of emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How did it happen, doctor?” he asked quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hollis tried to introduce his suspicions lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But John Priestly’s brain was still the active brain of a young and clever man even if at sixty his body had failed him so miserably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You mean you suspect foul play? Poisoning?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctor nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priestly raised himself on the pillows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get Hawke for me—Dixon Hawke!” he said. “He’ll settle this in half the time the police will. Somewhere in Dover Street; you’ll find the number in the London telephone directory. Tell him to get here as quickly as he can. He’ll know my name—I employed him in several commercial cases. He’ll come.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very well, I’ll phone him right away,” said Dr. Hollis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixon Hawke and his assistant. Tommy Burke arrived little more than an hour later. They had flown to Shoreham airport and driven by road from there to John Priestly’s modern mansion on the South Downs six miles from Worthing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Denver, of the South Sussex constabulary, met him in the hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Hawke, you haven’t lost much time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke smiled. It was some five years since he had worked with Denver on a large-scale smuggling case, and he remembered that the inspector then had only thinly-concealed his distaste for unofficial assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guessed you’d have it all settled if I didn’t get down quickly, Inspector,” he said lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denver Hushed. “This isn’t the sort of case for quick results. We shall have to do a lot of donkey work before we get on the right track. But we’ll find it all right; the police organisation can’t fail in a crime of this type.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Meaning you don’t think it’s a job for me?” murmured Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector shrugged his shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, no offence, Hawke, but one man can’t possibly investigate all the possibilities there are in this affair— not in the time the police will take, anyway. You see, this Mrs. Priestly had plenty of enemies. One of them sent her a box of poisoned chocolates. Well, we shall make a list of suspects and then tackle each one of them for an alibi for the time when the chocolates were handed in at the post office.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Splendid,” declared the famous criminologist. “In that case I shall earn my fee without having to do much work for it. I’ll join you later, Inspector. I must go and report my arrival to my old friend, John Priestly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy Burke followed him to the foot of the staircase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hang around, Tommy,” said Hawke, “and keep your ears open for facts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-invalid&quot;&gt;The Invalid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upstairs in the invalid’s bedroom Hawke was distressed to see the feeble physical condition of the man whom he had once considered to be the fittest and most alert director in the City. But he soon realised that John Priestly had lost none of his old mental qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I should never have married Sonia, Hawke. I freely admit it. But perhaps she never had a fair chance; I became a bedridden invalid just four months after we were married. She was only thirty—it was only natural she should want to enjoy herself elsewhere and with people of her own age. Had I remained fit and active we should have travelled—seen the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Priestly sighed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As it has turned out, I hardly saw her save for a few minutes each day. You see, I don’t need a wife, Hawke; only a nurse and occasional visits from Harley Street. I can’t pretend that I loved my wife—I was disappointed in her, to be perfectly frank. I felt that she might have spared me a little more of the time she so readily gave to—to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But someone has killed her, Hawke! And I will spare no expense until that someone is brought to trial! That is why I sent for you. Whether her death means less to me than people would think or not, she was under my protection and under my roof when she was poisoned!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve no suspicions, sir?” asked Hawke quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man shook his head sadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“None. Ever since we came here I have been confined to this room. I know nothing of her friends—or her enemies. I know very little, too, of her past; we were married within two month of our first meeting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment the door opened. Hawke turned his head sharply to see a nurse with a dark, sallow face peering in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My nurse,” explained Priestly. “She’ll tell you more than I can about Sonia. She was with her when it happened. In fact, she might have been poisoned herself—she had one of the chocolates–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, you mustn’t upset yourself, Mr. Priestly,” broke in Nurse Wilmot. “You’ve your own health to consider, you know–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Mr. Dixon Hawke, Janie. He’s going to settle this dreadful business for us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse nodded coldly, as if already accusing Hawke of disturbing her patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d like to ask you a few questions later, nurse,” said Hawke as he left the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;tracing-the-parcel&quot;&gt;Tracing the Parcel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downstairs again the private detective asked Inspector Denver if he could see the box of chocolates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can tell you all there is to know about them,” said Denver, waving his hand to a large oblong box on the table. “Eight different kinds of liqueur chocolates—but only one kind has been tampered with. The cherry brandy ones have all got a little hole drilled in them from underneath.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke nodded. “So the murderer must have known Mrs. Priestly well enough to know that she particularly liked cherry brandy, and would probably take one of them first, as she did. What about the wrappings of the box?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denver produced a large piece of brown paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This was in the wastepaper basket,” he said. “Postmarked at Brighton. We shall trace it back to where it was handed in, with any luck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke examined the blurred markings across the stamp. The parcel had been handled at the sorting office at 7.30 p.m. the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The paper’s ordinary enough,” he commented. “Thousands of pieces like it everywhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Denver smiled. “Yes, I thought that even a private detective wouldn’t get a clue out of that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the string?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just the same—ordinary common or garden string.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector produced a length of string from his pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see that it was cut and not untied,” Hawke remarked while he examined the knot still left in the string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, what of that? Did you ever see a woman open a parcel patiently? Of course she cut it–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” said Hawke, coolly, “but what a good thing for us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without attempting to explain himself, he handed the length of string back to Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector stared at him with a puzzled, almost annoyed, expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re still working on your list of possible enemies, I suppose?” Hawke went on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denver grunted. “Yes. And I don’t mind saying it means a long job. Sonia Priestly seems to have spent most of her time playing about with the emotions of half Sussex. Fortunately she kept all her correspondence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then suppose I tackle the sorting office at Brighton? The box made rather an unusual shaped parcel—we ought to be able to trace it back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Denver hesitated. “Well, I was going to send Sergeant Welsh over there this afternoon, but–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Chief Constable won’t object to my going surely?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, all right,” snapped Denver. “I’ll tell Welsh to go over with you now. There’s no point in it until we’ve established a list of suspects, but you might as well be doing something, I suppose.” Hawke chuckled. “Self-importance in a policeman,” he mused, “is the criminal’s best friend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Brighton postal sorting office, however, he found officialdom more impressed by the mention of his famous name. Clerks and postmen set up lines of inquiry immediately they saw the parcel temporarily rewrapped in its original shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took time, but eventually results were forthcoming. The parcel had been collected by the van calling at the suboffices of Bream Road, Finch Street, Albert Road, Downs Avenue, and Royal Street. But the postman could not remember at which post office he had picked it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke and Sergeant Welsh at once proceeded to each of these branches of the postal service in turn. At Bream Road they were definitely told the parcel had not been handed in there. At Finch Street they found uncertainty. Albert Road and Downs Avenue, however, were quite sure they hadn’t handled it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We might have known it would be the last on the list,” said Hawke. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sub-postmistress at Royal Street remembered the parcel well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Usually people want us to weigh parcels, but this one was handed in already stamped. I said I’d check it, but the woman said she knew it was all right, and walked out before I’d even put it on the scales.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And it was correctly stamped?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, so I put it under the counter and thought no more about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What was this lady like?” asked Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hardly saw her. I’m afraid. She just handed it in and then went. She was dressed in dark clothes—a costume, I think, but I wouldn’t like to say for sure. Her face was painted more than any woman’s ought to be, that I will say! Only she came and went so quickly, and this is a busy shop.’’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Of course,” said Hawke gently. “About what height was she?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Average, I’d say. She wasn’t especially tall or short.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How about her build? Was she slim or stout?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just ordinary, I think, sir. She might have been a bit on the lean side rather than plump, if you know what I mean. But I wouldn’t be telling the truth if I said more than that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke smiled encouragingly. “I wish all witnesses we have to question would confine themselves to just what they are certain of and no more,” ha said. “Now, how about the time? Can you tell us when she called?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The postmistress looked happier. “Yes, sir, I can help you there. It must have been after half-past five because the parcel missed that collection; and before six because that’s when I go for my tea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Between five-thirty and six, eh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, and I’d say at a guess about a quarter to six, and I don’t think I’d be far out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Splendid. You’d never seen her before, of course?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, no, sir. An absolute stranger to these parts she was.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dover Street detective thanked her for her assistance, then left with Sergeant Welsh to drive back to the house on the Downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You noticed that the postmistress herself wasn’t averse to a pretty liberal use of lipstick?” said Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sergeant nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Therefore the woman who posted the parcel must have been excessively over-painted. One devotee of the cosmetics industry rarely criticises another without fair cause.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;wanteda-girl-guide&quot;&gt;Wanted—A Girl Guide!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was past three when they returned to Priestly s house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Hawke,” said Inspector Denver sarcastically, “do you know who we’ve got to arrest yet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixon Hawke shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector produced a sheet of notepaper on which was written a number of names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of those seven people sent the chocolates,” he announced. “Seven people in this district who have good reason to hate Sonia Priestly. Four wives whose husbands she had played about with and whose homes you can therefore say she’d seriously threatened; one girl whose fiancé she had captivated, and so caused the breaking of a previously happy engagement; and two men who, judging from their letters, didn’t like the way she’d dropped them stone cold without reason. Now you see—we’ll soon nail down one of those seven, Hawke. Hard work and routine investigation—none of the flash- of-genius business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criminologist glanced at the list. “Well, you can cross off the two men, Denver, because that parcel was posted by a woman.” He told the inspector the details. “And, if I were you,” he added casually, “I’d find out which of the five women have been Girl Guides.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Girl Guides!” exclaimed the inspector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke chuckled. “I don’t think it will help you much, though, because my suspect isn’t on your list. But if I’m wrong—well, it might.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked away to find Tommy Burke, and hear whether the youngster had anything to report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy was run to earth busily chatting with the chauffeur in the garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Tommy, any finds?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke’s assistant looked glum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing much, guv’nor. Inspector Denver hasn’t allowed me to do a thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I thought he’d be a bit unfriendly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been getting round the servants, though, and they’re all worked up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Naturally. A murder is–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy Burke’s eyes lit up excitedly. For once he was a jump ahead of Ins brilliant “guv’nor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, not so much that. They’re all furious the way the nurse has taken charge of the whole house. She’s giving orders to the cook and the maids, and they can’t stand it. Besides, they haven’t been told to acknowledge her authority, so–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good, Tommy,” broke in Hawke. “Just what I expected, if my theory is correct. But I hardly expected it so soon. What a pity for Denver that he hasn’t noticed it himself. Right under his nose, too.” Hawke leaned forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tommy, find out as quickly as you can whether Nurse Wilmot had the afternoon off yesterday, and, if she did, at what time she got back here. I’ll wait for you here. I don’t want to make a further move until I know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can soon find out about that,” said Burke, dashing off to the back of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five minutes later he was back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, guv’nor,” he exclaimed. “She was off duty, and she didn’t get back until after seven!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke smiled grimly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, Tommy, I want you to indulge in a little burglary. While I’m questioning Nurse Wilmot downstairs, get into her room and see if you can find any lipsticks or other cosmetics. You may only find a handkerchief on which paint has been wiped off. If you’re successful, don’t wait—come downstairs and interrupt us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again Tommy Burke sped away towards the back of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixon Hawke went indoors and waited in the lounge while a servant took a message to Nurse Wilmot asking her if she could spare him a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-clue-of-the-cosmetics&quot;&gt;The Clue of the Cosmetics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later the nurse entered the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can’t leave Mr. Priestly for long,” she said sharply. “I shouldn’t have left him at all after the shock he’s had to-day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From what I know of John Priestly,” said Hawke calmly, “he can still survive mental or emotional shocks. And a very good thing, too, for he may receive another shock before the day is out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse gave a nervous start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What—what do you mean, Mr. Hawke?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean that I think I know who sent the poisoned chocolates to Sonia Priestly—and why! Nurse, a woman posted that parcel yesterday at Brighton. I understand that you were off duty during the afternoon. May I ask how you spent your time and where?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse’s face went ashen grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have no right to ask such a question—no right at all! Why should I have questions asked about where I’ve been? I had one of the chocolates myself—it might have been me who was poisoned, not her–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoever put poison into those chocolates, nurse, knew quite well that only one kind had been tampered with. Where were you yesterday between five and six?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I went to the pictures. I can’t prove it. I went alone. No—no. I never went to Brighton at all. Why are you daring to suspect me? Why should I want to kill Sonia?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You had a strong motive for desiring Mrs. Priestly’s removal,” said Hawke smoothly. “Priestly is worth at least half a million, but I’m afraid he’s not going to live very long to enjoy it. As an invalid he needed you far more than he needed a young and flighty wife. With Sonia Priestly dead, you could easily persuade him to marry you, and, since he would then have no one else to whom he could leave his money, you would soon inherit that considerable fortune. Elderly and lonely invalids marry their nurses very often, don’t they, Nurse Wilmot?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is insufferable! Mr. Hawke, I–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But not unreasonable. Why, already I understand you have assumed the management of the house!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will complain to Mr. Priestly. How dare you throw servants’ tittle-tattle into my face like that!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment the door burst open and Tommy Burke dashed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here’s what you wanted, guv’nor!” he exclaimed excitedly. “Plenty of make-up material and the handkerchiefs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixon Hawke looked gravely at four sticks of cosmetic paint and three handkerchiefs stained from the removal of heavy applications of make-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You—you’ve been to my room?” cried the nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see. You admit that these are yours then?” said Hawke. “Strange, for you never use cosmetics normally. But what a neat method of disguising yourself if you wanted to for any purpose—such as posting a parcel at Royal Street, Brighton! That woman was heavily made up, Nurse Wilmot!” Jane Wilmot breathed heavily. For a moment she stood and stared at the criminologist with blazing hatred in her eyes. Then she fell into a chair and began to sob bitterly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I did it!” she burst out suddenly. “I hated her I She meant nothing to him—nothing. I was the one who looked after him while she deceived him. Why should she have got all his money when he died—for nothing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke turned to his assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tommy, go and fetch Inspector Denver and tell him the case is ended!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-knot-is-untied&quot;&gt;The “Knot” is Untied&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hour later Inspector Denver was in a very subdued mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But what beats me is how you got on to it, Hawke. It was pure guesswork, wasn’t it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was the string,” smiled Hawke. “You see, the parcel had been tied with a reef knot. And people don’t tie reef knots unless they have been trained to do so. Sailors, Boy Scouts, Girl Guides, firemen, and so on. And once I found it was a woman who had posted the parcel, I was almost certain it was Nurse Wilmot, because it’s a stem rule in hospitals that all slings and bandages are tied with reef knots I” “That’s what you meant about the Girl Guides, was it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke chuckled. “Yes. If Nurse Wilmot had an alibi that she could prove, I thought that perhaps one of your ladies on the list might have learnt to tie a reef knot that way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Denver coughed and cleared his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/the-case-of-the-frivolous-wife/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/the-case-of-the-frivolous-wife/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Case of the Duelling Pistols</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t kill him, Mr. Hawke! I swear I didn’t kill him!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foxy Lee’s rattish face was grey with fright. It was quiet in the interview room at Wandsworth Jail, and the little crook’s voice roused strange echoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He was dead when I broke in!” Foxy went on, beads of perspiration gathering on his forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told the truth to the inspector. I didn’t kill Michael Martin!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy,” Dixon Hawke said. “I’ll help you if I can, but the evidence against you is pretty black.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The famous criminologist had been called to the jail by the personal appeal of the prisoner, who was well known to him. Foxy was a crook, but a second-rater. He had carried out small robberies, but had never committed any crime of much magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now he was charged with murder —charged with the death of Michael Martin, and with enough evidence against him to hang a dozen men. They had found his fingerprints on the pistol by the side of the body. They had found his jemmy and other tools scattered on the floor. And Foxy had made a confession of breaking in with intent to rob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I didn’t kill the cove!” ho whimpered. “I tell you what happened, Mr. Hawke. I lifted a window and went in. There was just one light in the room, and that was shaded. I saw a pistol on the floor, and picked it up. Then I saw the—the body! I dropped the pistol and done a bolt!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, Foxy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every word’s true. They’ll ’ang me if you don’t do something! I didn’t kill him! I didn’t!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criminologist looked at the little man. If Foxy was acting the part of an innocent man, he was certainly doing it cleverly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re as crooked as they’re made,” the criminologist said, “but I don’t think you’d do murder. I’ll try my best to get you out of this mess.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bless you, Mr. ’Awke. You’re a real gent—straight! –Not like that inspector, who don’t care nothing so long as he gets the rope round my neck!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s enough!” growled Inspector Meadows, the C.I.D. officer responsible for the arrest. “I don’t want to see an innocent man hanged, but I think we’ve got the right chap in you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warder came to take Foxy away. Dixon Hawke and the inspector left the jail. The latter was half-defiant as they entered the car which had brought them to Wandsworth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They don’t call him Foxy without reason,” he suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, he’s clever, Meadows, but there are some queer facts in this case to be studied.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Meaning?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The weapon that killed Martin, for example.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was a duelling pistol. Martin had many queer things in his house. His real name, by the way, was Micha Martinez. He came originally from Moravia, and was naturalised as a British subject five years ago.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A curious character, I believe. I’d very much like to see the room where he was killed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have the keys to the house in my pocket. We’ve removed the body for the inquest, but everything else is as the housekeeper found it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She was away the night of the crime?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Her master had sent her away over the week-end, and he was alone in the place.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-bullet-in-the-wall&quot;&gt;The Bullet in the Wall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house was midway between Hampstead and Golders Green, standing at the edge of the wide heath. Inspector Meadow’s unlocked the doors and showed the way to the room where Martin had been killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an enormous room, dating back to the spacious days of the Victorians. The length was over fifty feet, and it was a good twenty wide. A thick carpet was underfoot, and the walls were hung with rich tapestries. The furniture was somewhat disarranged and moved back from the centre of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We found it like this,” Meadows said. “I don’t quite understand what Martin had been up to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where was he lying?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Over there by the window. The curtains were drawn, and the lamp near the fireplace turned on. The bullet had caught him above the heart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A duelling pistol, you say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ho has a collection of them. I think he must have been loading the weapon when Foxy came in. Possibly there was a struggle. The weapon was fired from a good forty feet, so I think Foxy had taken it from him and was making for the door when he lost his nerve and pulled the trigger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you found the pistol near the body r&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our man probably put it there in the hope the thing would look like suicide–”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In that case why did he leave his housebreaking tools scattered on the floor?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Meadows grunted, but did not answer. Hawke turned away, and began a careful search of the room. First, he examined the case containing the collection of pistols. They were all there except the one that had been found with the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One by one he picked them up. The pistols smelt of oil, and were in excellent condition. A number of bullets were in the collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bullets were round, and cast with all the care of the old-time gunsmith. For a long time the criminologist stood examining the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are spaces for twelve bullets,” he said at last. “Did you notice that two were missing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We found one in Martin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the other?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was probably lost long ago.” Hawke took one of the pistols. Slowly he moved to the chalk marks on the floor which showed the position in which the dead man had been found. He turned and faced the length of the room, raising his arm with the pistol extended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His eye was keen as he looked along the barrel. The weapon poised with exquisite balance. Hawke could see the tapestry-hung wall beyond the foresight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the hanging represented a pastoral scene. A goatherd played his pipes and a young kid skipped in the background. There was a tree with birds flying in and out of the foliage. Something queer about one of those birds, the investigator noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then a cry of astonishment burst from Hawke’s lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The other bullet! ” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurrying across the room he put a chair against the wall and climbed on to it. Carefully he moved the tapestry, and a shower of fine plaster fell from behind it. He began to dig with the blade of a knife, and presently a rounded lump of lead was in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you explain it?” he asked Meadows. “Did Martin have two pistols loaded and fire one at Foxy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m blessed if I know! ” The C.I.D. officer was mortified at the discovery of the bullet. “I searched thoroughly,” he added, “but I didn’t think of looking in that wall.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The angle of the shot was upward. Even if Martin had been lying on the floor ho couldn’t have put the ball where I found it. Something deflected it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can see faint stains on the lead. I notice spots on the carpet redder than the dye. If you have a test made, I am sure you will find traces of human blood 1 ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But there’s no mark on Foxy! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Quite—and I’m ready to bet that the little crook is innocent 1 ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-visitor-from-moravia&quot;&gt;A Visitor from Moravia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second bullet was a valuable clue, but at that the new line of investigation was halted. It had already been established that nobody had hoard the firing of the shots. The house stood alone at the edge of the heath and it was easy to enter or leave the place without being seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing in front of a cabinet, the criminologist looked at some photographs in silver frames. He picked up one which showed a group of officers in the smart uniforms of the Moravian Army. Meadows crossed to Hawke’s side and looked over his shoulder at the photograph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Martin is the one on the left,” ho volunteered. “Before he came to this country he was an officer in the Royal Guard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the man whose arm is linked in his is General Riccardo Pablo,” supplemented Hawke. “I saw his photograph in the papers a few days ago when he came here with a military mission. I wonder what caused Martinez to give up such a fine career and change his nationality?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know, Hawke—and it will be almost impossible to find out,” said Inspector Meadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll look into that myself. I’ll be glad, by the way, if you will have the two bullets and the collection of duelling pistols examined by an expert. You can got that done quickly?” rapped Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Certainly. What do you expect to find out?” asked the inspector, feeling more curious than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That the bullets were fired from different pistols! That one of the weapons in the case has been recently cleaned and oiled!” announced Hawke, his eyes glittering with excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Meadows blinked in astonishment. He was bewildered by the rapid developments in what had appeared to be a simple case. The officer shook his head as he went to the telephone and called Scotland Yard. Hawke’s strange requests were to be satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the scene of the tragedy, the criminologist returned to his Dover Street chambers. He ordered his assistant, Tommy Burke, to bring him the files of newspapers for the past three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journals came from all parts of Europe, those of Paris and Berlin arriving at Dover Street on the day of publication. Hawke knew several languages, and gleaned valuable information from his study of the foreign press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An English paper reported the arrival of the Moravian military mission, headed by General Pablo. Its business had been quickly accomplished, but the officers had stayed for various entertainments arranged for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Moravia was represented at Aider—shot by Colonel Battisti,” Hawke read. “General Pablo flew to Paris unexpectedly this morning. No explanation has been given for his sudden departure, but he is not expected to return.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The date of the paper was the previous day, an early evening edition. The criminologist then turned to the French file and worked through the columns of the “Paris Soir,” the popular newspaper of that city. He found what he was looking for on an inside page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“General Pablo, of Moravia, who has been in England, arrived by air at Le Bourget this afternoon. His visit was unexpected, and there was no reception. He left in a closed car for the Hotel du Roi”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the “Matin ” of that morning’s date there was another brief paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“General Pablo is confined to his apartment at the Hotel du Roi by a bad chill. He is being attended by a doctor from the Moravian Embassy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawke cut out the paragraphs and put them in his wallet. He spent some time walking up and down the room, his usually pale cheeks flushed with excitement. When the telephone rang in the other room he reached the instrument before Tommy Burke could lift the receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Meadows was on the wire. The C.I.D. man was excited. He could hardly control himself as he reported the findings of the firearms expert at Scotland Yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You must be a wizard, Hawke! The bullet you found in the wall was fired from one of the guns in the collection. It was carefully cleaned and oiled before being put back in the case.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Excellent! And do you think Foxy would have thought of that?” asked Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m blessed if I know! The evidence was all against him a few hours ago, but now he’s got a good defence,” said the inspector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about the stains on the carpet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;” It’s human blood all right. Somebody was hurt, but it wasn’t Foxy. The thing that puzzles me is this. If two guns were fired, why was the one that killed Martin found by his body and the one he apparently used cleaned and put away?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think the killer planned to clean both guns, but his wound made it necessary for him to leave. Either that, or he was forced to clear off when Foxy arrived,” Hawke suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the detective hesitated a moment. Meadows called his name several times before he replied, and then it was with a request as surprising as any he had made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can I have the gun and bullet packed and sent to meet me at Croydon?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘‘Croydon? What’s the idea, Hawke?” gasped Inspector Meadows, becoming more and more puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m taking the plane for Paris,” the criminologist answered. “I need the gun as—as a visiting-card, Meadows. As a visiting card! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;at-the-hotel-du-roi&quot;&gt;At the Hotel du Roi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Dixon Hawke, the French capital was as familiar as London. When the bus from Le Bourget dropped him at the air terminus on the Rue George V’., he strolled slowly along the boulevard to the great Place du Concorde. Under his arm was a small package which he had passed unopened through the Customs with the aid of his Scotland Yard credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For once the criminologist had no intention of asking for the aid of his French friends in the Sûreté. What he had come to do was entirely unofficial. He hesitated before entering the Hotel du Roi, but finally approached the desk and made an inquiry concerning General Pablo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I regret,” said the clerk, “the General does not receive visitors. He is ill.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I read in the papers,” Hawke said. “But it is very important that I sec him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clerk spoke on the telephone. Shortly afterwards a swarthy man of military appearance stepped from the lift. He introduced himself as the Moravian’s aide-de-camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is quite impossible,” he said. “The General is confined to his bed with a bad chill. If you will leave your card, perhaps an interview can be arranged later.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is my card,” Hawke said, holding out the flat case under his arm. “If you will give it to the General I’ll wait for his reply. I think he will sec me at once.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young officer bowed and went away. Hawke paced the lobby, his hands gripped behind his back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several minutes passed and then the clerk called him. He was requested to go up to the General’s apartment. Following the dapper page, he walked down a broad corridor and was admitted to a suite of rooms by the same swarthy aide-de-camp he had met a few minutes previously. There was a look of alarm on the man’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you please,” he said, opening the door of an inner room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-full-confession&quot;&gt;A Full Confession&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fine room, lighted by the bright evening sky. In a chair near the windows sat a tall and dignified man. He wore a dressing-gown over his pyjamas, and the detective noticed that his left arm was in a sling. As Hawke entered, lie gazed at him intently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am General Pablo,” he said. “You wish to see me? I understand that I am talking to Mr. Dixon Hawke.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I regret troubling you, General, but the matter is of some importance,’’ said Hawke grimly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I understand from your—er— visiting-card.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Moravian tapped the open case lying on the table. The pistol and misshapen bullet were open to view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your ‘cards’ are dangerous,” ho said reflectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In some hands. General. Such a * card ’ as this killed Micha Martinez, with whom I believe you were acquainted,” said Hawke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective looked at the man’s haggard face. It was with difficulty that ho forced the next words from his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did he shoot first?” he asked the General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before the clock struck for the signal. He was treacherous to the last! You know all, Mr. Hawke?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most of it. You went to Martinez and challenged him to a duel. The pistols were loaded and you fired from opposite ends of the room. His shot, I gather, struck your shoulder and was deflected upwards to the wall, where I found it. Yours, fired a second later, found his heart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Correct!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You started to clean the guns, hoping thereby to bewilder the police, but were interrupted by the arrival of a thief. You dropped the gun you had not cleaned near the body of Martinez, and hid. Afterwards you went away and left for Paris as quickly as possible. And an innocent man is accused of murder! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A troubled look showed in the Moravian’s eyes for a moment, and then he pushed a thick envelope towards the accuser. It was addressed to Scotland Yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Full confession,” he said. “I could do nothing else. The reason for the duel I cannot explain in detail. It concerns a lady—five years ago, when Martinez was my brother officer. He was a rat, Mr. Hawke! Is there any need for me to explain? I challenged him, but he ran from Moravia. When I came to London I sought him out and begged him to return to meet me in the proper manner. He refused, and then I saw the pistols. I repeat, he was more than a rat! I have no regrets—except for the man who was blamed for my action ! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words were spoken with considerable force, and the General sank back weakly in the chair when he had finished. Hawke stood before him, the envelope containing the confession between his fingers. It was a difficult moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had no reason to doubt the Moravian. The man’s tale of what had happened was perfectly true. Doubtless, too, Martinez had deserved to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But taking the law into one’s hands was a crime in England. General Pablo would be charged with manslaughter, perhaps murder, if the confession was put in the hands of Scotland Yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-present-from-foxy&quot;&gt;A Present from Foxy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will come with you to England if you wish,” the General said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not yet,” Hawke said. He had made up his mind. “I want your word as a soldier that you will not leave this hotel until I wire you permission. I am returning alone. If nothing else can save Foxy Lee, I must give the police your confession.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am at .your orders, Mr. Hawke ! ” The General rose to his feet. He stood at attention while the criminologist went to the door. It was a rare moment for Dixon Hawke, who actually regretted that he had succeeded in unravelling the mystery of the second bullet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his return to England, Hawke called Inspector Meadows at the Yard. The C.I.D. officer was in a cheerful mood, and asked him to come round at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” he said, rubbing his hands, “while you’ve been making mysteries I’ve been solving ’em ! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Solving them. Inspector?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You played a big part in it, Hawke. Foxy Lee has been released. It is quite obvious that Martinez shot himself I ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Eh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have discovered he used to practise shooting with his pistols. On the night in question he fired one weapon, and you found the bullet in the wall. He cleaned the gun and put it away. The second weapon went off accidentally and killed him. What do you think of the theory?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixon Hawke thrust his hands into his pockets. He felt the thick envelope containing the confession. It was a long time before he spoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Congratulations, Meadows,” ho said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you agree? We’re not so stupid at the Yard, after all, eh? And what about your crazy trip to Paris?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was just a crazy trip! ” Dixon Hawke said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days later a small package arrived at Dover Street. The criminologist opened it at the breakfast table, and whistled as he took out a valuable tiepin. A scrap of paper, containing a message pencilled in an uneducated hand, was wrapped around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re a gent!” he read. “You got me off having my neck stretched. Here’s something to show you my thanks! ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signature was that of Foxy Lee, and Hawke laughed as he examined the pin and then passed it over to his assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks from the criminal world ! ” he said. “Will you please check this up with the list of stolen property. Tommy? I’m very interested to know whom I must thank for Foxy’s gift!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/the-case-of-the-duelling-pistols/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/the-case-of-the-duelling-pistols/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Side Up</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;first-farmers-bank&quot;&gt;First Farmers Bank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long, sleek limousine rolled slowly to a halt in front of the First Farmers Bank of New Albany, Indiana. The liveried negro chauffeur started to turn off the ignition when a sharp, thin voice from the rear seat froze his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leave her running, George.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Y-yes, suh!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get out and go into the bank—slowly f I’ll be right in back of you. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, suh. I—I understand.” George’s face was a little pale as he got out of the car and walked slowly, as directed, through the door of the bank. Though there was a cool breeze, sweat beaded his forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind him the expensive car disgorged incongruously a stocky kid, not over sixteen, his cheap checked suit tightly buttoned and his cap peaked down to shade his face. Both his hands dug deep in the pockets of his coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were few passersby on Main Street that afternoon in 1948, and they paid no attention to the chauffeur or the youth who followed him. Within the bank, the tellers were beginning to lounge. It was near closing time. The bank guard leaned his elbow contemplatively on the grilled window behind which Henry Green was counting his money. Mr. Smythe, gray-haired president of the bank, placed a paperweight carefully on the report he had been reading, and got up from behind his desk. He had an appointment to play golf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton, the guard, turned as he heard the bank door open. George, the chauffeur, entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, George,” grinned Horton. “You almost didn’t make it; bank’s getting ready to close.” Everyone knew George. He chauffeured for Mr. Jones, owner of the big steel mill over in Louisville, just across the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But George didn’t answer with his usual ready smile. His face was rigid, imploring; he moved forward stiffly as though propelled irresistibly from behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong?” demanded the guard in surprise. Then: “Hey!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stocky kid had swung suddenly into view. The cap was low over his eyes. A gun thrust forward in his hand. “Up with your hands, you blankety-blank so-and-so!” he said in a high, bleak voice. “If you make a move, I’ll drill you, so help me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton’s fingers dropped away from his holster; his arms lifted slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the rest of you,” snarled the kid. “Stand still and shut up. Where’s Smythe, the president of this bank?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Smythe stood at his desk. He held himself carefully. “I’m Mr. Smythe,” he said; “if you think you can hold up this bank you’re—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up! Turn around and open that safe in back of you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look here, you can’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Open that safe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smythe braced himself. “I won’t,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid fired. Sharp sound filled the bank. Smythe jerked forward, staggered and fell headlong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horton gasped, dropped his right arm swiftly in a desperate attempt for his gun. The kid swerved; sound. again blasted the walls. The guard’s fingers uncurled, and the half-drawn gun dropped with a clatter to the floor. He followed it, shuddered and lay still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even as the reverberation of gunfire echoed from the marble, a new sound blasted with insistent clamor. The urgent shout of the alarm bell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid shoved his gun at the frightened teller. “You lousy son,” he screamed. “You asked for it” A single shot pierced the stridency of the alarm. Henry Green, his foot still on the buzzer, crumpled out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid backed toward the door, the smoking pistol covering his retreat. “You!” he stabbed at George. “Get the hell out there into the car. And no funny work. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—I understand.” Ashen-faced, the breath sobbing in his lungs, the chauffeur stumbled out into the light&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gunman waited until he heard him open the car door. Then he spun around, raced for the limousine, flung himself into the back seat “Drive like hell! I’ll tell you where to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind him was a shambles: three dead men, panic and the senseless clangor of the alarm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;we-gotta-get-the-facts-sister&quot;&gt;We Gotta Get The Facts, Sister&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson, ace reporter of the Louisville Courier Journal, bent over the dying man. It was hard to hear his words. His chest swathed in bandages to hide the_ gaping wound and keep the ebbing life within a little longer, rose and fell in labored spasms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hospital nurse said: “You two will have to be brief; talking isn’t good for him,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lt. Dave Hunt of the New Albany police said gruffly: “We gotta get the facts, sister. Go ahead, Al. See if you can make out what he’s saying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al bent even closer. His voice was gentle, sympathetic. “This is tough on you, George, but it’s important. Do you think you’ll be able to tell me the story?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wounded man opened his eyes, tried to gather his strength. “I’ve got to, Mr. Aronson,” he whispered. “The killer—he’s only a kid—but he’s killed four men and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Three, George.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sad smile flitted over the Negro’s drawn face. “Four, Mr. Aronson,” he corrected. “I know I’m through. But—I was waiting over in Louisville to pick up my boss when this kid puts a gun to me, an’ makes me drive him over the bridge to New Albany. When we came to the bank—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shudder coursed through the dying man. He shut his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save your strength,” said Aronson. “We know that part; what happened after?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That kid was mad—mean mad when we got back in the car. I’ve heard cursing before, but never like that. He was filthy-mouthed. Cursed the men he’d killed, cursed the alarm system, cursed me. And in between curses he kept directing me—turn down First Street, then into Cranberry, left on Lake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson nodded. “Knew the town, eh, George?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, suh. He sure did. I was scared silly, but I tried ta fool him. Kept making mistakes, twisted wrong, tried to get him in front of the police station. I expected to smash the car and yell for help, but—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He knew better,” Aronson interjected softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George stared up at the reporter, his face sweating with the memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Knew every twist an’ turn like he’d lived here all his life. Pushed his gun in my back, swore he’d blow me ta hell. Landed me in an alley on the riverfront where no one was. Got out, turned, pointed that gun at me, said with a nasty grin: ‘Only one way ta keep your mouth shut,’ and pulled the trigger. Next thing I know, I’m here and—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was going to die. George knew it as well as Al Aronson, Lt. Hunt, the nurse, the doctors, and everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor fellow, thought Aronson. No use trying to tell him he’s going to be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aloud he said: “What did he look like, George?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A heavy, tough kid— ‘bout seventeen, I’d say—and ‘bout five eight or nine. Wore a checked, tight suit o’ that loud green, and a cap. Couldn’t see much of his face; had his cap down too far; but he was full o’ pimples. Had a tough kid’s voice; the filthiest I ever did hear.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson straightened wearily. “That’s fine, George. Now, unless Lt. Hunt wants to ask you some more, just relax.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt set his jaw. “Just a couple o’ questions, George. In the first place—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chauffeur seemed to slump underneath the bedclothes. His eyes were fixed on Hunt, but they were blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save your question, Hunt,” said Aronson. “George will never answer it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;hunches&quot;&gt;Hunches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lt. Hunt chewed angrily on his cigar. “Stop trying to ride me, Aronson,” he exploded. “I’m telling you for the last time that killer was no local kid. I know every last hoodlum in town, and this punk doesn’t fit in. He’s an outsider.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned forward earnestly. “But,” he protested, “you heard George say that kid knew the back alleys here better than he did.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what? He could of come here a day before and studied the place. Why, for instance, would a local boy have to go over to Louisville to grab a car and bring it all the way here? Does that make sense?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It does sound screwy.” Aronson admitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, then. And don’t you go writing articles in your paper to the contrary, if you want the run of this place, either.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson was riding his hunches, and the hunch of George, the dead chauffeur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George had been sure the killer was a local boy. Yet Hunt was a damned good cop, and if he said that there wasn’t a hoodlum in New Albany who fit the description he was probably right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al Aronson disconsolately got into his car. He’d have to get back to the paper and write a story. Except it won’t be a story, he thought disgustedly. It’ll be a rehash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KILLER STILL ON THE LOOSE. NO CLUES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaperman in him revolted at the thought of dishing out yesterday’s warmed-over news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then an idea hit him! He heeled the car around in a screaming U-turn and went racing back to New Albany. He had an angle—not a very convincing one yet—but at least it explained how Lt. Hunt and the chauffeur could both be right. Maybe the kid had once lived in town, but had moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulling up at the first gas station, Aronson went into a huddle with a telephone book, and came out with the names and addresses of the six moving companies in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started making the rounds, interviewing the driver of every moving van. They listened to his description; then shook their heads. “Sorry, Buddy. If I ever saw him, I don’t remember.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson began to feel his job was futile. There was so little to go on. But he wouldn’t give up. Then—he struck pay dirt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mover named Davis said, “A mean kid, dark haired, pimples? A real low-down mean kid? Yeah, I remember him, all right; I’ll never forget the dirty little rat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When did you move him?” Al asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Must have been about a year ago. But I remember him good. Frankie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benson was his moniker. I moved him and his old man. The kid said he’d help me with a crate—a big crate—kind of a piano crate, but no piano in it When we had it up, he let go his end. Near busted my back. He started cussing me. Filthiest mouth I ever heard. I grabbed the punk and almost slugged him. Then I remembered he was just a kid, so I let him go. And when I turned around, he threw a hammer at me. Lucky his aim wasn’t too good. It missed my head, but near tore off my ear; here, I’ll show you the scar. They had to put three stitches in it, I woulda torn him apart if I got my hands on him, but he ran away, and I never saw him again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;but-what-could-i-do&quot;&gt;But What Could I Do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three hours later Al Aronson made his way down a dirty, ramshackle street in Louisville, to the address Davis had given him. He surveyed the paint-peeled, two room structure in the small, littered yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have gotten Hunt to come along, he thought. Wish I at least had a gun with me. Well, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crossed the street, now growing dark, and peered into the unlit front room. No one there. He made his way to the back of the house. Through a rear window he saw a stoop-shouldered, gray-haired man puttering around a stove. Apparently Frankie wasn’t at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson knocked on the door and introduced himself to Mr. Benson. He started telling the story, just the way it happened, carefully watching the old man’s face. Before the reporter was halfway through, the man suddenly burst out, “Don’t tell me no more; I don’t want to hear it It’s him, all right. I knew something like this would happen. Four men killed! Oh, my God! It’s my fault, I guess. He was bad all the way through, but what could I do?” The man’s voice was taking on a hysterical note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaperman helped the shaking old man to a chair; tried to quiet him. “All right, Mr. Benson, why don’t you tell me the whole thing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the floodgates opened. Benson poured out his story in a rush of words, as though something stored within him for years had now reached the bursting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t a particularly new story—not much different from dozens Aronson had written about— except its fateful climax. It was the story of a kid reared in the slums— a mother who died when the child was very young, and who hadn’t cared what happened to him before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A father who worked out of town, and saw him only a couple of hours on weekends. Frankie Benson had lived in the streets, almost like a wild animal, prowling back alleys for food, hanging around pool halls, bullying the smaller animals of the jungle he lived in and running from the larger ones; rejected and scorned by the decent elements of society, and nursing an ever-growing hatred. He had stolen, gone to reform school, and come out all the worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At first I thought he was just wild, like kids get sometimes,” the old man said hoarsely. “But then, when he was only thirteen, he started stealing. That’s when I knew he was bad. And I knew then that he’d end up rotten, that something like this would happen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Condemned at thirteen. Al thought bitterly. The kid never had a chance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His mind flashed back on his own boyhood. Thirteen—that was the year he was confirmed. He recalled that day in the synagogue— the joy and the warmth of it, surrounded by loving parents, relatives, friends, teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A kid needs people to love him, he said to himself. People rooting for him. Frankie never had anybody on his side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He used to hit me,” Benson went on in a voice that was now half sobbing. “His own father. I was afraid even to talk to him. I’d ask him to do something, he’d knock me down. Once when he was out in the box I yelled for him to come in to eat. He nearly choked me to death— said he’d kill me if I ever bothered him when he was busy with the box.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned over and said softly, “What box, Mr. Benson?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was a piano crate, I don’t know where he got it; he brought it home one day, years ago. He fixed it up and would stay in it. Sometimes almost a whole day. Like he was hiding from the world. It used to be sort of a game, I think—like most kids would use a tent. But then he’d shut himself in and hide. I don’t know from what.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s the box now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I shipped it out, like he told me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson leaned forward. “When did he tell you? When did you ship it? Where did you ship it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man thought for a moment. “Day before yesterday. That musta been the day those men were killed. He gave me some money, and said I should ship the crate to Knoxville. No address, just Railway Express, in Knoxville. He said I’d better do it the next day, or he’d take care of me. So that’s what I did. I sent it to Knoxville.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you seen Frankie since?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you have a receipt for the box?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. I’ll get it.” . Benson reached into a drawer in the kitchen table, brought out a couple of scraps of paper. He gave the receipt to Aronson, and then stood studying a dirty piece of notepaper in his hand. “I found this on the table that night, after he told me about sending the box. I—I didn’t know what he meant then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson took the note from his fingers, and read the child-like scrawl. Stop me, please, before I do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man looked entreatingly at the reporter. “Before he does it again! Oh, stop him! Stop him!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson’s lips tightened. He took the receipt and headed for the door. “I’ll try.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;ill-kill-you-ill-kill-you&quot;&gt;I’ll Kill You! I’ll Kill You!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the quiet of the darkened warehouse, Lt. Hunt flashed his light along the rows of high-piled crates, trunks and boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I must be crazy,” he said to Al Aronson, “letting you drag me out of bed to chase an old piano crate down to Knoxville. It would be different if he had gotten away with the bank robbery—maybe he’d have the dough in the crate. But he didn’t get a dime. We could have had the Knoxville police pick him up whenever he calls for the box. I don’t know what you expect to find inside of it, or what the big hurry is?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not so loud,” whispered Aronson. “The warehouseman said it would be somewhere in this corner.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you whispering for?” the Lieutenant demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t want to warn the kid we’re coming.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What makes you think the kid is here in the warehouse? How could he get in? It’s locked and guarded.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s in the piano crate; he was shipped in it from Louisville.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re crazy’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll see. Flash your light around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle of yellow light moved slowly down the row until it came to one larger than the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The piano crate!” Al said. He checked the markings on the box. “This is it, all right.” Then he pointed to a series of round holes bored in the side of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just as I thought,” he whispered. “Air holes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt swore under his breath; drew his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Al called out, “Okay, Frankie, we’ve got you covered. Come on out of the box.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aronson motioned for Hunt to take cover. He himself stepped behind a large trunk, said loudly, “Okay, Hunt, let’s roll this lousy crate over on its side.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two shots splintered holes in the box. A hysterical voice called, “Stay away from me, you lousy bums. I’ll kill you! I’ll kill you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be sensible, Kid,” the reporter called. “You can’t hit us because you can’t see us. But we can fill that box of yours full of lead; we can put more holes in it than a sieve. Come on out and give yourself up-”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obscene curse was the only answer, and a third shot crashed wood and spanged into a metal drum. “Show him we mean business, Lieutenant,” Al said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective fired a shot through the upper corner of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Next one goes right through the middle,” Aronson called out “What do you say, Frankie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a moment of silence, then a muffled sob, and the side of the case swung slowly back on its hinges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankie Benson came oat with his hands raised, crying. “Why did I do it?” he sobbed over mid over again. “Tell me why I did it. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lieutenant Hunt examined the piano crate; said, “Hey, AJ, he really had this thing rigged up—a Pullman bunk, three pistols, water bottles. cans of food—and straps -to hold everything in place. You ought to get a photographer down here. It will make a swell picture. You’ve got a great story—the story of the year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Al Aronson was staring at the sniveling kid in front of him, still sobbing, “Why did I do it? Why? Why? Why?” The sneering, ruthless killer who had coldly murdered four men without the slightest compunction was now just a scared, pimply-faced 16-year-old boy, all mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Al knew that the story he would write, the story that would command banner headlines on the front page, would not really be the main story. The important story was the one that would answer Frankie Benson’s plaintive entreaty—”Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, Al thought sadly, was an answer he didn’t know—a story that would never be written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/this-side-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/this-side-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Planned by the Stars</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-day-is-ill-omened&quot;&gt;The Day Is Ill-Omened&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sanctum of Madame Sovio was drab and tawdry. The room was small and done in faded blue draperies upon which were tinsel stars and moons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one window that overlooked Sixth Avenue bore the name of the astrologer in porcelain letters and the information that her hours of business were from two o’clock to five daily. A broad table that stood in the center of the room held a plaster skull and a quantity of astrological charts. Other charts were nailed up on either side of a door that led into an anteroom. The low ceiling had once been painted to give the impression of drifting clouds. Twin gas jets, blackening it, had long past destroyed the effect. The faint though pungent odor of gin hung on the stirless air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of the astrology parlor sat at the center table. Madame Sovio wore a flowing Egyptian kimono patterned extravagantly with the mystic signs of the zodiac. She was old, gaunt and unprepossessing. Her untidy hair was wreathed with a greasy veil; her shrewd eyes focused on the financial page of a morning newspaper. From time to time she stimulated herself with small quantities of fluid poured from a square bottle convenient to her elbow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio finished a perusal of the page she read and was turning languidly to the front sheet of the paper when she looked up. The door of the outer room had opened and closed. With the practice born of long experience she placed both bottle and newspaper in a lower drawer of the table, thrust a few cloves into her toothless mouth, and stood up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “waiting room” of the establishment was even smaller than the inner room. It contained nothing save a number of rickety chairs and a red-faced youth who was pinching out a cigarette ere consigning the stub to a coat pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caller was tall, bulky and unattractive. He wore a rusty brown suit and stained yellow brogans with bumpy toes. A celluloid collar held a stringy purple cravat; from under the sagging peak of a shoddy cap a low, protruding forehead, dark, crafty eyes and a loose, rapacious mouth were visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was evident to Madame Sovio that the youth was flotsam cast up by the turgid rivers of subterranea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He met her gaze and shuffled forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You the one that slides out the dope on what’s gonna happen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman inclined her head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Come in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visitor stepped into the room hung with the faded blue draperies. Madame Sovio closed the door after him. She indicated he should take the chair opposite her across the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you wish a horoscope or a reading?” she inquired as he sat down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A spinner on the docks give me the gab that you had steered him straight on the bang-tails. I’m due to gay-cat tonight on something important. I want a frame telling me how my luck is gonna break.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio twined her claw fingers together. She understood the youth to mean that some client who had sought her advice as to making bets on the races had recommended him to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The stars,” she began, following a usual procedure, “plan and compel! Their influence falls directly on each mortal. What is planned cannot be changed. A man’s planetary destiny is as inflexible as Fate. It is Fate. I charge one dollar for a reading.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red-faced youth produced a crumpled dollar and pushed it across the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give me the dope on how I’m gonna make out. Am I gonna be lucky or not ? Get the hop working and give me a buzz. Should I or shouldn’t I?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seamy lips of the astrologer came together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is your name?” she asked in a business-like voice. “What is the date of your birth? Upon what hour of that day or night were you born? I must know these things before I read the messages of the heavenly bodies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The youth continued to stare at her for a long minute. He muttered the name of Joe Carney, informed her of the date of his natal day and, without hesitation, said he had been born at the precise hour of midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio became engrossed in a deep study of her charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While she bent her gray-crowned head over the table Joe Carney settled back in his chair. He glanced about idly and wrinkled his nose at the familiar odor of gin that could not be disguised by the perfume of the cloves. He sat patiently until a slight exclamation moved his eyes to the woman across the table. He was surprised to see she was staring at a chart with every indication of horror. r&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not one hour of the twenty-four is propitious! The day is ill-omened! All the planetary influences are dark and evil. Mars, Saturn, Uranus and Mercury are adverse. Jupiter is in a hostile position and is ringed with red. This is the star that guides your footsteps through this constellation. Its scarlet rim foretells but one thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney met her gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio moved her hand slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Murder!” she said quietly. “At midnight you came upon this earth and at midnight the stars plan you shall be removed from it. Uranus intrudes and blurs the horoscope. I can read no further. That is all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney laughed harshly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The hell it is! I pay a dollar for that song and dance? Give me the money back. You’re a robber!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madame Sovio pushed the dirty bill he had laid on the table across to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it! It will bring you no good. You are in the shadow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red-faced youth pocketed his money, shrugged with contempt and slouched out, banging the door after him. For an interval the woman sat motionless, fingers picking at the thumb-marked chart before her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The red ring,” she said half-aloud. “Blood on the stars—murder on earth—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emerging onto Sixth Avenue, from the narrow entrance of the building housing the two rooms of the star-reader, Joe Carney laughed under his breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A hell of a spiel!” he said to himself. “I should get glomed for a bone to get that bunk dished out. “The old dame is nuts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crossed to the west side of Sixth Avenue and walked north. A firm believer in the Black Arts, he wished he had not listened to the dock-walloper who had told him of the astrologer. He could have interviewed a palmist or crystal-gazer and not wasted his time. He knew nothing, and now it was too late to seek another seer. Within twenty minutes he had an appointment with Stanley Ray, the leader of the Duster Band; final plans for the night’s adventures were to be unfolded to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sight of the shopping district Carney entered a side street. He put a number of avenues behind him, passed under the scaffolding of an overhead railroad and presently was on the threshold of the small area of the city, controlled by Stanley Ray’s band of thugs and gangsters. Tenement houses stood shoulder to shoulder in flanks of brick. Down the slope of the side street an avenue where freight cars rolled was visible; further distant was the waterfront and the Hudson River. Frowsy women leaned from countless windows; children played in the gutters; the summer air was dank with the stench of salt water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the avenue where the freight trains ran Joe Carney stepped. He put two blocks behind him and presently came upon a waterfront hotel—a building that had been old when the city was young. Joe Carney passed through the hostelry’s yawning front door and moved into a small lobby. A few loafers, smoking nauseous pipes, played checkers silently or slumbered loudly, shaggy heads tilted forward on flannelled chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the group, brooding over his cigarette, sat a tall, heavily built young man with a dark, sinister face in which was largely written both determination and courage. This man stood up as Carney entered, nodded his head slightly and opened a white-washed door a few feet back from where he had been sitting. When Carney had followed him into a small room that was used as a refuge for drug-peddlers and their victims, he closed the door and turned the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney promptly sat down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I’m here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray inclined his head slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I see.” He pulled up a chair and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dropped into it. “Listen carefully. I’m passing you the word that you turn the job on Tenth Avenue tonight. I’ve never told you where you’re to go or what you’ve to do. All that you know is you’ve been picked out by me to swing a deal and keep your peep closed. The frame is set so that all you have to do is to walk in, help yourself and walk out. A half-wit could turn this without a mistake. That’s how soft it is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney fished in his pocket for the half-consumed cigarette. He lighted it and inhaled deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I make you. Let’s have it all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray went to the door and listened. He returned to his chair and leaned forward. He lowered his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Limping Lou has turned straight— by request. He works for the gas company. Tuesday he went to a flat on Tenth Avenue to read the cellar meter. In the front basement of the place are two rooms rented by a woman called Mrs. Garber. Lou had finished reading the meter and was passing out when he heard a clinking noise. It came from inside Mrs. Garber’s front room. Lou tried to look through the keyhole, but it was plugged. So he went out into the alley and found the side window of the same room. This window was protected by bars, but was open at the top. Lou found a barrel, stood up on it and looked through the top of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney drew a breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What did he see?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray leaned still closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He saw Mrs. Garber sitting before a trunk—counting money! Lou said she was tying up bales of the green stuff in old aprons. He watched her until she put the aprons in the trunk, filled it to the top with old clothes and then shut it up! That’s what he saw!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney dropped his cigarette to the floor and ground it out with his heel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What else?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I stuck a plant up there,” Stanley Ray resumed. “I found out this Mrs. Garber is out every afternoon. She makes her money playing the stock market. It’s no use trying to get into the room during the day because the janitor of the building and a bunch of ginnies are laying pipe in the cellar. I sent the Turk up yesterday. He took a fall out of the bars. He filed them to the bone. A couple of pulls will yank them out. The window’s always open and you can go in over the top of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What time do I go in? Will the miser be there when I get to the trunk ? How much long change do I get out of this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leader of the Duster Band favored Carney with a direct, cold stare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You get what I give you! Have you anything to say about it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the bland stare of the gangster king Joe Carney’s eyes wavered and fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing,” he said hastily. “Put me right on it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Ray smiled faintly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I found out this Mrs. Garber gets telephone calls from Levy’s Drug Store. At a quarter of twelve I’ll telephone the drug store and tell them to send for Mrs. Garber. They’ll shoot their kike kid over to the basement. You’ll be in the alley at quarter of twelve. When she goes out you go in. I’ll stall her on the wire as long as possible. It should take you just about ten minutes to grab the dough and exit. Do you get me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney reflectively rubbed his beard-rusty chin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” he said laconically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-right-dope&quot;&gt;The Right Dope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night was hot and unstirring. A full moon rode high in a cloudless sky. The dank smell of the river grew more pronounced. The streets were lined with coatless loungers sprawling at ease in doorway or on stoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Carney, shuffling up Tenth Avenue, searched each store window for a clock to tell the hour by. It could not be very late. The avenue was well filled’ —a number of shops were open and doing business. Again he regretted some prophet had not been employed to prognosticate the fortunes attending the enterprise. In every task he had set out to accomplish he had been warned in advance as to the condition of his luck. If he had been told it was not favorable lie had postponed the event. And never once had he been apprehended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked on, hands rammed in the pockets of his coat. He eyed the numbers of the buildings as he passed them, still searching for a clock, growing aware his destination must be only a few blocks distant. He saw the moon creep up over the sullen rooftops and perceived the canopy of brightly shining stars. He thought of the astrologer of the early afternoon and the jumble of her words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A murder!” he chuckled, touching the automatic revolver hung under his left arm. “Swell chancel”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two more blocks traversed, he came abreast the building in whose basement the wealthy Mrs. Garber resided. And at the same minute his eyes fell upon the face of a clock in a store of the tenement and he started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hands of the clock pointed to five minutes of the midnight hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guiltily realizing he had been delinquent and heedless of time, Carney descended a number of steps that led down into the basement. He found himself in a cement-lined passageway. He followed it to its termination and found himself in the clothesline-hung backyard in the rear of the building. An alley ran into the backyard, presided over by a lean cat. Carney removed the animal from his path with a toe of his boot and crouched against the face of the alley’s brick wall, ceasing to curse the vivid moonlight only when a barred window of translucent glass leaped out to meet him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tingle of anticipation ran through Joe Carney. Hex found the same barrel Limping Lou had made his observations from and wheeled it close to the window. He mounted it cautiously and applied an ear to the aperture in the window’s top. All was quiet within. Obviously, he decided, Mrs. Garber was in the drug store or on her way to it. He was ten minutes late and would have to work rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The window bars yielded instantly to his grasp. He tore them roughly away, one by one. When the last bar had been wrenched loose, Carney pressed the top half of the window lower and poked a head into the inky blackness of the room. Low but distinctly he heard the monotonous ticking of a clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied that no menace crouched in the gloom, Carney threw a leg over the sash and lowered himself into the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until his eyes could grow accustomed to the murk he stood motionless. A faint odor of gin assailed his nostrils. Faint stirrings tuned his nerves to a high pitch. With a sense of direction fixed firmly in mind, he crept forward. The treasure chest, Stanley Ray had told him, rested to the right, against the room’s north wall. As the thought flashed through his mind, his knees came in contact with some low-set object. His outstretched hands clasped the top of something he knew immediately was the trunk, and he exhaled a breath of relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover of the trunk swung upward at his touch. He felt to make sure that the connecting arms were firmly fastened and delved into a mass of soft garments, placed layer upon layer. These he dug out and flung to the floor, burrowing, mole-like, to reach the apron-wrapped treasure. The scent of gin seemed to envelop him. He wondered why this odor should stir odd recollections—recollections he could not piece together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had pulled the last article of clothing from the trunk when the door of the room vibrated with a sudden staccato rapping. Ere its first echoes throbbed into silence, a nasal voice sup–planted the loud knocks with an insistent statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Garber! Somebody wants you on the telephone down at Levy’s!” Joe Carney’s hands closed convulsively. The clock he had looked upon had been fast or the telephone had marred Stanley Ray’s message!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, Mrs. Garber must be within a few feet of him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The messenger from the drug store began his rapping again. Stiff as stone Joe Carney sought to think. Then, as the knocks ceased for the moment, he heard, from some quarter close at hand, the creak of a bed, a soft footfall—a sibilant swish that told of a garment being donned. Followed at once the rasp of an opening door. A vagrant air current, stirred to new action, touched Carney’s forehead—cold against the sweat that had gathered upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breathless questions rushed through the mind of the intruder. Should he allow the woman to answer the messenger? Or should he strike before she reached the door?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another series of footfalls wheeled him silently about. Someone was approaching—had stepped through the door. He thought he could detect a muffled shape of shadow moving closer to him. The suspense of waiting was agony. A breath caressed his hot face and a hand touched his arm. Someone gasped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same moment he sprang forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a low growl he felt his fingers dig deep into a soft, stringy throat. Eyes glared into his own; for all of the fact she was a woman, the figure he clutched fought desperately, Carney released his left hand to bring it down with crushing force on the jaw of the struggling figure. Before he had crashed it savagely into the upturned face the woman managed to wrench a scream from between her lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursing, Carney struck again. He gripped the throat again with the hand he had used with hammer force and shook the woman as a terrier shakes a rat. As if from a distance he heard fresh raps falling upon the door—the voice of the messenger:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Garber! Mrs. Garber!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carney relaxed the gripping pressure of his death-working fingers. He found he was talking but knew not what he said. He had killed a woman, but it was her own fault. Hot blood pounded within him—rage and a gloating satisfaction. He felt that at that moment he wished she possessed the nine lives of the cat he had kicked from his path. He would strangle each from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then he realized the apron-wrapped loot would never be his if he stood longer, clutching the limp figure. He opened his hands. The body slumped to the floor. The moon, swinging around, entered the alley and crept into the room, lighting it up like a pale arc lamp. Carney looked down at the huddle of his victim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman had fallen on her back. Her face was upturned to him— wreathed with a horrible, fixed grin. He stared, fascinated, eying, too, greasy gray hair that seemed strangely familiar. For a full watch-tick he stared, rigid. The odor of gin—the gray hair—the gaunt face, painted with the ghastly moon glare. All at once knowledge flooded him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Garber wore the face of the Madame Sovio who had read the stars for him that afternoon in the Sixth Avenue room!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Murder!” Carney whispered. “She had the right dope!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something, as he straightened up, stopped the flow of the incoming moonlight. He raised his eyes and turned them to the window. His gaze flashed and fell upon a helmeted head looking in over the lowered top of the translucent window. His right hand darted under his jacket and gripped his automatic. In some blind, dizzy fashion he managed to drag it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before he could pull the trigger the yellow glare of an electric torch smote him directly between the eyes. A voice, curt and imperious, bade him throw up his hands. Carney, blinking like an owl drenched in sunshine, fell back. His weapon crept up to firing position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the heavy silence was shattered by the sound of six shots, so rapidly fired that they merged as one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The automatic fell from Carney’s hand. He wondered vaguely if he had been shot—why his legs seemed to be melting away. Cursing again, his brain reeled and scintillated with sparks. He groaned and fell heavily across something softly yielding … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock that had ticked monotonously whirred and struck the hour of twelve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/planned-by-the-stars/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/planned-by-the-stars/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parting Gift</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;its-me-honey&quot;&gt;It’s Me, Honey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret walked slowly up the path to his front door, clicked his key in the lock and stepped into the warmth of his own hallway. For a moment he stood there in the semi-darkness, breathing hard, tilting his head, smelling the old familiar smells and wondering at himself for the thing he was about to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His wife, Eva, called down from upstairs, “Joe, is that you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret shivered and tightened his hand around the bulky object in his overcoat pocket. He said, as steadily as he could, “It’s me, honey,” and tasted for a brief moment a spasm of panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took a cigarette from his breast pocket and tucked it between dry lips, dragging in the taste of the unlit tobacco. Then he took off his coat and hat and threw them over the packed bags lying near the hat-rack by the door, and with the package in his hand, walked stealthily out into the kitchen and opened the door leading down into his workshop in the cellar. He stood at the head of the wooden steps, feeling the hot rush of blood into his face and the dizziness in his head. He went down the stairs and turned on the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the dry cigarette still waggling between his lips, Pomfret sat down at his bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carefully, he unwrapped the package, revealing an expensive bronze table lighter fashioned after a globe of the world, with the ignition plunger where the north pole should be, and the countries etched in neatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead, the echo of his wife’s footsteps jarred through the floor, hurrying him along. He pulled the cigarette away from his lips, tearing off a strip of skin, and reached over to the rack for a screwdriver. He unscrewed the filler cap, picked out the cotton wool, threw it in a wastebasket. From the rack where his reloading tools lay he took down a canister of pistol powder. Next he removed the wick from the lighter and fitted into its place a short, fast-burning fuse, and began pouring the powder into the base of the lighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew powders, he knew gas pressures. He knew what would happen when someone picked up the lighter, holding it close to the end of the cigarette, and pressed the plunger for a light. They’d get a light, all right, a light that would show them the way into eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without air space, the hundred-odd grains of powder compressed into that bronze base would be as deadly as a hand-grenade. Pomfret had seen it work once before. Just four grains of powder jammed down by an improperly hand-loaded bullet to the bottom of a cartridge case, without air space for the expanding pressure of the gas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He still had the wreckage of a once perfectly good heavy-frame revolver in one of the drawers in his filing cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he had screwed the cap back in place he picked up the lighter, carrying it as cautiously as he would have carried a bottle of nitro-glycerine, and walked up the stairs. He felt as weak as if he had spent the afternoon running around the block. He closed the cellar door behind him and leaned his back against it, hard, until his shoulder blades ached from the contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went over to the tap for a drink of water. Then he walked slowly back into the living room and placed the lighter gently on the cocktail table, where no one could miss seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He knew how it would react on Harvey. He knew it would be the first thing Harvey, a chain-smoker, would pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He closed his eyes and thought about Harvey’s handsome face. Then he went out into the hallway and began putting on his hat and coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;harveys-cigarette-case&quot;&gt;Harvey’s Cigarette Case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eva came down the stairs, and Pomfret paused by the door, watching her, taking her in, gauging the full fluid motion of her body and the slow swing of her long tawny hair and the full rich beauty of her face, feeling again the desire for her and the need of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped then, and turned toward the living room and took a hesitant step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said, “What’s wrong, Joe?” and the sound of her voice clipped his resolution in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret laughed, the cracked sound of it echoing hollow and false in his brain. “Nothing at all,” he said lamely. “Tired, I guess. Had a hard day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came to him and rested her hand on his arm. The touch of her pulled the trigger on his mind and the hatred in him welled up then and flowed fresh and potent until he thought he would kill her then and there, without benefit of gadgets or tricks or long-range plans, if she didn’t take her hand off him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, hoarsely, “Has Harvey called for his cigarette case yet, Eva?” and his keen, suspicious eyes probed hers for some sign of fear or admission of her guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took her hand away and color touched her cheeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For heaven’s sake, Joe, do we have to go through all that again? I told you he left it in the living room the last time he was here, and I took it upstairs to the bedroom so I wouldn’t forget to ask you to give it back to him when you saw him at the office. Isn’t that reasonable enough for you? Do you expect me to go down on my knees and beg for belief from my own husband?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her voice was as tight as a plucked violin string, vibrating against the resistance in his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He thought again of the lighter on the living room table. He let out his breath. The taste in his mouth was as sour and he wanted to be sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead he reached for her and kissed her harshly, feeling the softness of her against him, the elusive, heady perfume, the taste of her lipstick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling, too, the resistance that had been there for months now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” he said quietly. “Okay, hon. Let’s skip it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He opened the door and reached down for his bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll be back,” he said, as if it mattered. “It may take time. Maybe a week or more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You be careful of those Toledo blondes,” she said, smiling up at him. “I don’t know if I should trust you that far away from home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me! he thought bitterly. You don’t know if you can trust me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried a laugh on, just to see if it would fit, and when it didn’t, he turned and walked quickly from the house to the oar. There was a harsh bitter nip of Fall in the air. The breaths he took crackled in his lungs and reminded him of football games and the sharp clean tang of mustard on hot-dogs and the closeness and warmth Eva had been to him then, before Harvey joined the firm and began his series of weekly visits, finally moving into the house next door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomfret almost tore the transmission out of the car getting it into second gear. As he passed Harvey’s house he saw the shadow of Harvey’s bulk against the windowshades, and he knew that before he reached the corner the big eager man would be sneaking slyly through the gate in the hedge to where Eva waited for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He put the car into high gear and went down the street and turned the corner, out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;theyll-never-suspect-a-thing&quot;&gt;They’ll Never Suspect A Thing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey grinned. He had a good-natured, boyish grin that worked well with some types of women. He stood in the middle of Joe Pomfret’s living room, staring at Joe Pomfret’s wife. There was sweat on his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said, “Look, from now on, it’s so much velvet, Ev. Everything’s going to be okay. It’ll all be over soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked over to the table and spun a pack of cigarettes so that one flipped out. This he tapped on the table and put in his mouth. He picked up the bronze lighter and held it in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Neat little gadget,” he said, making his voice loud, as if to drown out his own thoughts and the ones in Eva’s mind. “Where’d you get it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She sat tensely on the edge of the studio couch, staring at her hands. The whip in his voice brought her head up and she glanced at the lighter, then shrugged impatiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know. Joe, I guess. He’s always bringing something home.” She wet her lips. “When, Harv? How long will it be?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey put the lighter back on the table and poured himself a stiff drink. He put it down his throat in one long smooth motion, and glanced at his watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When he hits the Turnpike hill,” he said, keeping his voice even, “he’ll have to brake hard for the sharp turn there. When he does, the brake cable goes. I took care of the emergency, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He poured another drink, rattling the bottle against the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a hundred foot drop through that fence. He won’t feel a thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shivered. He took the cigarette from his mouth and went over to her. She came willingly and easily into his arms. He kissed her in a way that Joe Pomfret had never known and would never learn, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment she lay still in his arms, her breath hot on his face, her eyes closed. The room was very still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey put the cigarette back in his mouth and pushed her gently away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be fine, angel. They’ll never suspect a thing.” Her mouth touched his again, jostling the cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled. Her hand searched out across the table, touching the rough etched metal of the lighter, closing around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She slid her other arm around his neck, pulling his head down to hers, touching the lighter to the end of his cigarette. Her lips brushed his ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Light, darling?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/parting-gift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/parting-gift/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Odds Are On Death</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;lucks-a-fickle-jade&quot;&gt;Luck’s A Fickle Jade&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran threw snake-eyes. An audible gasp went up from the well-dressed crowd around the crap-table. They had seen Corcoran make six straight passes; watched him run a ten-spot up to six hundred and forty bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, since there was no limit in Spot Shelton’s ultra-select gambling establishment, Corcoran had shot the works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loudly the girl alongside him said: “You were foolish, honey. You should have dragged down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her name was Margie Zaine. She wore her blue-black hair sleekly coiffed; she had a Madonna face. Her figure was a poem of curves sheathed in a crimson satin evening gown. Men had a hard time keeping their eyes away from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was a capper for Spot Shelton’s place. Sucker-bait. But Corcoran was no sucker. He was a private dick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grinned down into her dark eyes. She was playing her part to perfection. Nobody on Spot Shelton’s staff would possibly suspect her of disloyalty to Shelton tonight … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nor could anybody guess what Corcoran was really up to. Thus far he’d played his part of a reckless sap to the hilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it had been a tough job trying to make the dice obey orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck’s a fickle jade; when a man wants to lose, he almost invariably wins. It had taken him more than ten minutes to go broke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;a-teller-at-my-bank&quot;&gt;A Teller At My Bank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tuxedoed croupier said: “Still your dice if you want them, Mister.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie Zaine pressed herself closer to Corcoran. She was trembling a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the far end of the table a tall, nervous young man flashed a veiled glance at the private dick; flicked his eyebrows. Corcoran took his cue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said to the croupier: “I’d like to keep on shooting, but I’m cleaned.” He passed the cubes to the player on his right. Then he said: “Could I get a check cashed?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up at the end of the table, the tall young man was listening to a willowy blonde in daring décolletage. He seemed annoyed. The blonde looked sore. The croupier beckoned an attendant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendant came up to Corcoran and said: “How large a check, sir?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, about five hundred.” Corcoran drew a checkbook from his dinner jacket pocket. He didn’t produce the flat .25 automatic which also reposed in that pocket. The attendant frowned dubiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m afraid I’ll have to let Mr. Shelton pass on that, sir. It’s more than I’m authorized to cash. I’ll take you to his office.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie Zaine said: “Never mind. I’ll show the way.” She looked archly at Corcoran. “I know Spot Shelton. I’ll introduce you. Come along, honey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a chuckle, of course, Margie knew Shelton. She worked for him! But she wouldn’t be working for him after tonight. Corcoran slipped an arm around her waist. She led him out of the casino-room and down a long, carpeted corridor. She knocked on a closed door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A voice said: “Come in.” It was Spot Shelton’s voice, sleek and purring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They entered. Margie said: “Hello, Spot. This is my friend, Mr. Jones. He wants a check cashed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton’s eyes were heavy-lidded and crafty to match the thin gash of his avaricious mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Glad to accommodate you,” he said affably. “How much will you need?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran raised his ante. “A thousand will do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a light turned off, Shelton’s smile faded abruptly. “A thousand?” he said sharply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” Corcoran said, “I’ve got plenty in the bank. Want proof?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What kind of proof?” Shelton purred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Send for Harry Greer. He’s out at the dice-table. I just saw him. He’s a teller at my bank. He knows the balance I carry. Call him in. Ask him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton spoke into a house-phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;you-might-call-it-a-stick-up&quot;&gt;You Might Call It A Stick-Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment the door opened. A tall, nervous young man came in, the one who had flicked his eyebrow at Corcoran a while ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “Why, hello, Margie. Good evening, Mr. Jones,” he added politely to Corcoran. Then he looked at Shelton. “You want me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “He wants to know how much money I’ve got on deposit in your bank, Harry. Tell him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer cleared his throat; it was his only sign of uneasiness. “Why, more than thirty thousand dollars, roughly speaking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah,” Shelton smiled apologetically to Corcoran. “In that case I’ll be delighted to cash your check, Mr. Jones.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to the wall behind his elaborate desk, shoved aside an etching, and toyed with the dial of a counter-sunk safe. A big yellow solitaire diamond glittered on the ring finger of his right hand as he opened the safe’s circular door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran pulled out his .25 automatic and said: “Thanks, Shelton. Now step back and sit down before I blast you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gambler whirled, his sallow cheeks pale. “What is this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You might call it a stick-up,” Corcoran said. “But I’d sooner say it’s a bit of justice outside the law. I’m not a hood. Just a private shamus working for Harry Greer and Miss Zaine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, you dirty — !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Tie him to the chair, Harry. And Margie, you grab the dough out of the box. Just thirty grand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thirty grand — ?” Shelton snarled an oath at the girl. “You double-crossing vixen!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer slugged him in the teeth. The gambler sagged into his chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer produced a skein of picture-wire, and bound Shelton’s wrists and ankles, saying: “Maybe Margie used to be a double-crosser. But not any more. She’s all through capping for you, Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margie was pulling packets of currency out of the safe, stuffing them into her beaded purse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer went on: “She got me to play your crooked games, Shelton. But you didn’t count on her falling for me, did you? Well, that’s what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Falling for you? That’s a laugh, you dirty — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer said: “I’m marrying Margie, see? That’s why I hired this detective to help me get back the thirty thousand dollars you took away from me with your loaded dice. Now I can put back what I took from the bank — before the auditors catch up with me. And from now on, Margie and I are going straight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gambler squirmed helplessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Margie he snarled: “Don’t be a sap, kid! Greer’s playing you for a sucker. He won’t marry you. Look what he did to Jackie Allan. Made her fall for him, too, then handed her the air. He’ll treat you the same way! Put that dough back, baby — and I’ll forget the whole thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added: “You can keep out five hundred if you want to. That’s all Greer ever lost to me, the lousy liar. He never dropped any thirty grand!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t believe you, Spot,” Margie said quietly. She snapped her purse shut. It bulged with the currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton raged: “You put that dough back in the safe or I’ll get you if it’s the last thing I ever do!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer hit him on the jaw again. The gambler sagged against his bonds, unconscious. Greer went over to him to make sure the wires were tightly knotted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “Okay. He won’t get loose for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;could-i-kiss-the-bride&quot;&gt;Could I Kiss The Bride?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door opened. A feminine voice said: “That’s what you think.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the willowy blonde who had approached Greer at the crap-table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer said: “Jackie Allan — !” in a scared whisper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of her heavy make-up she was gorgeous. Her hair was spun gold. She said: “I told you I’d get even with you for handing me the gate, Harry. I warned you I’d get something on you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer sputtered: “You — you — !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy, Harry,” she said frigidly. “And put that money back where it belongs. Spot Shelton was plenty decent to me after you walked out on me. This is my chance to make it up to him. You put that money back, or I’ll scream the place down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran went into action. He jumped at the blonde and slapped a muffling hand over her mouth. He looked at Greer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about this, Harry?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A pack of lies!” the bank-teller said harshly, indignantly. “It’s true I was nuts about her for a while. She was the one who first got me into playing Shelton’s crooked games. When I found out she was one of his come-ons, I ditched her. Then I fell in love with Margie, here. Margie came clean with me; promised to help me get my money back from Shelton … ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Hand me that picture-wire,” Corcoran snapped. He took the skein, tripped Jackie Allan to the floor, tied her. When he got through, she was gagged with a handkerchief and trussed like a turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran got up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Greer he said: “Get your coat and hat and go home. Margie and I will phone you from her apartment, later. We’ll leave shortly. It wouldn’t look good for all of us to be seen pulling out of this joint together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Corcoran and Margie strolled casually back into the gaming-room a little later, Greer was gone. Corcoran stopped at the roulette-table long enough to lose the fifty that Margie had slipped him. That was to make everything look okay. After all, he was supposed to have cashed a check … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four wrong guesses at the wheel, he yawned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s beat it, Margie. I’m tired,” he said loudly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She fastened herself to his arm. They went out; found a taxi. They headed for her apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You were swell,” she said. “Now Harry and I can be married, and — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Could I kiss the bride?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She gave him her lips in gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;and-finally-silence&quot;&gt;And Finally, Silence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab stopped in front of her apartment building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They went into the lobby. It was deserted and dimly lighted at this late hour. They made for the automatic elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a curtained alcove to the left, a hand appeared. It was a white, soft-looking hand wearing a yellow diamond solitaire and holding a revolver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the gun crashed, Margie Zaine screamed and clutched at her breast. Blood spurted through her fingers. She dropped her handbag and fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran made a grab for his automatic. He fired at the drapes. He knew he must have missed, because there was no answering fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bellowing, the private dick smashed toward the curtained alcove. As he hit the drapes, something thunked down on his head. He was stunned. Fireworks exploded inside his brain. He reeled drunkenly; pitched to his knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time he got up again, the alcove was empty. There was a doorway leading to the alley alongside the building. The door was open … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran stared stupidly at Margie Zaine’s sprawled form. Death’s waxen mist was on her Madonna face. Her handbag was open and empty. The money she had taken from Spot Shelton’s office wall-safe was now gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton, who had threatened her … Shelton, who had worn a yellow solitaire diamond on the ring finger of his white, effeminate hand … !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran snapped out of his daze. He was thinking of Harry Greer, now. Maybe the bank-teller would be next on Shelton’s list of victims. Maybe it was already too late —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinting out into the night, Corcoran grabbed a passing owl cab. It zipped him to Greer’s apartment house, an unpretentious three-story structure with exterior fire- escapes marring its old-fashioned red brick façade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran raced up to the second floor. He reached the bank-teller’s door and pounded on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Greer — let me in! It’s me, Corcoran — and hell’s to pay!” A muffled pistol-shot answered him. Then a heavy thump, as of a body falling. And finally, silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran hit the door. It bruisingly rebuffed him. He backed away and smashed at it again, putting his full two hundred pounds behind the impact. This time the portal gave way. He stumbled into the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;pinched-for-murder&quot;&gt;Pinched For Murder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An open window framed the iron fire-ladder just outside. In the room’s center lay Harry Greer, breathing heavily, with his eyes closed. Thick clotted blood wept from a raw hole in his left shoulder. A thin drift of gunpowder-smoke eddied in the dull light from a table-lamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran ran heavily to the window; stared outward, downward. He couldn’t see anybody. He returned to Greer and worked over him. At last the teller opened his eyes. “God … my shoulder … !” he groaned faintly. “Who drilled you? Was it Shelton?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I … don’t know! I was … getting ready to … start for Margie’s place … and a shot … came from … the window … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer sat up weakly. “What are you … doing here? My God … if Shelton shot me … he may go … gunning for Margie … You should have … stayed with her … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry, kid, but Margie — Margie’s dead.” Corcoran tried to break the news to him gently. “‘Take it easy while I try to do something to fix this shoulder of yours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Margie … dead … ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teller pushed Corcoran away. “Do something … .!” he cried hysterically. “Call the cops … trail that dirty rat … get him … kill him … !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His lips twisted vengefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Yeah. Trail Shelton. That’s a large order. He’ll be on the lam for sure, now. He must’ve got loose in his office; reached Margie’s place ahead of us. Then he blasted.He killed her — and thought he killed me, too. So he came here to bump you. But just as he fired at you from the window, he heard my voice out in the hall. He realized he hadn’t croaked me. And now he knows he’s in the soup; knows my testimony will convict him. He’ll go into hiding.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got to find him!” Greer sobbed. “Get going! I’ll phone the cops. Move, blast you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran went out. It was going to be tough, trying to locate Spot Shelton. Corcoran didn’t know where to start. Then he got an idea. He found a drugstore and a phone book. He looked up Jackie Allan’s name and found it. He made a note of her address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A taxi took him to a bungalow court. He rang her bell. When she opened the door, Corcoran drew his automatic and shoved the muzzle against her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “You’re pinched for murder, baby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was wearing lounging pajamas. Her wrists were red and chafed from the wire with which she’d been trussed back in Shelton’s office. There were marks on her ankles, too. The ankles themselves were slender and dainty, to match the rest of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said: “Pinched … for murder? What do you m-mean?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He backed her into the little living room and kicked the door shut behind him. He pushed her onto the divan and stood over her, glowering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What happened after I left Shelton’s joint?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why — why — I managed to spit that gag out of my mouth. I yelled for help. People came in and untied me and Shelton, too. Spot brought me home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Straight home?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes.” She seemed puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said: “You’re a liar, baby. You hated Harry Greer’s guts because he ditched you. You hated Margie Zaine for taking him away from you. So you gunned the both of them, to get even.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was preposterous, of course. Corcoran knew that. But he wanted to throw a scare into Jackie Allan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;to-save-a-guys-life&quot;&gt;To Save A Guy’s Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the color drained from her cheeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I — I don’t know what you’re talking about!” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Margie’s dead. You killed her. You tried to kill me. And you put a bullet through Harry Greer’s shoulder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I — I didn’t! My God, I wouldn’t — ” She reached up and grabbed his gun-arm. “D-don’t point that thing at me. And you can’t believe I’d — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at her, steadily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s just one way you can buy yourself out of this mess, baby. I want you to tell me where I can find Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the hallway, a voice growled: “That’s easy, snoop. Here I am. And this thing in my hand isn’t a saxophone. It’s a rod. It shoots bullets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “How did you get in here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve got a key,” Shelton said. “Why not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll be getting a key to the hot squat before long,” Corcoran said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I gathered that. I was home listening to the radio when I heard a bleat go out for me on a murder rap. That’s why I’m here now.” He looked at the blonde girl. “Why did you kill Margie, babe?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I didn’t — I didn’t! That’s what I was trying to tell this copper — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s okay. I understand the setup.” The gambler glared at Corcoran. “You’re not arresting her, snoop. I won’t let you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelton shifted his gun to his left hand, doubled his right. He hit Corcoran on the button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twice. Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran’s knees buckled. He took the count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he awoke, Shelton and Jackie were gone. The house was all upset, as if a hurried job of luggage packing had been accomplished during the private detective’s unconsciousness. Corcoran felt his bruised jaw. The flesh wasn’t cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stumbled out of the cottage. He walked four blocks before he found a cab. He gave the driver Greer’s address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And step on it — to save a guy’s life!” he panted. Seven minutes later he burst into Greer’s apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer had contrived to bandage his nicked shoulder. He stared at Corcoran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What — ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shelton’s still on the loose. He’s got a gun. He may be on his way here to finish you!” Corcoran said. “But we’ll trap him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“H-how?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you got a roscoe? He took mine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer opened a desk drawer. He brought out a revolver. Corcoran snatched it and jammed it three inches into the bank-teller’s belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The jig’s up,” he said grimly. “You bumped Margie. Where’s the dough?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer turned a pasty yellow. “Are you crazy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like a fox,” Corcoran snapped. “Listen. Shelton told the truth tonight when he said you only lost five hundred to him. When he told Margie you never intended to marry her. You were a smart skunk, Greer. You’d never swiped any dough from your bank. That was just a stall to make Margie fall in with your schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You planned to rob Spot Shelton. He looked like an easy touch. And you did a lot of groundwork before you pulled the strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You first tried to work through Jackie Allan; but when she wouldn’t work with you, you ditched her. You took up with Margie. Margie fell for your line. She really figured you loved her, wanted to marry her. And she believed you when you said Shelton had gypped you out of thirty grand. That was a lie. And besides, Shelton’s dice are straight … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, after Margie agreed to help you, you hired me. We pulled the heist; got the dough from Shelton’s safe. Shelton made threats. You saw a chance to get the money, be rid of Margie — and pin her murder on Shelton.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer gulped noisily. “You’re all wrong — ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuts. You swiped Shelton’s diamond ring off his finger while he was tied to his chair, knocked out. Then you went ahead to Margie’s apartment house. You waited behind that drape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wore Shelton’s ring when you shot Margie. All I saw was your gun-hand — and the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You didn’t drill me. You wanted me alive — so that I could testify it was Shelton’s hand I saw holding the murder-gun. You just conked me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I came to and rushed here to your place, you fired a shot out your window, so I’d hear it. Then you fell on the floor and played possum. You wanted me to think Shelton had come here and drilled you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But the wound in your shoulder was from my bullet, Greer! I winged you when I shot through that drape after you drilled Margie!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, Corcoran! You’re crazy!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuts! I should have guessed it right away, when I looked at your shoulder the first time. The blood had already started to clot. But I was dumb. I was dumb up to the time Spot Shelton slugged me on the jaw in Jackie Allan’s bungalow a little while ago. Then I saw the truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wh-what do you mean?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shelton poked me with his right — but it didn’t cut my cheek. He wasn’t wearing his ring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was the tip-off. Maybe somebody else had the ring. Not Jackie Allan, because her hands were smaller than the one I saw through that drape. And why didn’t Shelton croak me in Jackie’s bungalow when he had the chance? If he’d been guilty, he’d have drilled me to keep me from spilling. Instead, all he did was biff me. He just wanted a chance to get Jackie away — because he thought she was the killer. He loves her; wanted to protect her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Jackie wasn’t guilty. But if Shelton thought she was, it meant he was innocent himself. Get it? So that cleared everybody but you, Greer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You had motive: greed. You had opportunity. And you had my bullet hole through your shoulder. You also had a roscoe — which I just tricked away from you. Got anything to say now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;turn-em-loose&quot;&gt;Turn ’Em Loose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greer snarled: “You’ll never take me, Corcoran!” and swatted at the revolver in the private dick’s fist. Corcoran shot him through the other shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’ll suffer a little before they burn you,” he said. He was thinking of poor little Margie Zaine lying dead because she had loved unwisely … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search disclosed the thirty thousand dollars that Greer had taken from Margie’s handbag. And Corcoran also found Shelton’s diamond ring, under Greer’s mattress. Corcoran phoned police headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come and get the guy that bumped Margie Zaine,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve already got him. Spot Shelton. Picked him up with a blonde a while ago.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corcoran said: “Turn ’em loose. They’re clean. And you might tell Shelton that a dumb cluck named Corcoran would like an invite to the wedding … .”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/odds-are-on-death/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/odds-are-on-death/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nice Corpses Like Flowers</title>
        <description>&lt;section id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h6&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h6&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-7&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-8&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-9&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- table-of-contents --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;funeral-pieces&quot;&gt;Funeral Pieces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basement of the flower store was chill with dampness; the naked light-bulb above the work table glaring harshly, piled up huge, crouching shadows in the corners, police coat buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It glinted on Detective Clint Fleming pushed his brown felt hat farther back on his crinkly black hair and contemplated the body at his feet. Then he turned and swung sharp eyes at the group huddled behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I suppose,” he said wearily, “none of you know anything about this—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three heads shook quickly, involuntarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint Fleming glanced down again at the body of the slender young man. A florist’s knife—the kind used for trimming flowers—was in his chest, in the center of a crimson splash on his white shirtfront. Only the green enameled handle was visible. The head and shoulders were part way under the worktable, and the thin little coroner was complaining bitterly as he crawled out, stood up and brushed off his knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why,” he asked no one, “do corpses always get themselves in such awkward positions?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He picked up his worn satchel, clapped his hat on his head, and said briskly, “I’ll send my report around as usual. Fellow’s been dead about ten hours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint Fleming nodded absently, and nudged the gilt letters that lay in confusion on the cement floor with the toe of his shoe. In his hand he held the letter U he had picked from the dead man’s fingers. The pigeonholed box that had held the letters lay overturned, empty. A cluster of M’s were scattered near the lifeless hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, cover him up,” Detective Fleming jerked over his shoulder to one of the blue-coated officers. Then he turned back to the silent three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The redhead was crying soundlessly into her handkerchief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right,” he said, “let’s get down to cases. Tell me again what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl spoke. Her name was Pat Murray; she was new in the store, learning the flower business. She had discovered the body of Fred Jensen that morning when she had come down to the basement to bring up some vases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who called the police?” Clint asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tall, sallow young man on the girl’s right answered. “I did. I’m Jack Unger. I deliver the orders. Pat came screaming up the stairs—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unger,” Clint repeated. He glanced down at the paper letter in his hand and his gray eyes narrowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young man flushed. “Just because that letter was—” he moistened dry lips— “in Fred’s hand, it doesn’t mean—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn it,” Clint interrupted sharply, “it means something! Why would he have picked out a U? You use these letters to print out sentiments on ribbons, don’t you? For funeral pieces?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At his last words the girl squeezed her blue eyes shut, pressed the back of her hand against her mouth. Her slim shoulders trembled under her smock. Jack Unger touched her arm lightly and she drew away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’ll be all right, Pat,” he said softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She did not answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;lilacs&quot;&gt;Lilacs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man on her left spoke for the first time. He was short and stocky,, his black eyes antagonistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, Mister,” he told Clint, “Pat’s had about all she can stand. We don’t know any more than we told you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked at him. A brief smile flickered on his lips. Then he shrugged. “Sure,” he said kindly, “but somebody has to ask questions. The Chief has plopped this case in my lap. It’s up to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint thought: this being a detective isn’t so hot. Nobody likes you —they’re afraid if they do you’ll turn around and pin a murder rap on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glanced at Pat and she looked hastily away. Any other time, under the right circumstances, a girl like that would smile if a fellow’s eyes showed that he thought— Clint broke off his thoughts. He hadn’t missed the look that crossed her face when Unger touched her arm. Or the fact that the paper U in his hand was the second letter of her last name. It was also the second letter of murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had Fred Jenson been trying to spell cut something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s the boss?” Clint asked suddenly. “Who is the Davies this store is named after?” He looked a question at the stocky, dark man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My name’s Herb Martin. Thomas Davies owns the store. He’s usually here, but he’s been home the past few days. Heart trouble.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s been notified?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. “He said the police are welcome to come out and he’ll tell them what he knows.” Clint made a wry face. “Helpful people rarely know anything of use,” he observed. He started to walk toward the stairs that led up into the shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wouldn’t take any sudden trips, if I were you,” he told them. Then, with his hand on the wooden banister, he stopped. He took r deep breath of the damp air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned to Pat Murray and asked slowly, “Isn’t that lilacs I smell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She nodded and pointed to a large table that stood against a gloom-shrouded wall. “They’re over there. We have more upstairs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint pursed his lips. His words, when he brought them out, were careful. “Last week I tried to buy some lilacs—I was told that the season has been over for a half a month. How come you still have them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl started to speak, but Herb Martin interrupted with,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So we’re lucky? So what difference does that make?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“None at all—I suppose,” Cliff told him slowly. Then he leaned forward and his words were chill, “You know,” he said, “I don’t think I’m going to like you. And if I were you—I wouldn’t make me positive of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he looked past the man. “You can have the body taken away,” he told one of the officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went on up the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;suspects&quot;&gt;Suspects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Davies seemed more than anxious to help and he sat in a deep leather chair, his bread face puckered into a frown of worry, his fingers picking at the front of his dressing gown. His false teeth flashed whitely when he spoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A terrible thing,” he said. “A terrible thing, really. Fred was a nice boy. Why anyone should—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He had no enemies?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Davies’ eyebrows drew down. “I don’t want to say anything that will put blame—but, well, he and Tack Unger were both interested in Pat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And she preferred Jensen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. “I don’t think Jack would have—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about Herb Martin?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ob, he’s all right. Bit of a temper, but—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint sighed. “You think Unger did it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies stiffened. “I didn’t say that! In fact—” his eyes narrowed— “this would be just the sort of thing Mike Slone would have wanted to happen. He—” He broke off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, Slone has the flower shop on the next corner. He’s been fighting me for years. Plenty tough customer. Lately he’s been making threats.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What kind?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies waved a vague hand. “Says I ruin his business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint murmured deep in his throat. Then he stood up. “I’ll go around and see him.” He put out his hand. Davies took it, gripped it tightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to try to get down to the shop tomorrow,” the florist said. “Let me know if you find out anything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint grinned crookedly at him. “You’ll know,” he promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;yellow-roses&quot;&gt;Yellow Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint parked his car at the curb, and went o the door of “Davies Flowers” and rapped on the glass. Pat came to let him in. She was alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How come you didn’t go home?” Fleming wanted to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled thinly at him. “I’d rather work—it keeps my mind busy. There are a lot of orders to get out. Phone orders.” She jerked her red head at the crowd clustered outside the plate glass windows. “Would they love to come in and stare.” “Probably you can open the store tomorrow,” Clint told her. “But, where is everybody?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Herb is out having lunch; Jack is delivering.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Clint asked, “mind if I talk to you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shook her head and walked back to the counter on which she had been working. She picked up a snapdragon spike and with deft fingers stripped off the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint watched her until she had finished the bunch. Then she took the coppery blossoms, put them in a water-filled vase. Her hands stopped as Clint asked slowly, “Was Fred Jensen in love with you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stood a moment, her red lip caught in her teeth, then she answered, “Yes, I guess he was. I liked him—that was all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And Jack Unger?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned to him then. “Mr. Davies said that Jack killed Fred because of me?” she demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint lifted one shoulder. “Could be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t believe it,” she said hotly. “Simmer down—nobody’s accusing him. You like him, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pat tossed her head. “No,” she said flatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s been trying to change your mind—and Fred didn’t like that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well—” she began, then her voice trailed off. Nervously she picked up a glass bottle, unscrewed the cap, poured two white pellets into her palm and dropped them into the vase that held the snapdragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that?” Clint asked curiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aspirin. It makes them last longer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As long as three weeks?” Clint’s words were quick. “Or more?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl looked startled. “I don’t know—” she faltered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint leaned toward her, over the counter. “Doesn’t it strike you strange that you have flowers out of season when no one else has?” He pointed to a bowl of yellow roses in the window. “How long have they been there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pat followed his motion. “Well, they’re pretty expensive; they haven’t sold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About three and a half weeks.” Clint looked thoughtful. “See you later, chick,” he said abruptly, “I’m going down the street.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;u-in-murder&quot;&gt;U In Murder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Sloan’s store was called “The Patio.” It was smaller than Davies’ flower shop. A small, pasty-faced man came around the counter as Clint entered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can I help you?” he began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You Mike Slone?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man bobbed his head. “That’s right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Detective Fleming,” Clint said. “Investigating the murder of Fred Jensen. Did you know him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Slone swallowed hastily. “Yes, I’d seen him around. Poor boy. I heard—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint leaned against a glass case, dug in his pocket, pulled out a crushed package of cigarettes, selected one and lit it. He blew out a cloud of blue smoke and asked, “Know anything about him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slone shook his head hastily. “Seemed like a bright boy. Lots of times I wished he was working for me—but I don’t know anything that would help you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint dragged on his cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Davies says you’ve threatened him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little man’s pale blue eyes widened. “I may have done some talking, but I didn’t mean anything by it, honest! He does a good business, and I guess sometimes I get jealous.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked thoughtful. “I see.” He shrugged, then, “Well, thanks. I’ll be going—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint left the store, got into his car. His eyes were narrowed, speculative. That gilt U—where did it fit? U for Unger, U in Murray, U in murder … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He steered his coupe through the traffic over to the West side where Jensen had lived. It was a red- bricked rooming house with a sign, “To Let” in a lower, dirt-smeared window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landlady leaned on her broom and waved him crossly up the stairs when he asked Jensen’s room number. He’d sent Wilson and the fingerprint gang over earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson opened the door at Clint’s knock. He grinned at the detective. “Though you’d be showing up soon.” Fleming glanced quickly around. “What you find?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson spread wide hands. “Everything—and nothing.” He waved a hand at the disorder of opened bureau drawers, clothes scattered on the floor, the bed ripped apart. “Place was like this when we came. The door had been forced. Somebody was powerfully anxious to find something—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint scarcely heard him, for he had walked a few steps, stooped and picked up a half dozen yellow pencils from the floor. He whistled a thin thread of a tune from between set teeth as he studied them. All the points were well worn down. There were teeth marks at the eraser ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seems,” he observed half to himself, “that our friend Mr. Jensen did a powerful lot of writing lately. Wonder what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;gardenia&quot;&gt;Gardenia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next afternoon Clint Fleming was exactly where he had been the day before—nowhere near a solution. He’d been to see the a solution. He’d been to see the chief —which did nothing for his ego, as Chief Cummings had said he’d better start showing some action, or else. And the “or else” had been punctuated by the slam of a big fist on the top of a desk … .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked into the Davies’ flower store and Pat looked up from some violets she was stemming and came over to him. She looked better today —prettier, if possible. Some color had flowed back into her cheeks; her eyes had lost that reddened look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello there,” Clint said. He smiled, and Pat smiled back. This was more like it— “Your boss in?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl nodded, motioned with her red-curled head toward the balcony that ran half way around the inside of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s up in his office.” She rested quick fingers on his arm. “Have you found out anything?” she asked worriedly. Clint shook his head, and glanced past her to where Herb Martin and Jack Unger were standing. Neither smiled, and Herb’s eyes were chill as they met Clint’s In Unger’s, Clint saw sudden jealousy flare. Strangely, Clint wanted to grin—both those men were jealous of him! Of course, it was no wonder when a girl looked like Pat. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“See you later, chick,” he told her softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned and almost tripped over a flat, wood-slatted crate of roses that lay on the floor behind him. The roses were yellow-red and wrapped tightly in waxed paper. He bent and touched one of the buds with a forefinger—the flowers almost looked artificial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, behind him, someone snapped, “Keep your hands off those flowers!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He whirled and stared into the narrowed eyes of Herb Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why so touchy, Martin?” he asked quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man’s fist curled. “Roses cost money and I don’t want a dumb cop spoiling them—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint studied him coolly, then deliberately he bent down, broke off a bud and put it in his buttonhole. He gave it a final pat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So?” he suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin teetered close, his face dark with anger. Then, with an effort he kept his voice quiet. Over his shoulder he said, “Pat, fix Mr. Fleming a gardenia—he wants a boutonniere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, I already have one,” Clint told him, and turned and went up the stairs that led to Davies’ office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies was behind his desk. “Hello, Mr. Fleming,” he said. He pulled worriedly at his chin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint sat down in a straight-backed chair. “Now,” he began, “have you any idea why Jensen was here, alone, last night? Who closed the store?” Davies leaned back. “He did. I talked to Unger and Martin. They, and Miss Murray left the same time. Fred was going to clean up some things in the basement before he went home. I—” He broke off and stared at the rose in Fleming’s buttonhole. “Where did you get the Talisman?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint grinned. “It’s one of yours.” Davies seemed to be waiting for him to say more. Finally he asked slowly, “Martin give it to you?” “No—I took it. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies laughed falsely. “Martin’s very fussy about the roses. They’re sort of his department—” He tapped on his desk top with a pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint’s eyes were narrowed, watching him. “Yeah,” he said absently. Then he got to his feet. “Well, I’ll be shoving. See you around, Davies.” He went down the stairs and stopped at the counter where Pat was making the wired violets into a corsage. Her fingers were stained from the maidenhair fern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He kept his voice low, and for her ears. “Look,” he said. “Take care of yourself—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes widened. “Why—what’s the matter?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shrugged briefly. “I don’t know, but there’s plenty. Sometimes I get feelings—and I have one now.” He glanced around the shop. “The answer’s here someplace, if only I could find it—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abruptly he drew an order pad toward him and scribbled a number on it. He creased the sheet carefully and dropped it into Pat’s smock pocket. “This is just in case. If you hear anything, or see anything you think I ought to know about—call me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He caught Martin watching him, so he bent his head to the rose in his lapel. He took a deep sniff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This,” he said, “at least smells good—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;empty-buttonhole&quot;&gt;Empty Buttonhole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bell was ringing someplace. For a long time Fleming lay in his bed, his eyes closed, hoping it would go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t. Finally, with a sigh, he opened his eyes and reached for the alarm clock. His hand stopped half way through the motion—the room was dark. It was still night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sat up suddenly, awake now. He scooped the telephone receiver from its cradle on the nightstand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello?” he said sharply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A voice blurred at the other end. An excited voice; a voice shrill. Clint broke into the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take it easy—I can’t understand you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Clint Fleming, isn’t it?” the voice wanted to know. He recognized it, then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it’s you, Pat,” he said quickly. “What’s wrong?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Clint—I’ve found out something!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes? What? Where are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m down at the store. I came back tonight. After you said you thought the answer was here, I decided to look around—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crazy kid!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I got to thinking about those Talisman roses. There’s something funny about those crates. I never—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint cut her off. “And what did you find?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I—” she began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes—go on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no answer. Clint’s hand grew clammy on the receiver. He listened—the phone was dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat!” he shouted. Still the fear-starting silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one motion he had dropped the phone and was reaching for his clothes. There was only one reason why Pat didn’t answer—and that reason sent the blood from his face, leaving him white-lipped, trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He waited only long enough to pick up his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Clint Fleming careened his coupe through the deserted streets he suddenly reached up and felt at his buttonhole. The rose was gone; he had lost it someplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentally he damned himself—he’d had the answer on his lapel and never realized it! But what was the connection ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He screeched his car to a stop in front of the darkened flower shop, then he thought of calling the chief. But there wasn’t time for that now —not with Pat in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t expect the front door to be unlocked, but it was. It swung open under his hand and he walked into the store, his gun fisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat!” he called. “Where are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His voice echoed back at him, there was no other sound. Just the quiet, cool air, heavy with the scent of flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked softly to the basement door, opened it a crack. A light glimmered up from below, and he heard, now, a feverish rustling. Cautiously he started down the wooden&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stairs. The third step creaked under his weight, and abruptly the light winked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all—no sound, just the darkness rushing in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint stood where he was, poised, listening for the rasp of a foot, anything. There was nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He inched his wry forward, and again the stairs protested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, shattering the quiet, splitting the darkness, a gun spoke! Clint heard the bullet ricochet from the cement wall scarcely a foot from his head. But now he knew the direction, now he had a target for his gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pulled the trigger twice, but his aim was wrong. Again the orange flame blossomed, and this time the slug was closer. Too close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He plunged down into the darkness, firing as he went, aiming a little to the left of the last flash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a sharp cry that slipped down scale into a moan—he hadn’t missed that time! He felt for the light switch at the foot of the stairs, flicked it. The shadows fled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the left, by a wooden crate, a man was sprawled. Fleming walked to him, turned him over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herb Martin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trickle of blood seeped out of his hair where Clint’s bullet had grazed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-roses&quot;&gt;The Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint looked at the crate. It was the same one he had seen earlier, only now the waxed-paper-wrapped bundles of roses lay scattered on the cement. He stooped, picked up a bunch. The buds were open—but not naturally—they had been forced open. The very center of the roses were missing. And then Clint saw the little pile of white-powder-filled capsules by Martin’s hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective whistled softly. “Dope,” he murmured. “So that’s the answer—they were smuggling dope in the roses. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would have to wait. Right now he had something more important to worry about—Pat was still missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned, went up the stairs, calling her name, searching the office. If she’s here, he thought, she’d answer—if she could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was no sign of the girl— she had disappeared completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was just passing the counter, on his way back downstairs, when his foot caught on something. He reached down and felt it. It was a string—no, it was a ribbon, a long streamer that unwound from the big spool on the counter as he pulled at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where was the other end? He tugged, the ribbon did not give. He hadn’t been able to find the switch that worked the fluorescent lights, so now he struck a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ribbon curled away into the gloom, toward the side of the store. Gathering it in his hand he followed it. It stopped at the crack of a small, narrow door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he knew. Pat was inside—in the refrigerator! He jerked open the door. The chill, icy air struck him as he went inside. He groped on the floor. His fingers overturned a vase, sent it crashing. Then he touched a shoulder, a face, soft hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t breathe as he bent over the girl—was she alive? She was, she stirred slightly and moaned. The other end of the ribbon spool was twisted in her fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He picked her up gently, whispering her name incoherently, and carried her out into the store. He laid her down. He thought savagely. Where is that damn switch—I have to see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time he found it, and the fluorescence flooded the room. In its soft glow he studied her face anxiously. Then he took a deep breath. She was going to be all right. Just knocked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes fluttered open and she struggled to sit up. Then she clung to him, sobbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all right, darling,” he soothed. “The roses—” she began brokenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all over. I know about them. Martin’s down in the basement, unconscious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then he—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hush, darling.” He helped her to her feet. “You all right now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She nodded, swaying a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint turned and went to the wall phone. He dialed a number, spoke briefly to the chief. Then he hung up and dialed another number. When a voice answered he said, “Davies— come on down, I’ve found your murderer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chapternumber&quot; id=&quot;chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;chaptertitle no_toc&quot; id=&quot;fresh-flowers&quot;&gt;Fresh Flowers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cops were already there when the storeowner came hurrying in. His broad face was tense, and he looked as if he had fallen into his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went to where Clint was standing, talking to the chief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who did it?” he demanded. “Was it Unger?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming shook his head slowly. “Davies, did you know that Martin was in the dope smuggling business?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man’s eyes widened and his face paled. “No—” he managed. “You mean, here, in my store?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint nodded. “Yes. That was why he didn’t let anyone touch certain crates of roses but himself—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And Fred Jensen must have discovered it,” Davies cut in. “And that was why he killed him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detective shook his head slowly. “That may have been one of the reasons why Jensen had to die—but not the only one. Martin told me before they took him to the hospital. Jensen had discovered a formula for preserving fresh flowers. There’s thousands in such a discovery—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Jensen wanted to patent his formula, which was his right. For that, and because he was getting suspicious—he had to die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davies shook his head bewilderedly. “To think that Martin killed Jensen—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A faint, hard smile flickered at Fleming’s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But he didn’t—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said—well, who did then?” Davies exploded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint’s voice was very quiet. “You did, Davies!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re insane!” The man backed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re the one who’s insane,” the detective said relentlessly. “Martin didn’t know actually who killed Jensen any more than I did—until I began to add things up. The flowers lasting longer in your store than anywhere else. The fact that Jensen’s room was searched. That damn U in Jensen’s fingers—I finally tumbled to the fact that the poor kid had been trying to spell out something … and ‘formula’ is about the only word with a u in it that would fit into the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wanted the discovery yourself, didn’t you, Davies? You pictured yourself cornering the flower market—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lie!” Davies cut in shrilly. Fleming went on savagely, as if he hadn’t heard. “You didn’t even trust Martin, so you did it yourself—and tried to pin it on Unger. Failing that, you would have let Martin die for the murder you committed. He’ll get plenty on the dope charge—but you, you’re going to get the chair!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his last words, Davies lunged at Clint, his short arms flailing. It was almost pitiful, the ease with which Clint’s rock-hard fist arced up and caught him on the point of his soft jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sagged to the floor without a sound, and disappeared under a wave of blue-coated backs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming rubbed skinned knuckles and walked to where Pat was standing, white-faced, her hand to her throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He put out an arm and drew her to him. She stared up at him with wide eyes. “How did you know for sure, Clint?” she whispered shakily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grinned and kissed her on the tip of her tilted nose. “There was one little thing that really set me thinking—those pencils I found in Jensen’s room. They were all badly chewed. And then I saw Davies playing with a chewed pencil. I knew it wasn’t his, that he had picked it up someplace— It might have been coincidence—but it started me thinking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But how did you know it wasn’t Davies’?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleming laughed deep in his throat. “A guy with false teeth doesn’t go around biting on pencils, does he?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he looked at Pat a long moment. “How good are you at making bridal bouquets?” he asked suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because I got a feeling we’re going to be needing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;~ The End ~
&lt;h6 class=&quot;btt&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;Back to Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:3000/short-stories/nice-corpses-like-flowers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:3000/short-stories/nice-corpses-like-flowers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>short-stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
